[{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  B. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. ","  C. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers. ","  D. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Has a lower price than the competitor's product ","  B. Can reach the market quickly ","  C. Can be sold for a positive return ","  D. Has more features than the competitor's product "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably).  "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Middle management ","  B. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees ","  C. Top management ","  D. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.) "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve. "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Real property acquisitions ","  B. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore ","  C. Transfer cost decisions ","  D. Warehouse location decision"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  B. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  C. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs. ","  D. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations.  "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Jobs are not a focus of change. ","  B. Job responsibilities expand. ","  C. Jobs become more specialized. ","  D. Job tasks are simplified. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A new supply chain ","  B. A new product ","  C. A new corporate organization chart ","  D. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers ","  B. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers ","  C. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  D. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection. "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible. ","  B. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders. ","  C. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs. ","  D. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching.  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  B. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies ","  C. A limited number of essential supply chain processes ","  D. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  B. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns. ","  C. SCOR applies to product development. ","  D. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members. ","  B. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. ","  C. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network. ","  D. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"In a TQM initiative, the definition of \"defect\" is determined by which of the following?","choices":["A. Customer ","  B. Top management ","  C. Project team ","  D. Supply chain manager"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"According to TQM methodology, defects are defined from the customer's point of view.  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Electric power utility ","  B. Manufacturer connected to electric grid ","  C. Facility maintenance ","  D. Fuel supplier "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer. "},{"question":"A supply chain that produces and sells cigarettes using traditional forecasting at each stage has been experiencing the bullwhip effect. Which of the following has the strongest influence on this effect?","choices":["A. Announced promotions ","  B. Seasonal fluctuations ","  C. Safety stock ","  D. Excess supply liquidation "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Because cigarettes have relatively steady demand, the small variations in demand seen in the forecasting at the retail stage of the supply chain are padded by safety stock. Forecasting at each successive level uses the quantities ordered for forecasting rather than the actual sale amount, resulting in extremely variable demand at the other end of the supply chain. "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased cumulative setup time ","  B. Increased inventory accumulation ","  C. Increased holding costs ","  D. Increased handling costs"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Sustainability ","  B. Reliability ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Responsiveness"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market. "},{"question":"With the theory of supply chain versus supply chain in competition, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. Industries with a small number of dominant suppliers are not ideal but are best coordinated using horizontal supply chains. ","  B. Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors at a risk of losing proprietary data. ","  C. When supply chains share suppliers, alignment of business strategies with supply chain strategies is facilitated. ","  D. Investments in suppliers shared by a competitor will increase the partnership with that supplier to the detriment of the competitor."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors, but at the very least the situation invites conflict of interest. Insofar as manufacturers want to keep their designs and processes proprietary, they take a risk when they link up with competing component suppliers.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following approaches to production scheduling accurately incorporates the theory of constraints?","choices":["A. Speed up production in front of the bottleneck. ","  B. Decrease inventory at the front of the bottleneck. ","  C. Slow the process down to the bottleneck's speed. ","  D. Speed up production after the bottleneck. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The theory of constraints focuses attention on slowest-moving part of a manufacturing process because it determines the maximum output of the process. Speeding up production before the constraint only produces an oversupply of inventory in front of the constraint, while speeding up the process after the constraint will result only in a lack of inventory after the constraint. Avoiding either of these problems requires running the process at the speed of the constraint. "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Display cards used as production signals ","  B. Root cause ","  C. Interlocking business ownership ","  D. Continuous process improvement"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"According to total quality theory, which of the following would be of primary importance to document during the analysis phase of a continuous improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Customer attitudes toward the product produced by the process ","  B. Staff-level views of the practical difficulties involved in carrying out the process ","  C. Executive-level positions on the importance of the process ","  D. A thorough, factual description of the process "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Quality theory emphasizes the importance of data; therefore, improvement initiatives begin with a complete, unbiased, factual description of the process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  B. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping ","  C. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  D. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified. "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Conveyers ","  B. Shipping containers ","  C. Pallets ","  D. Protective packaging "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory. "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs. ","  B. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. ","  C. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. ","  D. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. The rate in the country of the headquarters ","  B. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates ","  C. The local country rate ","  D. A special international rate "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions. "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  B. Approval of top management ","  C. Outcome of the change initiative ","  D. Judgment of each participant's direct supervisor"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning). "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Commodity materials ","  C. Bottleneck materials ","  D. Leveragable materials "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions. ","  B. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  C. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers. ","  D. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things. "},{"question":"According to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model, if a refrigerator manufacturing company is at the center of the model, the supplier of materials to the sheet metal supplier has only which of the following processes to perform in relation to the manufacturer?","choices":["A. Make, source, deliver ","  B. Plan, deliver, return ","  C. Plan, source, make, deliver, return ","  D. Plan, source, return"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"From the perspective of the manufacturer, the supplier of metal to the sheet metal suppliers is on the second tier and may join in planning, but the manufacturer is otherwise concerned only with its ability to deliver and return goods as needed. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Process benchmarking ","  B. Competitive benchmarking ","  C. Best-in-class benchmarking ","  D. Oliver Wight benchmarking"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect. "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Supplier management ","  B. Collection and accounting for sales taxes ","  C. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer ","  D. Compliance with government regulations"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions ","  B. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods ","  C. One supply chain for all goods ","  D. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"A firm that is always claiming it has the best processes and highest quality has recently suffered losses because even though they dictate these processes to their long-term Asian suppliers, several of them have, without any explanation, recently had a string of additional costs and quality problems. Which of the following would best help this firm resolve its problems?","choices":["A. Enforce the provisions of the suppliers' contracts through litigation. ","  B. Move production so that it is once again performed correctly in-house. ","  C. Find new suppliers who can follow the firm's process more closely. ","  D. Increase visibility with the suppliers and allow the suppliers to suggest processes that work for them.  "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"35. Cultures tend to be egocentric and thus tend to resist external collaboration. They feel that their ways are the best ways of doing things and will often reject a different way without even considering it. Culture conflicts are increased when each company relies on its own sources of information and is unable to see the impact of its choices on other areas of the network. When companies don't see the negative results of their actions, they can't learn from their mistakes. Increasing visibility will correct some of these problems, but processes may need to be adaptable to the area in which they are performed, such as that litigation is seen as a betrayal of a relationship in many Asian countries. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software ","  B. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  C. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  D. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis. "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency material ","  B. Commodity material ","  C. Bottleneck material ","  D. Leveragable material"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. JIT ","  B. Kanban ","  C. Six-sigma ","  D. Lean "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies the emphasis of the Global Reporting Initiative?","choices":["A. Monitoring terrorist activities ","  B. Enforcing UN trade sanctions ","  C. Policing corporate and supply chain activities ","  D. Developing and publishing environmentally sustainable trade practices "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) is an independent group of organizations, including corporations, that develops and publishes sustainable corporate trade practices in regard to such environmental concerns as emissions, energy and resource consumption, and waste. It works with the UN and is entirely voluntary. "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  B. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"A manager decides to source their key Just-in-Time (JIT) manufacturing goods from a local producer even though an overseas producer sells identical goods for less, even with the added cost of shipping. Which of the following is this manager most likely emphasizing?","choices":["A. Availability ","  B. Positive supply chain contribution ","  C. Quality ","  D. Affordability "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The availability of the good is being emphasized because the manager needs a reliable supply of goods even if it costs more to get the good when it is needed for the JIT process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features ","  B. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems ","  C. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints ","  D. Successive approximations of a perfected process "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints. "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Planning ","  B. Making ","  C. Delivering ","  D. Sourcing  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Improved business focus and expertise ","  B. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  C. Technology to handle the increased complexity ","  D. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top. "},{"question":"According to the functional and innovative product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following would be a proper performance indicator for a typical innovative product?","choices":["A. Inventory reduction ","  B. Aggressively reducing lead times ","  C. Design for maximum performance at minimal cost ","  D. High inventory turns "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The key performance indicators for each supply chain differ because of the product characteristics. Aggressively reducing lead times, for example, is appropriate for innovative products but would be irrelevant for functional products that can be manufactured and delivered on predictable schedules in high volumes.  "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Internal business process improvement ","  B. Financials ","  C. Customer perspective ","  D. Employee learning and growth "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line.  "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  B. Make-to-order functional product ","  C. Make-to-order innovative product ","  D. Make-to-stock functional product"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks. "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain flexibility ","  B. Supply chain responsiveness ","  C. Supply chain reliability ","  D. Supply chain adaptability"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"What is the minimum level of enterprise evolution in which a firm might use a logistics supplier to integrate with external members and also internally combine warehousing and transportation activities to optimize cost versus customer service?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A company at Stage 3 will make advances such as carrying out warehousing and transportation decisions in tandem to achieve the optimal balance of cost-effectiveness and customer service. At this point, the nucleus firm may begin to take a step toward integration with the external members of the chain by contracting with a logistics supplier.  "},{"question":"In SCOR Level 1, if you divide the sum of the cycle times for all orders delivered by the total number of orders delivered, you are using a metric for which of the following supply chain attributes?","choices":["A. Adaptability ","  B. Flexibility ","  C. Responsiveness ","  D. Reliability "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Average actual cycle time (sum of cycle times divided by number of deliveries) measures the responsiveness of the supply chain. It doesn't tell you if the deliveries were on time, which would be a reliability metric.  "},{"question":"Company A has installed supply chain management (SCM) software to achieve cross-functional integration. However, some members of the overall value chain that are not directly part of the supply chain itself have not provided the desired level of support for SCM initiatives. Which of the following departments is most likely to be the one lacking in support?","choices":["A. Human resources ","  B. Inbound logistics ","  C. Customer service ","  D. Marketing and sales "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Human resources is part of the value chain support activities that sustain the supply chain. The incorrect answers are all directly part of the supply chain. Managers from outside the supply chain often don't understand the requirements of supply chain management, can't distinguish value chain from supply chain, and consequently don't provide the SCM support required from their areas. "},{"question":"Which of the following scenarios is most likely to occur at the Stage 3 (integrated enterprise) level of supply chain evolution or higher?","choices":["A. Sales rep finds a market opportunity but is unable to bring it to the attention of new product development. ","  B. Dominant partner coerces others to force price concessions. ","  C. Manager provides a broad mission and backs it up with threats for nonconformance. ","  D. Warehouses are located near each market and have more than enough inventory to handle the next big sale"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"When firms first move past internal integration into external collaboration, the first collaboration can also be the last one if the arrangement fails to produce positive results for the weaker partner as well as for the channel master. Early manufacturer-supplier linkages, for example, were too often the result of coercion by the dominant partner, who was looking for guaranteed on-time delivery of quality items at a relatively low price.  "},{"question":"The Global Supply Chain Forum (GSCF) defines supply chain management as \"the integration of key business processes from end user through original suppliers that provides products, services, and information that add value for customers and other stakeholders.\" Which two processes are considered to constitute the core of supply chain management in the GSCF model?","choices":["A. Customer service management and manufacturing flow management ","  B. Order management and supplier relationship management ","  C. Demand management and supplier management ","  D. Customer and supplier management"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"At the heart of the GSCF model is the combination of customer relationship management and supplier relationship management, because these two processes create and manage the link between adjacent partners in the supply chain. "},{"question":"Which of the following results from having a firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) software designed for automatic calculation of corporate taxes?","choices":["A. The software will most likely fail to take legally available deductions. ","  B. The firms will risk violating Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) reporting requirements. ","  C. The software will earn a tax deduction based on its use in tax planning. ","  D. The firm will most likely underreport income."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"ERP software can be programmed to determine the firm's exact tax liability and, at the same time, comply with Sarbanes-Oxley and earn a deduction for itself.  "},{"question":"JIT \"cells\" are laid out to accommodate which of the following?","choices":["A. One type of machine ","  B. One production process ","  C. One product family with similar manufacturing processes ","  D. One specialized type of worker"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Cells are arranged to allow for the most efficient production of a product family manufactured with similar production processes. Workers and machines are grouped to provide all the skills and equipment required for that product family in an efficiently arranged layout.  "},{"question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 focuses on which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Terrorism ","  B. Financial reporting and controls ","  C. Hazardous materials ","  D. Material content reporting"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Sarbanes-Oxley focuses on financial reporting and controls, including reporting on supply chain controls. Plans to respond to events such as terrorism are included in the reporting requirements, but they are not the focus of the legislation, which was drafted in response to corporate corruption "},{"question":"If a firm has 25 days of accounts payables outstanding and 30 days invested in inventory and their cash-to-cash cycle time is 80 days, how many days of accounts receivables do they have?","choices":["A. 105 days ","  B. 80 days ","  C. 75 days ","  D. 50 days "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The correct answer is 75 days: 80 days (cash to cash) + 25 days (payables) - 30 days (inventory) = 75 days receivables. The cash-to-cash cycle (or cash conversion cycle) is the number of days between the time a firm pays for raw materials and the time it receives payment for finished goods. The equation for calculating the cash-to-cash cycle is Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time = Average Inventory Collection Period + Average Receivables Processing Period - Average Payables Period; therefore, Days of Accounts Receivable = Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time + Days of Accounts Payable - Days of Inventory.  "},{"question":"Benchmarking is a tool used to carry out which function of a quality initiative?","choices":["A. Determine the roles in an initiative. ","  B. Assess process performance. ","  C. Analyze the steps in a process. ","  D. Implement a process improvement initiative."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Benchmarks provide a point of comparison that allows a project team to assess the relative effectiveness of a process and set a goal for its improvement.  "},{"question":"When preparing for a potential business disruption, which of the following is valid advice for contingency planners?","choices":["A. Having extra stores of inventory is inadequate protection against a disruption in production. ","  B. After assessing all potential risks, ensure that each one has a plan for continued functioning regardless of the cost. ","  C. Create contingency plans for yourself and for your supply chain partners. ","  D. Contingency plans are the responsibility of each departmental manager in addition to their regular duties."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Don't rely only on extra stores of inventory. There can never be enough of it to cover all potential problems, and it, too, is vulnerable. You need alternate processes to keep functioning after a disaster. "},{"question":"When setting supply chain strategy at a firm that isn't the nucleus firm, which of the following is the most important to focus on?","choices":["A. What's good for one's own firm ","  B. What's good for the nucleus firm ","  C. What's good for extended supply chain partners ","  D. What's good for the final customer "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"When it comes to supply chains, it's what's good for the final customer that counts, not what's good for the nucleus company or even what seems to be good for the supply chain itself. Supply chain management ought to be all about giving the final customer the right product at the right time and place for the right price. "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  B. Make-to-order functional product ","  C. Make-to-stock functional product ","  D. Make-to-order innovative product "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks.   "},{"question":"Which one of the following authorities has issued directives mandating reporting, reduction, and recycling of heavy metals in end-of-life electronics products?","choices":["A. Chinese government ","  B. United Nations ","  C. European Union ","  D. United States government"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The European Union has issued several directives regarding hazardous components of electronics products, including the Waste from Electronic Equipment directive (WEEE) and the directive restricting the use of heavy metals and retardants in electrical and electronic equipment (RoHS). "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Job responsibilities expand. ","  B. Jobs are not a focus of change. ","  C. Jobs become more specialized. ","  D. Job tasks are simplified. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"According to total quality theory, which of the following would be of primary importance to document during the analysis phase of a continuous improvement initiative?","choices":["A. A thorough, factual description of the process ","  B. Staff-level views of the practical difficulties involved in carrying out the process ","  C. Customer attitudes toward the product produced by the process ","  D. Executive-level positions on the importance of the process "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Quality theory emphasizes the importance of data; therefore, improvement initiatives begin with a complete, unbiased, factual description of the process.  "},{"question":"A channel master is finding that many of its current partners have begun finding ways of bypassing the firm, while others are performing redundant functions that cause unnecessary competition among supply chain members. Which of the following is a likely cause of this behavior?","choices":["A. Individual incentives conflicting with organizational goals ","  B. Working with competitors as peers ","  C. Weakest collaborative links becoming bottlenecks ","  D. Exploitation of power-based relationships "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Power-based relationships occur where a nucleus firm dictates the terms of the relationship to the other members. While its profits increase, other members of the network may suffer losses. When this occurs, the disadvantaged partners may rebel. Resistance may result in redundancy, loss of overall profitability for the chain, or an actual reversal of the power relationship.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the people or the metrics involved in supply chain management?","choices":["A. Supply chain management must be the responsibility of a department-level manager who is equal in hierarchy to other department heads. ","  B. Current supply chain performance is better quantitatively benchmarked against the firm's desired performance than qualitatively benchmarked. ","  C. Performance must be measured by ratios of profitability and velocity, not by a checklist. ","  D. Supply chain strategy and control of the related processes depend on having people educated in functional rather than department thinking."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Numbers (quantitative) generally provide the most convincing supporting evidence in the boardroom and investment analyst's office. If you're bragging about your cash-to-cash cycle, for instance, you might say, \"We've got it down from 50 days to 20, and that's below the industry average.\"  "},{"question":"Which one of the following tools provides a visual method for tracking process variance as part of an improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Pareto diagram ","  B. Process map ","  C. Oliver Wight checklist ","  D. Control chart "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A control chart tracks process variance, allowing a project team to see quickly when defects have spiked to unacceptable levels. It can be used to manage as well as improve a process.  . "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Responsiveness ","  B. Sustainability ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Reliability "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market.   "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  B. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.   "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding supply chain organizations?","choices":["A. A raw material producer has no Tier 1 suppliers. ","  B. Service supplier considerations are important only after a manufacturing site has been selected. ","  C. Supply chains can loop back on themselves, making suppliers into customers. ","  D. There is a long but always finite number of tiers of suppliers in any supply chain."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"No matter how far you travel toward the supply end of a supply chain, you will never run out of new tiers of suppliers. A coal mine may ship coal to a generating plant that supplies power to the manufacturer that produces a machine that is shipped to a distributor that sells mining equipment to the same mine that began the process: supply chains can double back on themselves.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. JIT ","  B. Lean ","  C. Six-sigma ","  D. Kanban "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  . "},{"question":"According to a noted Japanese approach to analyzing business process problems, why is it necessary to ask \"Why?\" as many as five times when seeking the cause of a process defect?","choices":["A. Most defects tend to have multiple causes, not just one. ","  B. First responses tend to name superficial causes rather than the root causes. ","  C. Most employees won't admit making an error the first few times they are asked. ","  D. There may be more than one cause for the defect. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A Japanese method of root cause analysis referred to as \"Why? Why? Why? Why? Why?\" is based on the idea that it's not always easy to identify the root cause of a customer complaint or other process failure; the first suggestion is likely to be the result of bias or superficial analysis.   "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A new supply chain ","  B. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale ","  C. A new corporate organization chart ","  D. A new product "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a true prerequisite for developing collaborative relationships central to supply chain strategy?","choices":["A. Deterrence-based arrangements such as aligning sales and management goals to collaborative objectives ","  B. The most advanced communications hardware and software ","  C. Sharing some benefits but none of the burdens of collaboration with partners ","  D. Auditable information exchange to share knowledge, not just data "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Auditable information exchange and technology for connectivity should allow sharing of knowledge, not mere data. The required technology itself may not have to be the most powerful, but it must be compatible to allow information exchange.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  B. Technology to handle the increased complexity ","  C. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions ","  D. Improved business focus and expertise "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top.  "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers. ","  B. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers. ","  C. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  D. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things.  "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Compliance with government regulations ","  B. Collection and accounting for sales taxes ","  C. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer ","  D. Supplier management "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Interlocking business ownership ","  B. Continuous process improvement ","  C. Display cards used as production signals ","  D. Root cause "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"The developers of the balanced scorecard approach to performance were concerned that traditional metrics placed too much emphasis on which of the following considerations?","choices":["A. Past financial performance ","  B. Current profitability ","  C. Future performance objectives ","  D. Customer complaints"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The developers of the balanced scorecard, Robert S. Kaplan and David Norton, believed that the traditional reliance on financial measures of performance placed too much emphasis on the past and too little on the present and future and, in addition, ignored other types of measures that contribute to success.  "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Shipping containers ","  B. Pallets ","  C. Conveyers ","  D. Protective packaging "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory.  "},{"question":"A supply chain that produces and sells cigarettes using traditional forecasting at each stage has been experiencing the bullwhip effect. Which of the following has the strongest influence on this effect?","choices":["A. Excess supply liquidation ","  B. Announced promotions ","  C. Safety stock ","  D. Seasonal fluctuations "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Because cigarettes have relatively steady demand, the small variations in demand seen in the forecasting at the retail stage of the supply chain are padded by safety stock. Forecasting at each successive level uses the quantities ordered for forecasting rather than the actual sale amount, resulting in extremely variable demand at the other end of the supply chain.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective ","  B. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies ","  C. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  D. A limited number of essential supply chain processes "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"What enforcement authority does the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission bring to its role in regard to the provisions of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act?","choices":["A. Authority to impose jail sentences on executives ","  B. Investigative authority only ","  C. Authority to bring civil court actions ","  D. Authority to bring cases to criminal court "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The SEC has the authority to bring civil suits against corporations and individuals it believes to be out of compliance with securities regulations, including the Sarbanes-Oxley Act. It can refer cases to law enforcement agencies, which can institute criminal proceedings.  "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints ","  B. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features ","  C. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems ","  D. Successive approximations of a perfected process "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs. ","  B. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. ","  C. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. ","  D. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies the emphasis of the Global Reporting Initiative?","choices":["A. Enforcing UN trade sanctions ","  B. Monitoring terrorist activities ","  C. Developing and publishing environmentally sustainable trade practices ","  D. Policing corporate and supply chain activities "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) is an independent group of organizations, including corporations, that develops and publishes sustainable corporate trade practices in regard to such environmental concerns as emissions, energy and resource consumption, and waste. It works with the UN and is entirely voluntary.  "},{"question":"Consider a simplified supply chain in which Lucy sells psychiatric advice from a booth to her classmates for five cents. Subconsciously, she gets her information from her psychiatrist parent and from her pastor. Which of the following are Tier 2 suppliers in this model?","choices":["A. Lucy ","  B. Parent/pastor ","  C. Higher education/seminary ","  D. There are no Tier 2 suppliers in this situation."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lucy's parent and pastor are the Tier 1 suppliers to Lucy, the service producer. They owe their supply of information to either higher education or a seminary, so these sources are the Tier 2 suppliers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  B. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs. ","  C. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  D. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations. "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Competitive benchmarking ","  B. Oliver Wight benchmarking ","  C. Best-in-class benchmarking ","  D. Process benchmarking"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"Which of the following members of the firm are typically involved in continuous process improvement initiatives?","choices":["A. Executives ","  B. All members of the firm, including executives, managers, and labor ","  C. Shop-floor workers and supervisors ","  D. Middle managers"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Continuous process improvement requires the participation of everyone involved in the targeted processes, the executives who are accountable for the process, the managers responsible for directing it, and the workers who carry it out.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following constitutes the range of acceptable variability on a six-sigma control chart?","choices":["A. Zero variability ","  B. Mean defects plus/minus 3 sigmas ","  C. Mean defects plus 6 sigmas ","  D. Mean defects plus/minus 6 sigmas "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The acceptable range of variability is the number of defects within a range of six sigmas (standard deviations) above and below the mean number of defects. The chart helps control the variability in a process.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers ","  B. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  C. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers ","  D. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection. "},{"question":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of training at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Top management only ","  B. All levels ","  C. Customer-facing employees only ","  D. All management levels "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of all process participants, from top management to basic service or shop-floor employees, and it includes training at all levels.  "},{"question":"Which of the following continuous improvement methodologies focuses on reduction of defects to statistical insignificance?","choices":["A. Just-in-Time (JIT) ","  B. Lean ","  C. Six-sigma ","  D. Theory of constraints"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Six-sigma seeks to limit defects to no more than 3.4 per million opportunities. Of course, no initiative sets out to increase defects, but six-sigma makes defect reduction its specific objective.  "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Warehouse location decisions ","  B. Transfer cost decisions ","  C. Real property acquisitions ","  D. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility.  "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency material ","  B. Bottleneck material ","  C. Leveragable material ","  D. Commodity material"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Customer perspective ","  B. Internal business process improvement ","  C. Financials ","  D. Employee learning and growth"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line. "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  B. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand ","  C. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  D. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified. "},{"question":"Which of the following could be a key performance indicator (KPI) for replenishment?","choices":["A. Inventory turns ","  B. Introduction lead time ","  C. Order fill rate ","  D. Volume growth"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fill rate provides a measure of the success of the key process of replenishment. A high fill rate indicates good performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding a supply chain?","choices":["A. Cash flows downstream while materials flow upstream. ","  B. Information flows upstream, downstream, and between network members and external entities. ","  C. An electrical power producer that powers a manufacturer's plant is downstream from the manufacturer. ","  D. Services may be part of a manufacturing supply chain but do not have a distinct supply chain themselves."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The information in a supply chain flows upstream toward the supplier end, downstream toward the customer end, and also back and forth within the entities and between the chain and external entities, such as governments, markets, and competitors.  "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased inventory accumulation ","  B. Increased holding costs ","  C. Increased handling costs ","  D. Increased cumulative setup time"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions ","  B. One supply chain for all goods ","  C. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods ","  D. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"A manager decides to source their key Just-in-Time (JIT) manufacturing goods from a local producer even though an overseas producer sells identical goods for less, even with the added cost of shipping. Which of the following is this manager most likely emphasizing?","choices":["A. Affordability ","  B. Positive supply chain contribution ","  C. Quality ","  D. Availability "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The availability of the good is being emphasized because the manager needs a reliable supply of goods even if it costs more to get the good when it is needed for the JIT process.  "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Sourcing ","  B. Making ","  C. Planning ","  D. Delivering "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates ","  B. A special international rate ","  C. The local country rate ","  D. The rate in the country of the headquarters "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following approaches to production scheduling accurately incorporates the theory of constraints?","choices":["A. Speed up production after the bottleneck. ","  B. Decrease inventory at the front of the bottleneck. ","  C. Speed up production in front of the bottleneck. ","  D. Slow the process down to the bottleneck's speed."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The theory of constraints focuses attention on slowest-moving part of a manufacturing process because it determines the maximum output of the process. Speeding up production before the constraint only produces an oversupply of inventory in front of the constraint, while speeding up the process after the constraint will result only in a lack of inventory after the constraint. Avoiding either of these problems requires running the process at the speed of the constraint.   "},{"question":"A focus on quality, affordability, or availability indicates a focus on which of the following?","choices":["A. Social value ","  B. Financial value ","  C. Customer value ","  D. Collaborative value"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Depending upon the market being served, a supply chain may be managed with an eye to delivering one or more of the following values to its end customers: quality, affordability, availability, or service. "},{"question":"A nucleus firm in the banking industry uses independent brokers to market new stock issues and has been successful in this channel. After investing some profits in the firm itself, they choose to reward their stockholders by distributing all remaining profits in a special dividend even though independent brokers are prohibited from owning these shares. Which of the following has this firm forgotten to account for in its creation of financial value?","choices":["A. Gains must be fairly distributed among stakeholders. ","  B. Tradeoffs must not be self-defeating. ","  C. Independent brokers should be rewarded through social incentives and reminded that shareholders must come first. ","  D. It takes money to make money. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Possibly the most common mistake in this regard is to send all cost savings all the way to the consumers' end of the chain, which in this case is the shareholders. And perhaps most challenging of all in a lateral supply chain is the need for productive sharing of any financial gains. As noted earlier, a powerful nucleus firm can gather in the benefits of an alteration in the placement of inventory (or any other process change) at the expense of other stakeholders such as the independent brokers. "},{"question":"With the theory of supply chain versus supply chain in competition, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. Investments in suppliers shared by a competitor will increase the partnership with that supplier to the detriment of the competitor. ","  B. Industries with a small number of dominant suppliers are not ideal but are best coordinated using horizontal supply chains. ","  C. When supply chains share suppliers, alignment of business strategies with supply chain strategies is facilitated. ","  D. Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors at a risk of losing proprietary data"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors, but at the very least the situation invites conflict of interest. Insofar as manufacturers want to keep their designs and processes proprietary, they take a risk when they link up with competing component suppliers.  "},{"question":"Many Japanese companies use keiretsu to avoid which of the following?","choices":["A. The semifunctional enterprise stage (Stage 2) ","  B. Lacking specialization and focus in a network of independent firms ","  C. Needing to abandon the control and full integration of a vertical environment ","  D. The challenges of synchronizing a network of independent firms "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Keiretsu is an intermediate form of integration that differs from vertical integration or horizontal integration in that suppliers and customers are not completely independent but instead own significant stakes in one another. This helps the network of firms be more willing to consider each other's needs.  "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.) ","  B. Top management ","  C. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees ","  D. Middle management "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve.  "},{"question":"Volume growth is a key performance indicator for which of the following?","choices":["A. Product merchandizing ","  B. Customer service ","  C. Supply chain variability ","  D. Replenishment "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Volume growth measures the success of merchandizing efforts.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  B. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software ","  C. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  D. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is among the Global Supply Chain Forum's eight essential supply chain management processes?","choices":["A. Production ","  B. Purchasing ","  C. Logistics ","  D. Order fulfillment"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is one of the GSCF's essential processes. The other answers identify activities that contribute to the supply chain processes, but they are not among the processes identified in the GSCF's model. "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  B. Judgment of each participant's direct supervisor ","  C. Approval of top management ","  D. Outcome of the change initiative "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning).  "},{"question":"The antiterrorism measures developed by the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism (C-TPAT) apply to which of the following entities?","choices":["A. C-TPAT corporate participants ","  B. All U.S. importers ","  C. All U.S. exporters ","  D. All domestic and foreign firms involved in U.S. supply chains "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Participation in the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism is voluntary, and compliance with its regulations is required only of participants. Failure to comply can lead to suspension of privileges or cancellation of partnership.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network. ","  B. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members. ","  C. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results. ","  D. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Has a lower price than the competitor's product ","  B. Can reach the market quickly ","  C. Has more features than the competitor's product ","  D. Can be sold for a positive return"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably).  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share. ","  B. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  C. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. ","  D. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure.  "},{"question":"Which of the following scenarios is most likely to occur at the Stage 3 (integrated enterprise) level of supply chain evolution or higher?","choices":["A. Sales rep finds a market opportunity but is unable to bring it to the attention of new product development. ","  B. Warehouses are located near each market and have more than enough inventory to handle the next big sale. ","  C. Manager provides a broad mission and backs it up with threats for nonconformance. ","  D. Dominant partner coerces others to force price concessions. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"When firms first move past internal integration into external collaboration, the first collaboration can also be the last one if the arrangement fails to produce positive results for the weaker partner as well as for the channel master. Early manufacturer-supplier linkages, for example, were too often the result of coercion by the dominant partner, who was looking for guaranteed on-time delivery of quality items at a relatively low price.  "},{"question":"A firm that is always claiming it has the best processes and highest quality has recently suffered losses because even though they dictate these processes to their long-term Asian suppliers, several of them have, without any explanation, recently had a string of additional costs and quality problems. Which of the following would best help this firm resolve its problems?","choices":["A. Increase visibility with the suppliers and allow the suppliers to suggest processes that work for them. ","  B. Find new suppliers who can follow the firm's process more closely. ","  C. Move production so that it is once again performed correctly in-house. ","  D. Enforce the provisions of the suppliers' contracts through litigation."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Cultures tend to be egocentric and thus tend to resist external collaboration. They feel that their ways are the best ways of doing things and will often reject a different way without even considering it. Culture conflicts are increased when each company relies on its own sources of information and is unable to see the impact of its choices on other areas of the network. When companies don't see the negative results of their actions, they can't learn from their mistakes. Increasing visibility will correct some of these problems, but processes may need to be adaptable to the area in which they are performed, such as that litigation is seen as a betrayal of a relationship in many Asian countries.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the potential for different quality methods to work together?","choices":["A. JIT and lean are compatible with each other but not with six-sigma. ","  B. JIT, lean, and six-sigma work best when combined. ","  C. JIT and six-sigma are compatible with each other but not with lean. ","  D. Six-sigma and lean are compatible with each other but not with JIT. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The three quality-based systems are mutually compatible and give the best results when combined to eliminate wasted materials, wasted time, defects, and variability.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Bottleneck materials ","  C. Leveragable materials ","  D. Commodity materials "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs. "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. ","  B. SCOR applies to product development. ","  C. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  D. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain responsiveness ","  B. Supply chain reliability ","  C. Supply chain flexibility ","  D. Supply chain adaptability "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Fuel supplier ","  B. Electric power utility ","  C. Manufacturer connected to electric grid ","  D. Facility maintenance"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer.  "},{"question":"In the Global Supply Chain Forum supply chain management model, which of the following combine to create a link between adjacent partners and form a context for the other six processes?","choices":["A. Manufacturing flow management and order fulfillment ","  B. Product development and commercialization and manufacturing flow management ","  C. Supplier relationship management and demand management ","  D. Customer relationship management and supplier relationship management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Customer relationship management (CRM) and supplier relationship management (SRM) are at the heart of the eight processes. Their combination creates and manages the link between adjacent partners in the chain and provides the context for the other processes.  "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching. ","  B. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible. ","  C. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs. ","  D. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a tool that helps visually identify the 20 percent of causes responsible for 80 percent of problems (using those percentages as approximations)?","choices":["A. Process map ","  B. Pareto diagram ","  C. Checklist ","  D. Focus group"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A Pareto diagram applies the Pareto principle that 80 percent of results tend to be the result of 20 percent of causes. The diagram helps visually distinguish the small number of causes that result in the largest number of process flaws. Focus groups are useful in gathering customer complaints: the flaws in the diagram.  "},{"question":"China has restricted U.S. imports of wood pallets for which of the following reasons?","choices":["A. Lack of Chinese wood content in pallets ","  B. Excessive weight of soft wood pallets ","  C. Risk of insect pests in the wood ","  D. Pallets weren't being properly recycled "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"China, the European Union, and other destinations have placed restrictions on wood pallets coming from the United States because of possible infestation by harmful insects. "},{"question":"Benchmarking is a tool used to carry out which function of a quality initiative?","choices":["A. Implement a process improvement initiative. ","  B. Analyze the steps in a process. ","  C. Assess process performance. ","  D. Determine the roles in an initiative."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Benchmarks provide a point of comparison that allows a project team to assess the relative effectiveness of a process and set a goal for its improvement.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Has more features than the competitor's product ","  B. Has a lower price than the competitor's product ","  C. Can be sold for a positive return ","  D. Can reach the market quickly"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably).  "},{"question":"Which of the following is among the Global Supply Chain Forum's eight essential supply chain management processes?","choices":["A. Purchasing ","  B. Logistics ","  C. Production ","  D. Order fulfillment "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is one of the GSCF's essential processes. The other answers identify activities that contribute to the supply chain processes, but they are not among the processes identified in the GSCF's model.  "},{"question":"Corporate participants in C-TPAT (Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism) receive which one of the following benefits?","choices":["A. Increased protection for overseas shipments ","  B. Exemption from border inspections ","  C. Reduced tariffs ","  D. Greater reliance on self-policing "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Corporate partners in C-TPAT benefit from a greater emphasis on self-policing rather than customs verification and other benefits. "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints ","  B. Successive approximations of a perfected process ","  C. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features ","  D. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  B. Judgment of each participant's direct supervisor ","  C. Outcome of the change initiative ","  D. Approval of top management "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning).  "},{"question":"A nucleus firm in the banking industry uses independent brokers to market new stock issues and has been successful in this channel. After investing some profits in the firm itself, they choose to reward their stockholders by distributing all remaining profits in a special dividend even though independent brokers are prohibited from owning these shares. Which of the following has this firm forgotten to account for in its creation of financial value?","choices":["A. It takes money to make money. ","  B. Tradeoffs must not be self-defeating. ","  C. Independent brokers should be rewarded through social incentives and reminded that shareholders must come first. ","  D. Gains must be fairly distributed among stakeholders"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Possibly the most common mistake in this regard is to send all cost savings all the way to the consumers' end of the chain, which in this case is the shareholders. And perhaps most challenging of all in a lateral supply chain is the need for productive sharing of any financial gains. As noted earlier, a powerful nucleus firm can gather in the benefits of an alteration in the placement of inventory (or any other process change) at the expense of other stakeholders such as the independent brokers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to product development. ","  B. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. ","  C. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  D. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Improved business focus and expertise ","  B. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions ","  C. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  D. Technology to handle the increased complexity "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top.  "},{"question":"Which of the following results from having a firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) software designed for automatic calculation of corporate taxes?","choices":["A. The software will earn a tax deduction based on its use in tax planning. ","  B. The firm will most likely underreport income. ","  C. The firms will risk violating Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) reporting requirements. ","  D. The software will most likely fail to take legally available deductions."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"ERP software can be programmed to determine the firm's exact tax liability and, at the same time, comply with Sarbanes-Oxley and earn a deduction for itself.  "},{"question":"Where on a balanced scorecard would you enter a seminar on financial management for nonfinancial managers developed for the sales managers?","choices":["A. Financial perspective ","  B. Innovation and learning perspective ","  C. Business process perspective ","  D. Customer perspective "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Regardless of the content of the seminar, training belongs in the innovation and learning quadrant of the balanced scorecard.  "},{"question":"When setting supply chain strategy at a firm that isn't the nucleus firm, which of the following is the most important to focus on?","choices":["A. What's good for the nucleus firm ","  B. What's good for one's own firm ","  C. What's good for extended supply chain partners ","  D. What's good for the final customer"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"When it comes to supply chains, it's what's good for the final customer that counts, not what's good for the nucleus company or even what seems to be good for the supply chain itself. Supply chain management ought to be all about giving the final customer the right product at the right time and place for the right price.  "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain adaptability ","  B. Supply chain reliability ","  C. Supply chain responsiveness ","  D. Supply chain flexibility "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"The antiterrorism measures developed by the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism (C-TPAT) apply to which of the following entities?","choices":["A. All domestic and foreign firms involved in U.S. supply chains ","  B. C-TPAT corporate participants ","  C. All U.S. importers ","  D. All U.S. exporters"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Participation in the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism is voluntary, and compliance with its regulations is required only of participants. Failure to comply can lead to suspension of privileges or cancellation of partnership.  "},{"question":"A value stream map is associated with which of the following improvement methods?","choices":["A. Lean ","  B. Focus groups ","  C. Job redesign ","  D. Six-sigma "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Value stream maps are paper-and-pencil sketches of the steps in a process overlaid with supporting information flows. They are used in lean projects to identify non-value-adding steps for elimination. (The first map shows all steps; a second map shows the process with all non-value-adding steps eliminated.)  "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. A special international rate ","  B. The local country rate ","  C. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates ","  D. The rate in the country of the headquarters "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions.  "},{"question":"A channel master is finding that many of its current partners have begun finding ways of bypassing the firm, while others are performing redundant functions that cause unnecessary competition among supply chain members. Which of the following is a likely cause of this behavior?","choices":["A. Working with competitors as peers ","  B. Exploitation of power-based relationships ","  C. Weakest collaborative links becoming bottlenecks ","  D. Individual incentives conflicting with organizational goals "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Power-based relationships occur where a nucleus firm dictates the terms of the relationship to the other members. While its profits increase, other members of the network may suffer losses. When this occurs, the disadvantaged partners may rebel. Resistance may result in redundancy, loss of overall profitability for the chain, or an actual reversal of the power relationship.  "},{"question":"JIT \"cells\" are laid out to accommodate which of the following?","choices":["A. One product family with similar manufacturing processes ","  B. One specialized type of worker ","  C. One type of machine ","  D. One production process"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Cells are arranged to allow for the most efficient production of a product family manufactured with similar production processes. Workers and machines are grouped to provide all the skills and equipment required for that product family in an efficiently arranged layout.  "},{"question":"Which of the following illustrates an emphasis on the affordability aspect of customer value?","choices":["A. A cement-mixing tub of greater durability and flexibility than similar offerings ","  B. No-hassle, no-negotiation sales price on new cars at a dealership ","  C. A luxury boat priced lower than other luxury boats of similar size and feature ","  D. Same-day delivery of goods via courier-to-air-to-courier "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Affordability does not refer solely to discount goods but to goods that have a price at the lower end of an appropriate price level for the value received.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Adaptability ","  B. Responsiveness ","  C. Reliability ","  D. Sustainability "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods ","  B. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods ","  C. One supply chain for all goods ","  D. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"According to research by Rice and Hoppe, the theory that supply chains of companies allied as partners in supply networks may compete directly with other similar supply chain networks in reality exists only with which of the following?","choices":["A. Individual companies such as an automobile manufacturer based on their supply chain management capabilities ","  B. Horizontal supply chains such as PC sales ","  C. Channel masters such as retail consumer good giants ","  D. Vertical supply chains such as poultry sellers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Groups of companies allied as partners in supply networks will compete with other groups of companies allied in supply networks. The networks will be distinct from one another in all ways. The head-to-head supply chain competitors tend toward the vertically integrated company rather than the extended enterprise. The fashion and poultry industries are suggested as arenas in which supply chains compete with supply chains.  "},{"question":"A midsize manufacturing firm works with a large retailer as its primary customer and has several sources of supply for each of its key materials. The firm is trying to align its supply chain strategy with corporate strategy. Which of the following must be the primary consideration when this firm is setting corporate strategy?","choices":["A. Setting the firm's own strategic objectives to leverage a more profitable margin from their customers ","  B. The objectives of the ultimate end customer regardless of what any intermediaries may interject ","  C. Alignment with the strategic objectives of their suppliers to generate long-term stability of supply ","  D. Alignment with the retailer's corporate strategy to holistically maintain a profitable relationship "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Because the retailer in this situation appears to be the nucleus firm, alignment of the retailer's corporate strategy with the firm's own corporate strategy must take precedence over other considerations.  "},{"question":"When defining roles for each party in a collaboration, how should these interactions be structured and why?","choices":["A. Reciprocal interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. ","  B. Sequential interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  C. Sequential interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. ","  D. Reciprocal interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Conflicts can occur when defining roles for each party if the roles make one party more dependent upon another than they wish to be. To alleviate this common problem, networks should avoid sequential interdependence, in which the second party cannot begin work until the first party is done; instead, they should establish reciprocal independence, in which the exchange of tasks and services occurs in both directions. "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Employee learning and growth ","  B. Customer perspective ","  C. Internal business process improvement ","  D. Financials"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line.  "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Root cause ","  B. Interlocking business ownership ","  C. Continuous process improvement ","  D. Display cards used as production signals"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"The Level 2 SCOR measure for cost of goods sold includes which of the following supply chain costs?","choices":["A. Costs of sourcing and making ","  B. Costs of sourcing, making, and delivering ","  C. Costs of planning, sourcing, making, and delivering ","  D. Total costs of planning, sourcing, making, delivering, and returning "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The SCOR Level 2 metric for cost of goods sold includes all the costs related to the five SCOR supply chain processes (plan, source, make, deliver, and return).  "},{"question":"The developers of the balanced scorecard approach to performance were concerned that traditional metrics placed too much emphasis on which of the following considerations?","choices":["A. Current profitability ","  B. Past financial performance ","  C. Future performance objectives ","  D. Customer complaints"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The developers of the balanced scorecard, Robert S. Kaplan and David Norton, believed that the traditional reliance on financial measures of performance placed too much emphasis on the past and too little on the present and future and, in addition, ignored other types of measures that contribute to success. "},{"question":"Many Japanese companies use keiretsu to avoid which of the following?","choices":["A. Needing to abandon the control and full integration of a vertical environment ","  B. The semifunctional enterprise stage (Stage 2) ","  C. Lacking specialization and focus in a network of independent firms ","  D. The challenges of synchronizing a network of independent firms "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Keiretsu is an intermediate form of integration that differs from vertical integration or horizontal integration in that suppliers and customers are not completely independent but instead own significant stakes in one another. This helps the network of firms be more willing to consider each other's needs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. Six-sigma ","  B. JIT ","  C. Kanban ","  D. Lean "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  "},{"question":"According to the functional and innovative product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following would be a proper performance indicator for a typical innovative product?","choices":["A. Aggressively reducing lead times ","  B. Inventory reduction ","  C. High inventory turns ","  D. Design for maximum performance at minimal cost"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The key performance indicators for each supply chain differ because of the product characteristics. Aggressively reducing lead times, for example, is appropriate for innovative products but would be irrelevant for functional products that can be manufactured and delivered on predictable schedules in high volumes.  "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-order innovative product ","  B. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  C. Make-to-stock functional product ","  D. Make-to-order functional product"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of supply chains?","choices":["A. Supply chains run in only one direction, toward the customer. ","  B. Competition is an outside stakeholder to a supply chain that threatens or energizes it. ","  C. Supply chain processes are entirely contained within each entity within a supply chain. ","  D. There are two flows that can be engineered in a chain, products and cash. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Competitors affect the functioning of a supply chain in more ways than one: They can threaten or energize the chain. Sometimes competing businesses directly foster each other's growth by participation in trade associations and joint ventures. Whenever a competitor creates an improved product or business process, the entire marketplace is enriched by the new ideas.  "},{"question":"When an enterprise buys new technology, which one of the following should be the primary selection criterion?","choices":["A. Appropriateness to supply chain strategy ","  B. Features representing the very latest designs ","  C. Processing power ","  D. Low cost "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Strategy should govern choice of technology. Features and processing power should be right for the strategic needs of the enterprise. Low cost is not always the right cost in any purchase. Even a small amount of money is wasted if it doesn't purchase what you need.  "},{"question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 focuses on which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Hazardous materials ","  B. Terrorism ","  C. Financial reporting and controls ","  D. Material content reporting "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Sarbanes-Oxley focuses on financial reporting and controls, including reporting on supply chain controls. Plans to respond to events such as terrorism are included in the reporting requirements, but they are not the focus of the legislation, which was drafted in response to corporate corruption.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers. ","  B. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions. ","  C. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  D. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding supply chain organizations?","choices":["A. There is a long but always finite number of tiers of suppliers in any supply chain. ","  B. A raw material producer has no Tier 1 suppliers. ","  C. Supply chains can loop back on themselves, making suppliers into customers. ","  D. Service supplier considerations are important only after a manufacturing site has been selected"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"No matter how far you travel toward the supply end of a supply chain, you will never run out of new tiers of suppliers. A coal mine may ship coal to a generating plant that supplies power to the manufacturer that produces a machine that is shipped to a distributor that sells mining equipment to the same mine that began the process: supply chains can double back on themselves.  "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  B. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  C. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping ","  D. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. ","  B. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs. ","  C. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. ","  D. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a true prerequisite for developing collaborative relationships central to supply chain strategy?","choices":["A. Auditable information exchange to share knowledge, not just data ","  B. Deterrence-based arrangements such as aligning sales and management goals to collaborative objectives ","  C. Sharing some benefits but none of the burdens of collaboration with partners ","  D. The most advanced communications hardware and software "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Auditable information exchange and technology for connectivity should allow sharing of knowledge, not mere data. The required technology itself may not have to be the most powerful, but it must be compatible to allow information exchange.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following constitutes the range of acceptable variability on a six-sigma control chart?","choices":["A. Zero variability ","  B. Mean defects plus/minus 3 sigmas ","  C. Mean defects plus 6 sigmas ","  D. Mean defects plus/minus 6 sigmas"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The acceptable range of variability is the number of defects within a range of six sigmas (standard deviations) above and below the mean number of defects. The chart helps control the variability in a process.  "},{"question":"According to total quality theory, which of the following would be of primary importance to document during the analysis phase of a continuous improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Staff-level views of the practical difficulties involved in carrying out the process ","  B. A thorough, factual description of the process ","  C. Executive-level positions on the importance of the process ","  D. Customer attitudes toward the product produced by the process "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Quality theory emphasizes the importance of data; therefore, improvement initiatives begin with a complete, unbiased, factual description of the process.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following approaches to production scheduling accurately incorporates the theory of constraints?","choices":["A. Speed up production after the bottleneck. ","  B. Speed up production in front of the bottleneck. ","  C. Slow the process down to the bottleneck's speed. ","  D. Decrease inventory at the front of the bottleneck. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The theory of constraints focuses attention on slowest-moving part of a manufacturing process because it determines the maximum output of the process. Speeding up production before the constraint only produces an oversupply of inventory in front of the constraint, while speeding up the process after the constraint will result only in a lack of inventory after the constraint. Avoiding either of these problems requires running the process at the speed of the constraint.  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Facility maintenance ","  B. Electric power utility ","  C. Fuel supplier ","  D. Manufacturer connected to electric grid "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer.  "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  B. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following tools provides a visual method for tracking process variance as part of an improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Control chart ","  B. Pareto diagram ","  C. Process map ","  D. Oliver Wight checklist "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A control chart tracks process variance, allowing a project team to see quickly when defects have spiked to unacceptable levels. It can be used to manage as well as improve a process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following continuous improvement methodologies focuses on reduction of defects to statistical insignificance?","choices":["A. Six-sigma ","  B. Theory of constraints ","  C. Just-in-Time (JIT) ","  D. Lean"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Six-sigma seeks to limit defects to no more than 3.4 per million opportunities. Of course, no initiative sets out to increase defects, but six-sigma makes defect reduction its specific objective.  "},{"question":"Company A has installed supply chain management (SCM) software to achieve cross-functional integration. However, some members of the overall value chain that are not directly part of the supply chain itself have not provided the desired level of support for SCM initiatives. Which of the following departments is most likely to be the one lacking in support?","choices":["A. Marketing and sales ","  B. Human resources ","  C. Inbound logistics ","  D. Customer service "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Human resources is part of the value chain support activities that sustain the supply chain. The incorrect answers are all directly part of the supply chain. Managers from outside the supply chain often don't understand the requirements of supply chain management, can't distinguish value chain from supply chain, and consequently don't provide the SCM support required from their areas.  "},{"question":"When the APICS Dictionary, 11th edition, refers to a supply chain as a \"global network,\" which of the following correctly indicates what could comprise this network?","choices":["A. Entities and processes of any size or configuration ","  B. Only international entities or global processes ","  C. Processes of any size or configuration but only international entities ","  D. Entities of any size or configuration but not processes "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The global network referred to in the definition of a supply chain comprises a network of both entities and processes (the engineered flow). A supply chain doesn't have to be global.  "},{"question":"A manager decides to source their key Just-in-Time (JIT) manufacturing goods from a local producer even though an overseas producer sells identical goods for less, even with the added cost of shipping. Which of the following is this manager most likely emphasizing?","choices":["A. Positive supply chain contribution ","  B. Availability ","  C. Affordability ","  D. Quality "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The availability of the good is being emphasized because the manager needs a reliable supply of goods even if it costs more to get the good when it is needed for the JIT process.  "},{"question":"What is the minimum level of enterprise evolution in which a firm might use a logistics supplier to integrate with external members and also internally combine warehousing and transportation activities to optimize cost versus customer service?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A company at Stage 3 will make advances such as carrying out warehousing and transportation decisions in tandem to achieve the optimal balance of cost-effectiveness and customer service. At this point, the nucleus firm may begin to take a step toward integration with the external members of the chain by contracting with a logistics supplier.  "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Warehouse location decisions ","  B. Transfer cost decisions ","  C. Real property acquisitions ","  D. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility. "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A new supply chain ","  B. A new product ","  C. A new corporate organization chart ","  D. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative. "},{"question":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of training at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Customer-facing employees only ","  B. Top management only ","  C. All management levels ","  D. All levels "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of all process participants, from top management to basic service or shop-floor employees, and it includes training at all levels.  "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Pallets ","  B. Protective packaging ","  C. Shipping containers ","  D. Conveyers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory.  "},{"question":"In a TQM initiative, the definition of \"defect\" is determined by which of the following?","choices":["A. Supply chain manager ","  B. Top management ","  C. Project team ","  D. Customer"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"According to TQM methodology, defects are defined from the customer's point of view.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of contracts for partnerships?","choices":["A. Contracts should always be used in the negotiation process to keep relationships true to the agreement. ","  B. Cultural differences in contracts and problem resolution styles should be a primary consideration when arranging formal contracts. ","  C. Contracts should be fixed at the start of the relationship because alterations are difficult to enact between multiple parties. ","  D. Courts can become involved in conflicts in most Asian countries without long-term detriment to a relationship. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Contracts, policies and procedures, and informal conflict resolution must be sensitive to cultural differences. While courts can become involved in conflicts in the United States without long-term detriment, the opposite is true in most Asian countries.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following authorities has issued directives mandating reporting, reduction, and recycling of heavy metals in end-of-life electronics products?","choices":["A. United States government ","  B. Chinese government ","  C. United Nations ","  D. European Union"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The European Union has issued several directives regarding hazardous components of electronics products, including the Waste from Electronic Equipment directive (WEEE) and the directive restricting the use of heavy metals and retardants in electrical and electronic equipment (RoHS). "},{"question":"Which of the following members of the firm are typically involved in continuous process improvement initiatives?","choices":["A. Middle managers ","  B. Executives ","  C. All members of the firm, including executives, managers, and labor ","  D. Shop-floor workers and supervisors "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Continuous process improvement requires the participation of everyone involved in the targeted processes, the executives who are accountable for the process, the managers responsible for directing it, and the workers who carry it out.  "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Making ","  B. Planning ","  C. Sourcing ","  D. Delivering "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members. ","  B. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. ","  C. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network. ","  D. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"Consider a simplified supply chain in which Lucy sells psychiatric advice from a booth to her classmates for five cents. Subconsciously, she gets her information from her psychiatrist parent and from her pastor. Which of the following are Tier 2 suppliers in this model?","choices":["A. Lucy ","  B. Parent/pastor ","  C. Higher education/seminary ","  D. There are no Tier 2 suppliers in this situation. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lucy's parent and pastor are the Tier 1 suppliers to Lucy, the service producer. They owe their supply of information to either higher education or a seminary, so these sources are the Tier 2 suppliers.  "},{"question":"If a firm has 25 days of accounts payables outstanding and 30 days invested in inventory and their cash-to-cash cycle time is 80 days, how many days of accounts receivables do they have?","choices":["A. 105 days ","  B. 80 days ","  C. 75 days ","  D. 50 days "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The correct answer is 75 days: 80 days (cash to cash) + 25 days (payables) - 30 days (inventory) = 75 days receivables. The cash-to-cash cycle (or cash conversion cycle) is the number of days between the time a firm pays for raw materials and the time it receives payment for finished goods. The equation for calculating the cash-to-cash cycle is Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time = Average Inventory Collection Period + Average Receivables Processing Period - Average Payables Period; therefore, Days of Accounts Receivable = Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time + Days of Accounts Payable - Days of Inventory.  "},{"question":"In SCOR Level 1, if you divide the sum of the cycle times for all orders delivered by the total number of orders delivered, you are using a metric for which of the following supply chain attributes?","choices":["A. Reliability ","  B. Adaptability ","  C. Flexibility ","  D. Responsiveness "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Average actual cycle time (sum of cycle times divided by number of deliveries) measures the responsiveness of the supply chain. It doesn't tell you if the deliveries were on time, which would be a reliability metric.  "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Bottleneck material ","  B. Commodity material ","  C. Leveragable material ","  D. Direct/core competency material"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"At which of the following stages would a company be if it has multiple uncoordinated improvement efforts occurring sequentially instead of in concurrence, such as inventory reduction, better forecasting techniques, and lower cost procurement?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A company at Stage 2 will have multiple initiatives to improve individual functional areas, but these will not generally be coordinated with one another and will therefore fall short of their potential for reducing costs, improving margins, expanding markets, or delivering better service.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  B. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective ","  C. A limited number of essential supply chain processes ","  D. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer ","  B. Collection and accounting for sales taxes ","  C. Compliance with government regulations ","  D. Supplier management"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers ","  B. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers ","  C. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  D. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection.  "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Job tasks are simplified. ","  B. Job responsibilities expand. ","  C. Jobs become more specialized. ","  D. Jobs are not a focus of change. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"Volume growth is a key performance indicator for which of the following?","choices":["A. Product merchandizing ","  B. Supply chain variability ","  C. Customer service ","  D. Replenishment"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Volume growth measures the success of merchandizing efforts.  "},{"question":"A manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, and retailer all agree to base their orders on actual consumer orders instead of performing detailed forecasts based on each party's Tier 1 customer's actual orders. Which of the following will result, and what are the likely risks of this method?","choices":["A. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect. ","  B. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  C. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  D. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The firms have decided to move to a make-to-order environment, moving the push/pull frontier back to the manufacturer, which will reduce the bullwhip effect and the risk of inventory obsolescence, but at the risk of greater overtime and rush orders if there is a sudden spike in demand.  "},{"question":"According to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model, if a refrigerator manufacturing company is at the center of the model, the supplier of materials to the sheet metal supplier has only which of the following processes to perform in relation to the manufacturer?","choices":["A. Plan, source, make, deliver, return  ","  B. Plan, source, return ","  C. Make, source, deliver ","  D. Plan, deliver, return"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"From the perspective of the manufacturer, the supplier of metal to the sheet metal suppliers is on the second tier and may join in planning, but the manufacturer is otherwise concerned only with its ability to deliver and return goods as needed. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  B. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software ","  C. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  D. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Commodity materials ","  C. Bottleneck materials ","  D. Leveragable materials"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. ","  B. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  C. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers. ","  D. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure.  "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased handling costs ","  B. Increased cumulative setup time ","  C. Increased holding costs ","  D. Increased inventory accumulation"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible. ","  B. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders. ","  C. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching. ","  D. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change. "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  B. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used. ","  C. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  D. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations.  "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.) ","  B. Top management ","  C. Middle management ","  D. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve.  "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Process benchmarking ","  B. Oliver Wight benchmarking ","  C. Competitive benchmarking ","  D. Best-in-class benchmarking "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"A focus on quality, affordability, or availability indicates a focus on which of the following?","choices":["A. Social value ","  B. Collaborative value ","  C. Customer value ","  D. Financial value"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Depending upon the market being served, a supply chain may be managed with an eye to delivering one or more of the following values to its end customers: quality, affordability, availability, or service.  "},{"question":"The developers of the balanced scorecard approach to performance were concerned that traditional metrics placed too much emphasis on which of the following considerations?","choices":["A. Current profitability ","  B. Customer complaints ","  C. Future performance objectives ","  D. Past financial performance"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The developers of the balanced scorecard, Robert S. Kaplan and David Norton, believed that the traditional reliance on financial measures of performance placed too much emphasis on the past and too little on the present and future and, in addition, ignored other types of measures that contribute to success.  "},{"question":"According to a noted Japanese approach to analyzing business process problems, why is it necessary to ask \"Why?\" as many as five times when seeking the cause of a process defect?","choices":["A. There may be more than one cause for the defect. ","  B. Most employees won't admit making an error the first few times they are asked. ","  C. Most defects tend to have multiple causes, not just one. ","  D. First responses tend to name superficial causes rather than the root causes. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A Japanese method of root cause analysis referred to as \"Why? Why? Why? Why? Why?\" is based on the idea that it's not always easy to identify the root cause of a customer complaint or other process failure; the first suggestion is likely to be the result of bias or superficial analysis.  "},{"question":"The Global Supply Chain Forum (GSCF) defines supply chain management as \"the integration of key business processes from end user through original suppliers that provides products, services, and information that add value for customers and other stakeholders.\" Which two processes are considered to constitute the core of supply chain management in the GSCF model?","choices":["A. Customer and supplier management ","  B. Demand management and supplier management ","  C. Customer service management and manufacturing flow management ","  D. Order management and supplier relationship management "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"At the heart of the GSCF model is the combination of customer relationship management and supplier relationship management, because these two processes create and manage the link between adjacent partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Volume growth is a key performance indicator for which of the following?","choices":["A. Customer service ","  B. Supply chain variability ","  C. Product merchandizing ","  D. Replenishment"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Volume growth measures the success of merchandizing efforts.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following constitutes the range of acceptable variability on a six-sigma control chart?","choices":["A. Zero variability ","  B. Mean defects plus/minus 3 sigmas ","  C. Mean defects plus 6 sigmas ","  D. Mean defects plus/minus 6 sigmas "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The acceptable range of variability is the number of defects within a range of six sigmas (standard deviations) above and below the mean number of defects. The chart helps control the variability in a process. "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Top management ","  B. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees ","  C. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.) ","  D. Middle management"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve.  "},{"question":"Which of the following could be a key performance indicator (KPI) for replenishment?","choices":["A. Inventory turns ","  B. Volume growth ","  C. Introduction lead time ","  D. Order fill rate "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fill rate provides a measure of the success of the key process of replenishment. A high fill rate indicates good performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding a supply chain?","choices":["A. Services may be part of a manufacturing supply chain but do not have a distinct supply chain themselves. ","  B. Information flows upstream, downstream, and between network members and external entities. ","  C. An electrical power producer that powers a manufacturer's plant is downstream from the manufacturer. ","  D. Cash flows downstream while materials flow upstream."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The information in a supply chain flows upstream toward the supplier end, downstream toward the customer end, and also back and forth within the entities and between the chain and external entities, such as governments, markets, and competitors.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  B. SCOR applies to product development. ","  C. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns. ","  D. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. Successive approximations of a perfected process ","  B. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints ","  C. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems ","  D. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following authorities has issued directives mandating reporting, reduction, and recycling of heavy metals in end-of-life electronics products?","choices":["A. European Union ","  B. United States government ","  C. Chinese government ","  D. United Nations"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The European Union has issued several directives regarding hazardous components of electronics products, including the Waste from Electronic Equipment directive (WEEE) and the directive restricting the use of heavy metals and retardants in electrical and electronic equipment (RoHS). "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Leveragable materials ","  C. Bottleneck materials ","  D. Commodity materials"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs.  "},{"question":"A nucleus firm in the banking industry uses independent brokers to market new stock issues and has been successful in this channel. After investing some profits in the firm itself, they choose to reward their stockholders by distributing all remaining profits in a special dividend even though independent brokers are prohibited from owning these shares. Which of the following has this firm forgotten to account for in its creation of financial value?","choices":["A. It takes money to make money. ","  B. Gains must be fairly distributed among stakeholders. ","  C. Independent brokers should be rewarded through social incentives and reminded that shareholders must come first. ","  D. Tradeoffs must not be self-defeating."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Possibly the most common mistake in this regard is to send all cost savings all the way to the consumers' end of the chain, which in this case is the shareholders. And perhaps most challenging of all in a lateral supply chain is the need for productive sharing of any financial gains. As noted earlier, a powerful nucleus firm can gather in the benefits of an alteration in the placement of inventory (or any other process change) at the expense of other stakeholders such as the independent brokers.  "},{"question":"What is the minimum level of enterprise evolution in which a firm might use a logistics supplier to integrate with external members and also internally combine warehousing and transportation activities to optimize cost versus customer service?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A company at Stage 3 will make advances such as carrying out warehousing and transportation decisions in tandem to achieve the optimal balance of cost-effectiveness and customer service. At this point, the nucleus firm may begin to take a step toward integration with the external members of the chain by contracting with a logistics supplier.  "},{"question":"If a firm has 25 days of accounts payables outstanding and 30 days invested in inventory and their cash-to-cash cycle time is 80 days, how many days of accounts receivables do they have?","choices":["A. 105 days ","  B. 80 days ","  C. 75 days ","  D. 50 days"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The correct answer is 75 days: 80 days (cash to cash) + 25 days (payables) - 30 days (inventory) = 75 days receivables. The cash-to-cash cycle (or cash conversion cycle) is the number of days between the time a firm pays for raw materials and the time it receives payment for finished goods. The equation for calculating the cash-to-cash cycle is Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time = Average Inventory Collection Period + Average Receivables Processing Period - Average Payables Period; therefore, Days of Accounts Receivable = Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time + Days of Accounts Payable - Days of Inventory.  "},{"question":"In the Global Supply Chain Forum supply chain management model, which of the following combine to create a link between adjacent partners and form a context for the other six processes?","choices":["A. Manufacturing flow management and order fulfillment ","  B. Supplier relationship management and demand management ","  C. Product development and commercialization and manufacturing flow management ","  D. Customer relationship management and supplier relationship management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Customer relationship management (CRM) and supplier relationship management (SRM) are at the heart of the eight processes. Their combination creates and manages the link between adjacent partners in the chain and provides the context for the other processes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of contracts for partnerships?","choices":["A. Courts can become involved in conflicts in most Asian countries without long-term detriment to a relationship. ","  B. Contracts should be fixed at the start of the relationship because alterations are difficult to enact between multiple parties. ","  C. Cultural differences in contracts and problem resolution styles should be a primary consideration when arranging formal contracts. ","  D. Contracts should always be used in the negotiation process to keep relationships true to the agreement. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Contracts, policies and procedures, and informal conflict resolution must be sensitive to cultural differences. While courts can become involved in conflicts in the United States without long-term detriment, the opposite is true in most Asian countries.  "},{"question":"When defining roles for each party in a collaboration, how should these interactions be structured and why?","choices":["A. Reciprocal interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  B. Reciprocal interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. ","  C. Sequential interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  D. Sequential interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Conflicts can occur when defining roles for each party if the roles make one party more dependent upon another than they wish to be. To alleviate this common problem, networks should avoid sequential interdependence, in which the second party cannot begin work until the first party is done; instead, they should establish reciprocal independence, in which the exchange of tasks and services occurs in both directions.  "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Real property acquisitions ","  B. Transfer cost decisions ","  C. Warehouse location decisions ","  D. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Improved business focus and expertise ","  B. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  C. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions ","  D. Technology to handle the increased complexity "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top.  "},{"question":"According to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model, if a refrigerator manufacturing company is at the center of the model, the supplier of materials to the sheet metal supplier has only which of the following processes to perform in relation to the manufacturer?","choices":["A. Plan, deliver, return ","  B. Make, source, deliver ","  C. Plan, source, make, deliver, return ","  D. Plan, source, return "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"From the perspective of the manufacturer, the supplier of metal to the sheet metal suppliers is on the second tier and may join in planning, but the manufacturer is otherwise concerned only with its ability to deliver and return goods as needed. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"A midsize manufacturing firm works with a large retailer as its primary customer and has several sources of supply for each of its key materials. The firm is trying to align its supply chain strategy with corporate strategy. Which of the following must be the primary consideration when this firm is setting corporate strategy?","choices":["A. Setting the firm's own strategic objectives to leverage a more profitable margin from their customers ","  B. Alignment with the strategic objectives of their suppliers to generate long-term stability of supply ","  C. The objectives of the ultimate end customer regardless of what any intermediaries may interject ","  D. Alignment with the retailer's corporate strategy to holistically maintain a profitable relationship "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Because the retailer in this situation appears to be the nucleus firm, alignment of the retailer's corporate strategy with the firm's own corporate strategy must take precedence over other considerations.  "},{"question":"In a TQM initiative, the definition of \"defect\" is determined by which of the following?","choices":["A. Customer ","  B. Project team ","  C. Supply chain manager ","  D. Top management"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"According to TQM methodology, defects are defined from the customer's point of view.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the people or the metrics involved in supply chain management?","choices":["A. Supply chain management must be the responsibility of a department-level manager who is equal in hierarchy to other department heads. ","  B. Supply chain strategy and control of the related processes depend on having people educated in functional rather than department thinking. ","  C. Performance must be measured by ratios of profitability and velocity, not by a checklist. ","  D. Current supply chain performance is better quantitatively benchmarked against the firm's desired performance than qualitatively benchmarked."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Numbers (quantitative) generally provide the most convincing supporting evidence in the boardroom and investment analyst's office. If you're bragging about your cash-to-cash cycle, for instance, you might say, \"We've got it down from 50 days to 20, and that's below the industry average.\"   "},{"question":"A manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, and retailer all agree to base their orders on actual consumer orders instead of performing detailed forecasts based on each party's Tier 1 customer's actual orders. Which of the following will result, and what are the likely risks of this method?","choices":["A. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  B. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect. ","  C. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  D. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The firms have decided to move to a make-to-order environment, moving the push/pull frontier back to the manufacturer, which will reduce the bullwhip effect and the risk of inventory obsolescence, but at the risk of greater overtime and rush orders if there is a sudden spike in demand.  "},{"question":"A supply chain that produces and sells cigarettes using traditional forecasting at each stage has been experiencing the bullwhip effect. Which of the following has the strongest influence on this effect?","choices":["A. Announced promotions ","  B. Excess supply liquidation ","  C. Safety stock ","  D. Seasonal fluctuations "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Because cigarettes have relatively steady demand, the small variations in demand seen in the forecasting at the retail stage of the supply chain are padded by safety stock. Forecasting at each successive level uses the quantities ordered for forecasting rather than the actual sale amount, resulting in extremely variable demand at the other end of the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following members of the firm are typically involved in continuous process improvement initiatives?","choices":["A. Middle managers ","  B. All members of the firm, including executives, managers, and labor ","  C. Shop-floor workers and supervisors ","  D. Executives"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Continuous process improvement requires the participation of everyone involved in the targeted processes, the executives who are accountable for the process, the managers responsible for directing it, and the workers who carry it out.  "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Protective packaging ","  B. Shipping containers ","  C. Conveyers ","  D. Pallets"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory.  "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain flexibility ","  B. Supply chain adaptability ","  C. Supply chain reliability ","  D. Supply chain responsiveness"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Manufacturer connected to electric grid ","  B. Facility maintenance ","  C. Electric power utility ","  D. Fuel supplier "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software ","  B. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  C. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  D. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Responsiveness ","  B. Reliability ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Sustainability "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market.  "},{"question":"According to the functional and innovative product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following would be a proper performance indicator for a typical innovative product?","choices":["A. Design for maximum performance at minimal cost ","  B. Aggressively reducing lead times ","  C. High inventory turns ","  D. Inventory reduction"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The key performance indicators for each supply chain differ because of the product characteristics. Aggressively reducing lead times, for example, is appropriate for innovative products but would be irrelevant for functional products that can be manufactured and delivered on predictable schedules in high volumes.  "},{"question":"The Level 2 SCOR measure for cost of goods sold includes which of the following supply chain costs?","choices":["A. Costs of sourcing and making ","  B. Costs of sourcing, making, and delivering ","  C. Costs of planning, sourcing, making, and delivering ","  D. Total costs of planning, sourcing, making, delivering, and returning "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The SCOR Level 2 metric for cost of goods sold includes all the costs related to the five SCOR supply chain processes (plan, source, make, deliver, and return).  "},{"question":"What enforcement authority does the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission bring to its role in regard to the provisions of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act?","choices":["A. Authority to impose jail sentences on executives ","  B. Authority to bring cases to criminal court ","  C. Investigative authority only ","  D. Authority to bring civil court actions"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The SEC has the authority to bring civil suits against corporations and individuals it believes to be out of compliance with securities regulations, including the Sarbanes-Oxley Act. It can refer cases to law enforcement agencies, which can institute criminal proceedings.  "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Financials ","  B. Internal business process improvement ","  C. Customer perspective ","  D. Employee learning and growth"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following approaches to production scheduling accurately incorporates the theory of constraints?","choices":["A. Speed up production in front of the bottleneck. ","  B. Slow the process down to the bottleneck's speed. ","  C. Speed up production after the bottleneck. ","  D. Decrease inventory at the front of the bottleneck"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The theory of constraints focuses attention on slowest-moving part of a manufacturing process because it determines the maximum output of the process. Speeding up production before the constraint only produces an oversupply of inventory in front of the constraint, while speeding up the process after the constraint will result only in a lack of inventory after the constraint. Avoiding either of these problems requires running the process at the speed of the constraint.  "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Interlocking business ownership ","  B. Display cards used as production signals ","  C. Root cause ","  D. Continuous process improvement"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Job tasks are simplified. ","  B. Job responsibilities expand. ","  C. Jobs are not a focus of change. ","  D. Jobs become more specialized."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a tool that helps visually identify the 20 percent of causes responsible for 80 percent of problems (using those percentages as approximations)?","choices":["A. Checklist ","  B. Focus group ","  C. Process map ","  D. Pareto diagram"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A Pareto diagram applies the Pareto principle that 80 percent of results tend to be the result of 20 percent of causes. The diagram helps visually distinguish the small number of causes that result in the largest number of process flaws. Focus groups are useful in gathering customer complaints: the flaws in the diagram.  "},{"question":"A manager decides to source their key Just-in-Time (JIT) manufacturing goods from a local producer even though an overseas producer sells identical goods for less, even with the added cost of shipping. Which of the following is this manager most likely emphasizing?","choices":["A. Availability ","  B. Affordability ","  C. Quality ","  D. Positive supply chain contribution"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The availability of the good is being emphasized because the manager needs a reliable supply of goods even if it costs more to get the good when it is needed for the JIT process.  "},{"question":"A firm that is always claiming it has the best processes and highest quality has recently suffered losses because even though they dictate these processes to their long-term Asian suppliers, several of them have, without any explanation, recently had a string of additional costs and quality problems. Which of the following would best help this firm resolve its problems?","choices":["A. Enforce the provisions of the suppliers' contracts through litigation. ","  B. Move production so that it is once again performed correctly in-house. ","  C. Increase visibility with the suppliers and allow the suppliers to suggest processes that work for them. ","  D. Find new suppliers who can follow the firm's process more closely. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Cultures tend to be egocentric and thus tend to resist external collaboration. They feel that their ways are the best ways of doing things and will often reject a different way without even considering it. Culture conflicts are increased when each company relies on its own sources of information and is unable to see the impact of its choices on other areas of the network. When companies don't see the negative results of their actions, they can't learn from their mistakes. Increasing visibility will correct some of these problems, but processes may need to be adaptable to the area in which they are performed, such as that litigation is seen as a betrayal of a relationship in many Asian countries.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  B. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective ","  C. A limited number of essential supply chain processes ","  D. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"Benchmarking is a tool used to carry out which function of a quality initiative?","choices":["A. Assess process performance. ","  B. Determine the roles in an initiative. ","  C. Implement a process improvement initiative. ","  D. Analyze the steps in a process. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Benchmarks provide a point of comparison that allows a project team to assess the relative effectiveness of a process and set a goal for its improvement.  "},{"question":"Where on a balanced scorecard would you enter a seminar on financial management for nonfinancial managers developed for the sales managers?","choices":["A. Customer perspective ","  B. Business process perspective ","  C. Financial perspective ","  D. Innovation and learning perspective"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Regardless of the content of the seminar, training belongs in the innovation and learning quadrant of the balanced scorecard.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following tools provides a visual method for tracking process variance as part of an improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Process map ","  B. Pareto diagram ","  C. Control chart ","  D. Oliver Wight checklist "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A control chart tracks process variance, allowing a project team to see quickly when defects have spiked to unacceptable levels. It can be used to manage as well as improve a process.  "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased cumulative setup time ","  B. Increased handling costs ","  C. Increased inventory accumulation ","  D. Increased holding costs"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"The Global Supply Chain Forum (GSCF) defines supply chain management as \"the integration of key business processes from end user through original suppliers that provides products, services, and information that add value for customers and other stakeholders.\" Which two processes are considered to constitute the core of supply chain management in the GSCF model?","choices":["A. Order management and supplier relationship management ","  B. Customer service management and manufacturing flow management ","  C. Demand management and supplier management ","  D. Customer and supplier management"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"At the heart of the GSCF model is the combination of customer relationship management and supplier relationship management, because these two processes create and manage the link between adjacent partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"China has restricted U.S. imports of wood pallets for which of the following reasons?","choices":["A. Risk of insect pests in the wood ","  B. Pallets weren't being properly recycled ","  C. Excessive weight of soft wood pallets ","  D. Lack of Chinese wood content in pallets "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"China, the European Union, and other destinations have placed restrictions on wood pallets coming from the United States because of possible infestation by harmful insects.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Has more features than the competitor's product ","  B. Can be sold for a positive return ","  C. Can reach the market quickly ","  D. Has a lower price than the competitor's product "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably).  "},{"question":"At which of the following stages would a company be if it has multiple uncoordinated improvement efforts occurring sequentially instead of in concurrence, such as inventory reduction, better forecasting techniques, and lower cost procurement?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A company at Stage 2 will have multiple initiatives to improve individual functional areas, but these will not generally be coordinated with one another and will therefore fall short of their potential for reducing costs, improving margins, expanding markets, or delivering better service.  "},{"question":"With the theory of supply chain versus supply chain in competition, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. When supply chains share suppliers, alignment of business strategies with supply chain strategies is facilitated. ","  B. Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors at a risk of losing proprietary data. ","  C. Investments in suppliers shared by a competitor will increase the partnership with that supplier to the detriment of the competitor. ","  D. Industries with a small number of dominant suppliers are not ideal but are best coordinated using horizontal supply chains. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors, but at the very least the situation invites conflict of interest. Insofar as manufacturers want to keep their designs and processes proprietary, they take a risk when they link up with competing component suppliers.  "},{"question":"When preparing for a potential business disruption, which of the following is valid advice for contingency planners?","choices":["A. After assessing all potential risks, ensure that each one has a plan for continued functioning regardless of the cost. ","  B. Create contingency plans for yourself and for your supply chain partners. ","  C. Having extra stores of inventory is inadequate protection against a disruption in production. ","  D. Contingency plans are the responsibility of each departmental manager in addition to their regular duties."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Don't rely only on extra stores of inventory. There can never be enough of it to cover all potential problems, and it, too, is vulnerable. You need alternate processes to keep functioning after a disaster.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  B. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  C. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used. ","  D. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies the emphasis of the Global Reporting Initiative?","choices":["A. Developing and publishing environmentally sustainable trade practices ","  B. Enforcing UN trade sanctions ","  C. Monitoring terrorist activities ","  D. Policing corporate and supply chain activities"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) is an independent group of organizations, including corporations, that develops and publishes sustainable corporate trade practices in regard to such environmental concerns as emissions, energy and resource consumption, and waste. It works with the UN and is entirely voluntary.  "},{"question":"According to a noted Japanese approach to analyzing business process problems, why is it necessary to ask \"Why?\" as many as five times when seeking the cause of a process defect?","choices":["A. First responses tend to name superficial causes rather than the root causes. ","  B. Most defects tend to have multiple causes, not just one. ","  C. Most employees won't admit making an error the first few times they are asked. ","  D. There may be more than one cause for the defect. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A Japanese method of root cause analysis referred to as \"Why? Why? Why? Why? Why?\" is based on the idea that it's not always easy to identify the root cause of a customer complaint or other process failure; the first suggestion is likely to be the result of bias or superficial analysis.  "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Planning ","  B. Sourcing ","  C. Delivering ","  D. Making"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. The rate in the country of the headquarters ","  B. The local country rate ","  C. A special international rate ","  D. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions.  "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Approval of top management ","  B. Outcome of the change initiative ","  C. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  D. Judgment of each participant's direct superviso"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning).  "},{"question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 focuses on which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Hazardous materials ","  B. Material content reporting ","  C. Terrorism ","  D. Financial reporting and controls"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Sarbanes-Oxley focuses on financial reporting and controls, including reporting on supply chain controls. Plans to respond to events such as terrorism are included in the reporting requirements, but they are not the focus of the legislation, which was drafted in response to corporate corruption.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding a supply chain?","choices":["A. Cash flows downstream while materials flow upstream. ","  B. An electrical power producer that powers a manufacturer's plant is downstream from the manufacturer. ","  C. Services may be part of a manufacturing supply chain but do not have a distinct supply chain themselves. ","  D. Information flows upstream, downstream, and between network members and external entities. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The information in a supply chain flows upstream toward the supplier end, downstream toward the customer end, and also back and forth within the entities and between the chain and external entities, such as governments, markets, and competitors. "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A new supply chain ","  B. A new corporate organization chart ","  C. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale ","  D. A new product "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative.  "},{"question":"JIT \"cells\" are laid out to accommodate which of the following?","choices":["A. One type of machine ","  B. One product family with similar manufacturing processes ","  C. One production process ","  D. One specialized type of worker "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Cells are arranged to allow for the most efficient production of a product family manufactured with similar production processes. Workers and machines are grouped to provide all the skills and equipment required for that product family in an efficiently arranged layout.  "},{"question":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of training at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Customer-facing employees only ","  B. Top management only ","  C. All management levels ","  D. All levels "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of all process participants, from top management to basic service or shop-floor employees, and it includes training at all levels.  "},{"question":"According to research by Rice and Hoppe, the theory that supply chains of companies allied as partners in supply networks may compete directly with other similar supply chain networks in reality exists only with which of the following?","choices":["A. Channel masters such as retail consumer good giants ","  B. Vertical supply chains such as poultry sellers ","  C. Individual companies such as an automobile manufacturer based on their supply chain management capabilities ","  D. Horizontal supply chains such as PC sales "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Groups of companies allied as partners in supply networks will compete with other groups of companies allied in supply networks. The networks will be distinct from one another in all ways. The head-to-head supply chain competitors tend toward the vertically integrated company rather than the extended enterprise. The fashion and poultry industries are suggested as arenas in which supply chains compete with supply chains.  "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  B. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"A channel master is finding that many of its current partners have begun finding ways of bypassing the firm, while others are performing redundant functions that cause unnecessary competition among supply chain members. Which of the following is a likely cause of this behavior?","choices":["A. Weakest collaborative links becoming bottlenecks ","  B. Exploitation of power-based relationships ","  C. Working with competitors as peers ","  D. Individual incentives conflicting with organizational goals  "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Power-based relationships occur where a nucleus firm dictates the terms of the relationship to the other members. While its profits increase, other members of the network may suffer losses. When this occurs, the disadvantaged partners may rebel. Resistance may result in redundancy, loss of overall profitability for the chain, or an actual reversal of the power relationship.  "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Bottleneck material ","  B. Leveragable material ","  C. Direct/core competency material ","  D. Commodity material"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following continuous improvement methodologies focuses on reduction of defects to statistical insignificance?","choices":["A. Six-sigma ","  B. Theory of constraints ","  C. Lean ","  D. Just-in-Time (JIT) "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Six-sigma seeks to limit defects to no more than 3.4 per million opportunities. Of course, no initiative sets out to increase defects, but six-sigma makes defect reduction its specific objective.   "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. Lean ","  B. Six-sigma ","  C. JIT ","  D. Kanban"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  B. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand ","  C. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  D. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  B. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers ","  C. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers ","  D. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection.  "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-order innovative product ","  B. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  C. Make-to-order functional product ","  D. Make-to-stock functional product "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks.  "},{"question":"Consider a simplified supply chain in which Lucy sells psychiatric advice from a booth to her classmates for five cents. Subconsciously, she gets her information from her psychiatrist parent and from her pastor. Which of the following are Tier 2 suppliers in this model?","choices":["A. Lucy ","  B. Parent/pastor ","  C. Higher education/seminary ","  D. There are no Tier 2 suppliers in this situation."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lucy's parent and pastor are the Tier 1 suppliers to Lucy, the service producer. They owe their supply of information to either higher education or a seminary, so these sources are the Tier 2 suppliers.  "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Oliver Wight benchmarking ","  B. Competitive benchmarking ","  C. Process benchmarking ","  D. Best-in-class benchmarking"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the potential for different quality methods to work together?","choices":["A. JIT and lean are compatible with each other but not with six-sigma. ","  B. JIT, lean, and six-sigma work best when combined. ","  C. Six-sigma and lean are compatible with each other but not with JIT. ","  D. JIT and six-sigma are compatible with each other but not with lean. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The three quality-based systems are mutually compatible and give the best results when combined to eliminate wasted materials, wasted time, defects, and variability.  "},{"question":"Which of the following results from having a firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) software designed for automatic calculation of corporate taxes?","choices":["A. The firm will most likely underreport income. ","  B. The software will most likely fail to take legally available deductions. ","  C. The software will earn a tax deduction based on its use in tax planning. ","  D. The firms will risk violating Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) reporting requirements."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"ERP software can be programmed to determine the firm's exact tax liability and, at the same time, comply with Sarbanes-Oxley and earn a deduction for itself.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. ","  B. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. ","  C. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs. ","  D. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following scenarios is most likely to occur at the Stage 3 (integrated enterprise) level of supply chain evolution or higher?","choices":["A. Dominant partner coerces others to force price concessions. ","  B. Warehouses are located near each market and have more than enough inventory to handle the next big sale. ","  C. Manager provides a broad mission and backs it up with threats for nonconformance. ","  D. Sales rep finds a market opportunity but is unable to bring it to the attention of new product development. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"When firms first move past internal integration into external collaboration, the first collaboration can also be the last one if the arrangement fails to produce positive results for the weaker partner as well as for the channel master. Early manufacturer-supplier linkages, for example, were too often the result of coercion by the dominant partner, who was looking for guaranteed on-time delivery of quality items at a relatively low price.  "},{"question":"A focus on quality, affordability, or availability indicates a focus on which of the following?","choices":["A. Customer value ","  B. Financial value ","  C. Social value ","  D. Collaborative value"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Depending upon the market being served, a supply chain may be managed with an eye to delivering one or more of the following values to its end customers: quality, affordability, availability, or service.  "},{"question":"Corporate participants in C-TPAT (Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism) receive which one of the following benefits?","choices":["A. Increased protection for overseas shipments ","  B. Reduced tariffs ","  C. Exemption from border inspections ","  D. Greater reliance on self-policing"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Corporate partners in C-TPAT benefit from a greater emphasis on self-policing rather than customs verification and other benefits.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results. ","  B. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. ","  C. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network. ","  D. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"Which of the following could be a key performance indicator (KPI) for replenishment?","choices":["A. Introduction lead time ","  B. Inventory turns ","  C. Order fill rate ","  D. Volume growth "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fill rate provides a measure of the success of the key process of replenishment. A high fill rate indicates good performance.  "},{"question":"Many Japanese companies use keiretsu to avoid which of the following?","choices":["A. Needing to abandon the control and full integration of a vertical environment ","  B. The semifunctional enterprise stage (Stage 2) ","  C. Lacking specialization and focus in a network of independent firms ","  D. The challenges of synchronizing a network of independent firms "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Keiretsu is an intermediate form of integration that differs from vertical integration or horizontal integration in that suppliers and customers are not completely independent but instead own significant stakes in one another. This helps the network of firms be more willing to consider each other's needs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of supply chains?","choices":["A. There are two flows that can be engineered in a chain, products and cash. ","  B. Competition is an outside stakeholder to a supply chain that threatens or energizes it. ","  C. Supply chain processes are entirely contained within each entity within a supply chain. ","  D. Supply chains run in only one direction, toward the customer. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Competitors affect the functioning of a supply chain in more ways than one: They can threaten or energize the chain. Sometimes competing businesses directly foster each other's growth by participation in trade associations and joint ventures. Whenever a competitor creates an improved product or business process, the entire marketplace is enriched by the new ideas.  "},{"question":"In SCOR Level 1, if you divide the sum of the cycle times for all orders delivered by the total number of orders delivered, you are using a metric for which of the following supply chain attributes?","choices":["A. Adaptability ","  B. Responsiveness ","  C. Flexibility ","  D. Reliability "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Average actual cycle time (sum of cycle times divided by number of deliveries) measures the responsiveness of the supply chain. It doesn't tell you if the deliveries were on time, which would be a reliability metric.  "},{"question":"Which of the following illustrates an emphasis on the affordability aspect of customer value?","choices":["A. A cement-mixing tub of greater durability and flexibility than similar offerings ","  B. Same-day delivery of goods via courier-to-air-to-courier ","  C. A luxury boat priced lower than other luxury boats of similar size and feature ","  D. No-hassle, no-negotiation sales price on new cars at a dealership"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Affordability does not refer solely to discount goods but to goods that have a price at the lower end of an appropriate price level for the value received.  "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs. ","  B. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching. ","  C. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders. ","  D. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change.  "},{"question":"When the APICS Dictionary, 11th edition, refers to a supply chain as a \"global network,\" which of the following correctly indicates what could comprise this network?","choices":["A. Processes of any size or configuration but only international entities ","  B. Entities of any size or configuration but not processes ","  C. Only international entities or global processes ","  D. Entities and processes of any size or configuration "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The global network referred to in the definition of a supply chain comprises a network of both entities and processes (the engineered flow). A supply chain doesn't have to be global.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers. ","  B. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share. ","  C. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  D. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure.  "},{"question":"In the Global Supply Chain Forum supply chain management model, which of the following combine to create a link between adjacent partners and form a context for the other six processes?","choices":["A. Customer relationship management and supplier relationship management ","  B. Product development and commercialization and manufacturing flow management ","  C. Manufacturing flow management and order fulfillment ","  D. Supplier relationship management and demand management "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Customer relationship management (CRM) and supplier relationship management (SRM) are at the heart of the eight processes. Their combination creates and manages the link between adjacent partners in the chain and provides the context for the other processes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is among the Global Supply Chain Forum's eight essential supply chain management processes?","choices":["A. Purchasing ","  B. Production ","  C. Logistics ","  D. Order fulfillment "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is one of the GSCF's essential processes. The other answers identify activities that contribute to the supply chain processes, but they are not among the processes identified in the GSCF's model.  "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Supplier management ","  B. Collection and accounting for sales taxes ","  C. Compliance with government regulations ","  D. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  B. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods ","  B. One supply chain for all goods ","  C. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions ","  D. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following constitutes the range of acceptable variability on a six-sigma control chart?","choices":["A. Zero variability ","  B. Mean defects plus/minus 3 sigmas ","  C. Mean defects plus 6 sigmas ","  D. Mean defects plus/minus 6 sigmas"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The acceptable range of variability is the number of defects within a range of six sigmas (standard deviations) above and below the mean number of defects. The chart helps control the variability in a process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers. ","  B. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions. ","  C. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  D. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things.  "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer ","  B. Supplier management ","  C. Compliance with government regulations ","  D. Collection and accounting for sales taxes "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"When preparing for a potential business disruption, which of the following is valid advice for contingency planners?","choices":["A. Having extra stores of inventory is inadequate protection against a disruption in production. ","  B. Contingency plans are the responsibility of each departmental manager in addition to their regular duties. ","  C. After assessing all potential risks, ensure that each one has a plan for continued functioning regardless of the cost. ","  D. Create contingency plans for yourself and for your supply chain partners. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Don't rely only on extra stores of inventory. There can never be enough of it to cover all potential problems, and it, too, is vulnerable. You need alternate processes to keep functioning after a disaster. "},{"question":"JIT \"cells\" are laid out to accommodate which of the following?","choices":["A. One specialized type of worker ","  B. One product family with similar manufacturing processes ","  C. One type of machine ","  D. One production process "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Cells are arranged to allow for the most efficient production of a product family manufactured with similar production processes. Workers and machines are grouped to provide all the skills and equipment required for that product family in an efficiently arranged layout.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  B. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used. ","  C. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  D. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations.  "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale ","  B. A new supply chain ","  C. A new product ","  D. A new corporate organization chart"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies the emphasis of the Global Reporting Initiative?","choices":["A. Policing corporate and supply chain activities ","  B. Monitoring terrorist activities ","  C. Developing and publishing environmentally sustainable trade practices ","  D. Enforcing UN trade sanctions"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) is an independent group of organizations, including corporations, that develops and publishes sustainable corporate trade practices in regard to such environmental concerns as emissions, energy and resource consumption, and waste. It works with the UN and is entirely voluntary.  "},{"question":"The Global Supply Chain Forum (GSCF) defines supply chain management as \"the integration of key business processes from end user through original suppliers that provides products, services, and information that add value for customers and other stakeholders.\" Which two processes are considered to constitute the core of supply chain management in the GSCF model?","choices":["A. Order management and supplier relationship management ","  B. Customer and supplier management ","  C. Customer service management and manufacturing flow management ","  D. Demand management and supplier management "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"At the heart of the GSCF model is the combination of customer relationship management and supplier relationship management, because these two processes create and manage the link between adjacent partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Continuous process improvement ","  B. Display cards used as production signals ","  C. Interlocking business ownership ","  D. Root cause"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Leveragable materials ","  C. Bottleneck materials ","  D. Commodity materials "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs.  "},{"question":"Benchmarking is a tool used to carry out which function of a quality initiative?","choices":["A. Implement a process improvement initiative. ","  B. Determine the roles in an initiative. ","  C. Analyze the steps in a process. ","  D. Assess process performance."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Benchmarks provide a point of comparison that allows a project team to assess the relative effectiveness of a process and set a goal for its improvement.  "},{"question":"A focus on quality, affordability, or availability indicates a focus on which of the following?","choices":["A. Financial value ","  B. Customer value ","  C. Collaborative value ","  D. Social value "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Depending upon the market being served, a supply chain may be managed with an eye to delivering one or more of the following values to its end customers: quality, affordability, availability, or service. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a true prerequisite for developing collaborative relationships central to supply chain strategy?","choices":["A. The most advanced communications hardware and software ","  B. Auditable information exchange to share knowledge, not just data ","  C. Sharing some benefits but none of the burdens of collaboration with partners ","  D. Deterrence-based arrangements such as aligning sales and management goals to collaborative objectives"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Auditable information exchange and technology for connectivity should allow sharing of knowledge, not mere data. The required technology itself may not have to be the most powerful, but it must be compatible to allow information exchange.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software ","  B. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  C. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  D. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis.  . "},{"question":"The developers of the balanced scorecard approach to performance were concerned that traditional metrics placed too much emphasis on which of the following considerations?","choices":["A. Future performance objectives ","  B. Current profitability ","  C. Past financial performance ","  D. Customer complaints "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The developers of the balanced scorecard, Robert S. Kaplan and David Norton, believed that the traditional reliance on financial measures of performance placed too much emphasis on the past and too little on the present and future and, in addition, ignored other types of measures that contribute to success.  "},{"question":"According to the functional and innovative product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following would be a proper performance indicator for a typical innovative product?","choices":["A. Aggressively reducing lead times ","  B. Inventory reduction ","  C. High inventory turns ","  D. Design for maximum performance at minimal cost "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The key performance indicators for each supply chain differ because of the product characteristics. Aggressively reducing lead times, for example, is appropriate for innovative products but would be irrelevant for functional products that can be manufactured and delivered on predictable schedules in high volumes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following scenarios is most likely to occur at the Stage 3 (integrated enterprise) level of supply chain evolution or higher?","choices":["A. Sales rep finds a market opportunity but is unable to bring it to the attention of new product development. ","  B. Dominant partner coerces others to force price concessions. ","  C. Warehouses are located near each market and have more than enough inventory to handle the next big sale. ","  D. Manager provides a broad mission and backs it up with threats for nonconformance. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"When firms first move past internal integration into external collaboration, the first collaboration can also be the last one if the arrangement fails to produce positive results for the weaker partner as well as for the channel master. Early manufacturer-supplier linkages, for example, were too often the result of coercion by the dominant partner, who was looking for guaranteed on-time delivery of quality items at a relatively low price.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns. ","  B. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. ","  C. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  D. SCOR applies to product development. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems ","  B. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features ","  C. Successive approximations of a perfected process ","  D. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints.  "},{"question":"Which of the following results from having a firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) software designed for automatic calculation of corporate taxes?","choices":["A. The firm will most likely underreport income. ","  B. The software will most likely fail to take legally available deductions. ","  C. The software will earn a tax deduction based on its use in tax planning. ","  D. The firms will risk violating Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) reporting requirements. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"ERP software can be programmed to determine the firm's exact tax liability and, at the same time, comply with Sarbanes-Oxley and earn a deduction for itself. "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Employee learning and growth ","  B. Customer perspective ","  C. Internal business process improvement ","  D. Financials"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line.  "},{"question":"When setting supply chain strategy at a firm that isn't the nucleus firm, which of the following is the most important to focus on?","choices":["A. What's good for extended supply chain partners ","  B. What's good for one's own firm ","  C. What's good for the final customer ","  D. What's good for the nucleus firm "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When it comes to supply chains, it's what's good for the final customer that counts, not what's good for the nucleus company or even what seems to be good for the supply chain itself. Supply chain management ought to be all about giving the final customer the right product at the right time and place for the right price.  "},{"question":"Where on a balanced scorecard would you enter a seminar on financial management for nonfinancial managers developed for the sales managers?","choices":["A. Innovation and learning perspective ","  B. Business process perspective ","  C. Financial perspective ","  D. Customer perspective "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Regardless of the content of the seminar, training belongs in the innovation and learning quadrant of the balanced scorecard.  "},{"question":"Volume growth is a key performance indicator for which of the following?","choices":["A. Product merchandizing ","  B. Customer service ","  C. Supply chain variability ","  D. Replenishment "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Volume growth measures the success of merchandizing efforts.  "},{"question":"According to research by Rice and Hoppe, the theory that supply chains of companies allied as partners in supply networks may compete directly with other similar supply chain networks in reality exists only with which of the following?","choices":["A. Channel masters such as retail consumer good giants ","  B. Vertical supply chains such as poultry sellers ","  C. Horizontal supply chains such as PC sales ","  D. Individual companies such as an automobile manufacturer based on their supply chain management capabilities "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Groups of companies allied as partners in supply networks will compete with other groups of companies allied in supply networks. The networks will be distinct from one another in all ways. The head-to-head supply chain competitors tend toward the vertically integrated company rather than the extended enterprise. The fashion and poultry industries are suggested as arenas in which supply chains compete with supply chains.  "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand ","  B. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  C. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  D. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of supply chains?","choices":["A. Competition is an outside stakeholder to a supply chain that threatens or energizes it. ","  B. There are two flows that can be engineered in a chain, products and cash. ","  C. Supply chains run in only one direction, toward the customer. ","  D. Supply chain processes are entirely contained within each entity within a supply chain. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Competitors affect the functioning of a supply chain in more ways than one: They can threaten or energize the chain. Sometimes competing businesses directly foster each other's growth by participation in trade associations and joint ventures. Whenever a competitor creates an improved product or business process, the entire marketplace is enriched by the new ideas.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods ","  B. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions ","  C. One supply chain for all goods ","  D. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Jobs become more specialized. ","  B. Job responsibilities expand. ","  C. Jobs are not a focus of change. ","  D. Job tasks are simplified."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers ","  B. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  C. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers ","  D. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection.  "},{"question":"The antiterrorism measures developed by the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism (C-TPAT) apply to which of the following entities?","choices":["A. All U.S. exporters ","  B. All domestic and foreign firms involved in U.S. supply chains ","  C. All U.S. importers ","  D. C-TPAT corporate participants"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Participation in the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism is voluntary, and compliance with its regulations is required only of participants. Failure to comply can lead to suspension of privileges or cancellation of partnership.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following authorities has issued directives mandating reporting, reduction, and recycling of heavy metals in end-of-life electronics products?","choices":["A. United States government ","  B. Chinese government ","  C. European Union ","  D. United Nations"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The European Union has issued several directives regarding hazardous components of electronics products, including the Waste from Electronic Equipment directive (WEEE) and the directive restricting the use of heavy metals and retardants in electrical and electronic equipment (RoHS).  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Fuel supplier ","  B. Electric power utility ","  C. Manufacturer connected to electric grid ","  D. Facility maintenance "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer.  "},{"question":"In a TQM initiative, the definition of \"defect\" is determined by which of the following?","choices":["A. Supply chain manager ","  B. Customer ","  C. Top management ","  D. Project team "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"According to TQM methodology, defects are defined from the customer's point of view.  "},{"question":"Which of the following continuous improvement methodologies focuses on reduction of defects to statistical insignificance?","choices":["A. Lean ","  B. Six-sigma ","  C. Theory of constraints ","  D. Just-in-Time (JIT)"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Six-sigma seeks to limit defects to no more than 3.4 per million opportunities. Of course, no initiative sets out to increase defects, but six-sigma makes defect reduction its specific objective.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the potential for different quality methods to work together?","choices":["A. JIT and six-sigma are compatible with each other but not with lean. ","  B. Six-sigma and lean are compatible with each other but not with JIT. ","  C. JIT, lean, and six-sigma work best when combined. ","  D. JIT and lean are compatible with each other but not with six-sigma. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The three quality-based systems are mutually compatible and give the best results when combined to eliminate wasted materials, wasted time, defects, and variability.  "},{"question":"With the theory of supply chain versus supply chain in competition, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. Industries with a small number of dominant suppliers are not ideal but are best coordinated using horizontal supply chains. ","  B. Investments in suppliers shared by a competitor will increase the partnership with that supplier to the detriment of the competitor. ","  C. Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors at a risk of losing proprietary data. ","  D. When supply chains share suppliers, alignment of business strategies with supply chain strategies is facilitated. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors, but at the very least the situation invites conflict of interest. Insofar as manufacturers want to keep their designs and processes proprietary, they take a risk when they link up with competing component suppliers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  B. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers. ","  C. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions. ","  D. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things.  "},{"question":"A channel master is finding that many of its current partners have begun finding ways of bypassing the firm, while others are performing redundant functions that cause unnecessary competition among supply chain members. Which of the following is a likely cause of this behavior?","choices":["A. Weakest collaborative links becoming bottlenecks ","  B. Working with competitors as peers ","  C. Exploitation of power-based relationships ","  D. Individual incentives conflicting with organizational goals"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Power-based relationships occur where a nucleus firm dictates the terms of the relationship to the other members. While its profits increase, other members of the network may suffer losses. When this occurs, the disadvantaged partners may rebel. Resistance may result in redundancy, loss of overall profitability for the chain, or an actual reversal of the power relationship.  "},{"question":"A supply chain that produces and sells cigarettes using traditional forecasting at each stage has been experiencing the bullwhip effect. Which of the following has the strongest influence on this effect?","choices":["A. Safety stock ","  B. Announced promotions ","  C. Excess supply liquidation ","  D. Seasonal fluctuations"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because cigarettes have relatively steady demand, the small variations in demand seen in the forecasting at the retail stage of the supply chain are padded by safety stock. Forecasting at each successive level uses the quantities ordered for forecasting rather than the actual sale amount, resulting in extremely variable demand at the other end of the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Many Japanese companies use keiretsu to avoid which of the following?","choices":["A. Needing to abandon the control and full integration of a vertical environment ","  B. The challenges of synchronizing a network of independent firms ","  C. The semifunctional enterprise stage (Stage 2) ","  D. Lacking specialization and focus in a network of independent firms"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Keiretsu is an intermediate form of integration that differs from vertical integration or horizontal integration in that suppliers and customers are not completely independent but instead own significant stakes in one another. This helps the network of firms be more willing to consider each other's needs.  "},{"question":"Corporate participants in C-TPAT (Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism) receive which one of the following benefits?","choices":["A. Increased protection for overseas shipments ","  B. Reduced tariffs ","  C. Greater reliance on self-policing ","  D. Exemption from border inspections"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Corporate partners in C-TPAT benefit from a greater emphasis on self-policing rather than customs verification and other benefits.  "},{"question":"Company A has installed supply chain management (SCM) software to achieve cross-functional integration. However, some members of the overall value chain that are not directly part of the supply chain itself have not provided the desired level of support for SCM initiatives. Which of the following departments is most likely to be the one lacking in support?","choices":["A. Customer service ","  B. Marketing and sales ","  C. Inbound logistics ","  D. Human resources"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Human resources is part of the value chain support activities that sustain the supply chain. The incorrect answers are all directly part of the supply chain. Managers from outside the supply chain often don't understand the requirements of supply chain management, can't distinguish value chain from supply chain, and consequently don't provide the SCM support required from their areas.  "},{"question":"Consider a simplified supply chain in which Lucy sells psychiatric advice from a booth to her classmates for five cents. Subconsciously, she gets her information from her psychiatrist parent and from her pastor. Which of the following are Tier 2 suppliers in this model?","choices":["A. Lucy ","  B. Parent/pastor ","  C. Higher education/seminary ","  D. There are no Tier 2 suppliers in this situation. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lucy's parent and pastor are the Tier 1 suppliers to Lucy, the service producer. They owe their supply of information to either higher education or a seminary, so these sources are the Tier 2 suppliers.  "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased handling costs ","  B. Increased cumulative setup time ","  C. Increased inventory accumulation ","  D. Increased holding costs "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"Which of the following members of the firm are typically involved in continuous process improvement initiatives?","choices":["A. Shop-floor workers and supervisors ","  B. All members of the firm, including executives, managers, and labor ","  C. Middle managers ","  D. Executives "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Continuous process improvement requires the participation of everyone involved in the targeted processes, the executives who are accountable for the process, the managers responsible for directing it, and the workers who carry it out.  "},{"question":"When defining roles for each party in a collaboration, how should these interactions be structured and why?","choices":["A. Sequential interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. ","  B. Reciprocal interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  C. Sequential interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  D. Reciprocal interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Conflicts can occur when defining roles for each party if the roles make one party more dependent upon another than they wish to be. To alleviate this common problem, networks should avoid sequential interdependence, in which the second party cannot begin work until the first party is done; instead, they should establish reciprocal independence, in which the exchange of tasks and services occurs in both directions.  "},{"question":"Which of the following could be a key performance indicator (KPI) for replenishment?","choices":["A. Volume growth ","  B. Introduction lead time ","  C. Inventory turns ","  D. Order fill rate "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fill rate provides a measure of the success of the key process of replenishment. A high fill rate indicates good performance.  "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-order innovative product ","  B. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  C. Make-to-stock functional product ","  D. Make-to-order functional product"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a tool that helps visually identify the 20 percent of causes responsible for 80 percent of problems (using those percentages as approximations)?","choices":["A. Focus group ","  B. Process map ","  C. Checklist ","  D. Pareto diagram "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A Pareto diagram applies the Pareto principle that 80 percent of results tend to be the result of 20 percent of causes. The diagram helps visually distinguish the small number of causes that result in the largest number of process flaws. Focus groups are useful in gathering customer complaints: the flaws in the diagram.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding supply chain organizations?","choices":["A. There is a long but always finite number of tiers of suppliers in any supply chain. ","  B. Service supplier considerations are important only after a manufacturing site has been selected. ","  C. Supply chains can loop back on themselves, making suppliers into customers. ","  D. A raw material producer has no Tier 1 suppliers."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"No matter how far you travel toward the supply end of a supply chain, you will never run out of new tiers of suppliers. A coal mine may ship coal to a generating plant that supplies power to the manufacturer that produces a machine that is shipped to a distributor that sells mining equipment to the same mine that began the process: supply chains can double back on themselves.  "},{"question":"According to total quality theory, which of the following would be of primary importance to document during the analysis phase of a continuous improvement initiative?","choices":["A. A thorough, factual description of the process ","  B. Customer attitudes toward the product produced by the process ","  C. Executive-level positions on the importance of the process ","  D. Staff-level views of the practical difficulties involved in carrying out the process "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Quality theory emphasizes the importance of data; therefore, improvement initiatives begin with a complete, unbiased, factual description of the process.  "},{"question":"A manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, and retailer all agree to base their orders on actual consumer orders instead of performing detailed forecasts based on each party's Tier 1 customer's actual orders. Which of the following will result, and what are the likely risks of this method?","choices":["A. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect. ","  B. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  C. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect. ","  D. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The firms have decided to move to a make-to-order environment, moving the push/pull frontier back to the manufacturer, which will reduce the bullwhip effect and the risk of inventory obsolescence, but at the risk of greater overtime and rush orders if there is a sudden spike in demand.  "},{"question":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of training at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. All levels ","  B. Top management only ","  C. All management levels ","  D. Customer-facing employees only"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of all process participants, from top management to basic service or shop-floor employees, and it includes training at all levels.  "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Middle management ","  B. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees ","  C. Top management ","  D. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.)  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Responsiveness ","  B. Reliability ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Sustainability"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market.  "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Judgment of each participant's direct supervisor ","  B. Approval of top management ","  C. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  D. Outcome of the change initiative "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning).  "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Protective packaging ","  B. Conveyers ","  C. Pallets ","  D. Shipping containers"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory.  "},{"question":"In SCOR Level 1, if you divide the sum of the cycle times for all orders delivered by the total number of orders delivered, you are using a metric for which of the following supply chain attributes?","choices":["A. Reliability ","  B. Responsiveness ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Flexibility"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Average actual cycle time (sum of cycle times divided by number of deliveries) measures the responsiveness of the supply chain. It doesn't tell you if the deliveries were on time, which would be a reliability metric.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Can reach the market quickly ","  B. Has a lower price than the competitor's product ","  C. Has more features than the competitor's product ","  D. Can be sold for a positive return "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably). "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"According to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model, if a refrigerator manufacturing company is at the center of the model, the supplier of materials to the sheet metal supplier has only which of the following processes to perform in relation to the manufacturer?","choices":["A. Plan, deliver, return ","  B. Make, source, deliver ","  C. Plan, source, make, deliver, return ","  D. Plan, source, return"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"From the perspective of the manufacturer, the supplier of metal to the sheet metal suppliers is on the second tier and may join in planning, but the manufacturer is otherwise concerned only with its ability to deliver and return goods as needed. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council. "},{"question":"A midsize manufacturing firm works with a large retailer as its primary customer and has several sources of supply for each of its key materials. The firm is trying to align its supply chain strategy with corporate strategy. Which of the following must be the primary consideration when this firm is setting corporate strategy?","choices":["A. Alignment with the retailer's corporate strategy to holistically maintain a profitable relationship ","  B. Alignment with the strategic objectives of their suppliers to generate long-term stability of supply ","  C. Setting the firm's own strategic objectives to leverage a more profitable margin from their customers ","  D. The objectives of the ultimate end customer regardless of what any intermediaries may interject "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because the retailer in this situation appears to be the nucleus firm, alignment of the retailer's corporate strategy with the firm's own corporate strategy must take precedence over other considerations.  "},{"question":"What is the minimum level of enterprise evolution in which a firm might use a logistics supplier to integrate with external members and also internally combine warehousing and transportation activities to optimize cost versus customer service?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A company at Stage 3 will make advances such as carrying out warehousing and transportation decisions in tandem to achieve the optimal balance of cost-effectiveness and customer service. At this point, the nucleus firm may begin to take a step toward integration with the external members of the chain by contracting with a logistics supplier.  "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders. ","  B. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible. ","  C. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching. ","  D. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change.  "},{"question":"If a firm has 25 days of accounts payables outstanding and 30 days invested in inventory and their cash-to-cash cycle time is 80 days, how many days of accounts receivables do they have?","choices":["A. 105 days ","  B. 80 days ","  C. 75 days ","  D. 50 days"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The correct answer is 75 days: 80 days (cash to cash) + 25 days (payables) - 30 days (inventory) = 75 days receivables. The cash-to-cash cycle (or cash conversion cycle) is the number of days between the time a firm pays for raw materials and the time it receives payment for finished goods. The equation for calculating the cash-to-cash cycle is Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time = Average Inventory Collection Period + Average Receivables Processing Period - Average Payables Period; therefore, Days of Accounts Receivable = Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time + Days of Accounts Payable - Days of Inventory. "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates ","  B. The rate in the country of the headquarters ","  C. The local country rate ","  D. A special international rate "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. ","  B. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results. ","  C. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members. ","  D. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain adaptability ","  B. Supply chain responsiveness ","  C. Supply chain flexibility ","  D. Supply chain reliability "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of contracts for partnerships?","choices":["A. Cultural differences in contracts and problem resolution styles should be a primary consideration when arranging formal contracts. ","  B. Contracts should always be used in the negotiation process to keep relationships true to the agreement. ","  C. Courts can become involved in conflicts in most Asian countries without long-term detriment to a relationship. ","  D. Contracts should be fixed at the start of the relationship because alterations are difficult to enact between multiple parties. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Contracts, policies and procedures, and informal conflict resolution must be sensitive to cultural differences. While courts can become involved in conflicts in the United States without long-term detriment, the opposite is true in most Asian countries.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Improved business focus and expertise ","  B. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  C. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions ","  D. Technology to handle the increased complexity"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top.  "},{"question":"The Level 2 SCOR measure for cost of goods sold includes which of the following supply chain costs?","choices":["A. Costs of sourcing and making ","  B. Costs of sourcing, making, and delivering ","  C. Costs of planning, sourcing, making, and delivering ","  D. Total costs of planning, sourcing, making, delivering, and returning "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The SCOR Level 2 metric for cost of goods sold includes all the costs related to the five SCOR supply chain processes (plan, source, make, deliver, and return).  "},{"question":"China has restricted U.S. imports of wood pallets for which of the following reasons?","choices":["A. Risk of insect pests in the wood ","  B. Lack of Chinese wood content in pallets ","  C. Pallets weren't being properly recycled ","  D. Excessive weight of soft wood pallets "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"China, the European Union, and other destinations have placed restrictions on wood pallets coming from the United States because of possible infestation by harmful insects.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following tools provides a visual method for tracking process variance as part of an improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Control chart ","  B. Process map ","  C. Pareto diagram ","  D. Oliver Wight checklist"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A control chart tracks process variance, allowing a project team to see quickly when defects have spiked to unacceptable levels. It can be used to manage as well as improve a process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"What enforcement authority does the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission bring to its role in regard to the provisions of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act?","choices":["A. Investigative authority only ","  B. Authority to bring cases to criminal court ","  C. Authority to bring civil court actions ","  D. Authority to impose jail sentences on executives "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The SEC has the authority to bring civil suits against corporations and individuals it believes to be out of compliance with securities regulations, including the Sarbanes-Oxley Act. It can refer cases to law enforcement agencies, which can institute criminal proceedings. "},{"question":"A firm that is always claiming it has the best processes and highest quality has recently suffered losses because even though they dictate these processes to their long-term Asian suppliers, several of them have, without any explanation, recently had a string of additional costs and quality problems. Which of the following would best help this firm resolve its problems?","choices":["A. Increase visibility with the suppliers and allow the suppliers to suggest processes that work for them. ","  B. Enforce the provisions of the suppliers' contracts through litigation. ","  C. Move production so that it is once again performed correctly in-house. ","  D. Find new suppliers who can follow the firm's process more closely. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Cultures tend to be egocentric and thus tend to resist external collaboration. They feel that their ways are the best ways of doing things and will often reject a different way without even considering it. Culture conflicts are increased when each company relies on its own sources of information and is unable to see the impact of its choices on other areas of the network. When companies don't see the negative results of their actions, they can't learn from their mistakes. Increasing visibility will correct some of these problems, but processes may need to be adaptable to the area in which they are performed, such as that litigation is seen as a betrayal of a relationship in many Asian countries.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. Kanban ","  B. Lean ","  C. Six-sigma ","  D. JIT "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Bottleneck material ","  B. Direct/core competency material ","  C. Leveragable material ","  D. Commodity material "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following illustrates an emphasis on the affordability aspect of customer value?","choices":["A. A cement-mixing tub of greater durability and flexibility than similar offerings ","  B. No-hassle, no-negotiation sales price on new cars at a dealership ","  C. Same-day delivery of goods via courier-to-air-to-courier ","  D. A luxury boat priced lower than other luxury boats of similar size and feature"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Affordability does not refer solely to discount goods but to goods that have a price at the lower end of an appropriate price level for the value received.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share. ","  B. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  C. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. ","  D. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure. "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Delivering ","  B. Planning ","  C. Sourcing ","  D. Making"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the people or the metrics involved in supply chain management?","choices":["A. Supply chain management must be the responsibility of a department-level manager who is equal in hierarchy to other department heads. ","  B. Supply chain strategy and control of the related processes depend on having people educated in functional rather than department thinking. ","  C. Performance must be measured by ratios of profitability and velocity, not by a checklist. ","  D. Current supply chain performance is better quantitatively benchmarked against the firm's desired performance than qualitatively benchmarked."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Numbers (quantitative) generally provide the most convincing supporting evidence in the boardroom and investment analyst's office. If you're bragging about your cash-to-cash cycle, for instance, you might say, \"We've got it down from 50 days to 20, and that's below the industry average.\"  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies ","  B. A limited number of essential supply chain processes ","  C. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  D. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 focuses on which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Hazardous materials ","  B. Financial reporting and controls ","  C. Terrorism ","  D. Material content reporting "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Sarbanes-Oxley focuses on financial reporting and controls, including reporting on supply chain controls. Plans to respond to events such as terrorism are included in the reporting requirements, but they are not the focus of the legislation, which was drafted in response to corporate corruption. "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding a supply chain?","choices":["A. Information flows upstream, downstream, and between network members and external entities. ","  B. Services may be part of a manufacturing supply chain but do not have a distinct supply chain themselves. ","  C. Cash flows downstream while materials flow upstream. ","  D. An electrical power producer that powers a manufacturer's plant is downstream from the manufacturer. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The information in a supply chain flows upstream toward the supplier end, downstream toward the customer end, and also back and forth within the entities and between the chain and external entities, such as governments, markets, and competitors.  "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Competitive benchmarking ","  B. Best-in-class benchmarking ","  C. Process benchmarking ","  D. Oliver Wight benchmarking "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"When an enterprise buys new technology, which one of the following should be the primary selection criterion?","choices":["A. Low cost ","  B. Features representing the very latest designs ","  C. Appropriateness to supply chain strategy ","  D. Processing power"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Strategy should govern choice of technology. Features and processing power should be right for the strategic needs of the enterprise. Low cost is not always the right cost in any purchase. Even a small amount of money is wasted if it doesn't purchase what you need.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. ","  B. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. ","  C. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. ","  D. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"At which of the following stages would a company be if it has multiple uncoordinated improvement efforts occurring sequentially instead of in concurrence, such as inventory reduction, better forecasting techniques, and lower cost procurement?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A company at Stage 2 will have multiple initiatives to improve individual functional areas, but these will not generally be coordinated with one another and will therefore fall short of their potential for reducing costs, improving margins, expanding markets, or delivering better service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Transfer cost decisions ","  B. Warehouse location decisions ","  C. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore ","  D. Real property acquisitions"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility.  "},{"question":"The first step in setting strategy for moving toward greater collaboration in regard to the firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) system is to do which of the following?","choices":["A. Analyze the current ERP system and understand its limitations. ","  B. Customize the ERP system to allow the needed functionality. ","  C. Create a conceptual and simulation model. ","  D. Design a business architecture plan and an implementation plan. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Before determining a strategy for greater collaboration, the firm must know what it can and cannot do with its current system. Then the firm can set a strategy for where it wants to be and test the strategy's validity.  "},{"question":"Which of the following types of databases would be best for allowing several suppliers access to a limited set of the company's data without disclosing other proprietary data?","choices":["A. Relational database  ","  B. Data warehouse ","  C. Groupware database ","  D. Datamart"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While any of the listed databases could be used to allow sharing of data with the extended supply chain, groupware databases are specifically designed to regulate access to data and track updates without compromising the primary database.  "},{"question":"The competitive market encourages application developers to use standards. In comparison to older standards, these standards are all of the following except","choices":["A. Web-based. ","  B. closed. ","  C. cheaper to develop. ","  D. distributed. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Open, Web-based, and distributed standards are replacing older closed systems because they are cheaper to develop, integrate, and maintain.  "},{"question":"A tire producer partners with a natural rubber producer whose products are becoming subject to more and more demand even as the product becomes more rare. They also get old tires from a tire recycler. Which of the following collaborative intensities would be appropriate for these partners?","choices":["A. Shared processes and partnership level or higher for the natural rubber producer and arm's length for the tire recycler ","  B. Backward integration for the natural rubber producer and transactional and information collaboration or higher for the tire recycler ","  C. Linked competitive vision and strategic alliance or higher for the natural rubber producer and shared processes and partnership for the tire recycler ","  D. Arm's length relationship for the natural rubber producer and transactional and no relationship with the tire recycler "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because the natural rubber is becoming more rare, the tire producer should consider some form of alliance or better for this partner. The tire recycler is not offering a unique value-added service but a commodity service, so these transactions should be kept at arm's length.  "},{"question":"Which of the following describes a chaotic network?","choices":["A. Use of B2B marketplaces to create a new virtual supply chain for each specific need ","  B. Use of B2B marketplaces in a portal that combines content, transactions, and services for all-in-one functionality ","  C. Use of B2B marketplaces to provide pseudocertification to prospective members so that a wide audience can participate without too much risk ","  D. Use of B2B marketplaces to link each member of a supply chain by a hub in which the members are all spokes "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"When B2B marketplaces are used to create ad hoc relationships that can differ from transaction to transaction to form the chain best suited for the need, it is described as a chaotic rather than static network. These networks are quickly adaptable.  "},{"question":"Within an advance planning and scheduling (APS) system, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. Managers can set a rule that all manufacturing of Item A occurs at Plant B even if other plants have the capacity. ","  B. The bulk of the APS functions exist at the operational level. ","  C. At the strategic level, an APS system automatically determines the weighting of tradeoffs such as cost versus quality. ","  D. Materials, production, and distribution planning modules work sequentially to provide the master planner with plans after a single pass."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Managers can set rules such as that a particular plant prefers to make a particular type of good even when others have the capacity.  "},{"question":"For orders placed at the distribution centers by retail stores, which of the following measures the variation of orders relative to the average demand level for the orders?","choices":["A. Aggregate deviation ","  B. Standard deviation ","  C. Mean ","  D. Coefficient of variation"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The coefficient of deviation is the standard deviation divided by the mean, where the standard deviation measures the absolute variability of demand for the item and the mean is the average of the values.  "},{"question":"For an enterprise resources planning (ERP) initiative, which of the following expenditures or difficulties should be avoided, assuming the company can generate the capital to perform them all?","choices":["A. Customize the ERP system to match the company's best practices. ","  B. Change company processes to align with the ERP best practices. ","  C. Upgrade databases and operating systems to make them homogenous. ","  D. Upgrade hardware until the architecture is homogeneous. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Companies have been proven to be better off spending their resources getting their hardware, databases, operating systems, and other architecture up to a standard and then using the ERP. Without improving the company process and aligning them with best practices and ERP applications, they may end up spending their resources in customizing the ERP system, which has many hidden costs, up to seven to eight times the price of the software itself.  "},{"question":"Which of the following must champion the relationships to be formed across an extended supply chain?","choices":["A. Retailer ","  B. Manufacturer ","  C. Nucleus firm ","  D. Cross-enterprise technology team "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While the nucleus firm may be a manufacturer or a retailer, it is defined as the firm that has the most power or brand equity in a relationship, and this firm must take the initiative to move the extended supply chain network to a higher stage of supply chain development.  "},{"question":"Which of the following information levels is the most likely place in which specific production, funding, capacity, and staffing levels would be decided?","choices":["A. Tactical ","  B. Strategic ","  C. Operational planning ","  D. Operational execution "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The tactical level is where detailed production plans, sales plans, and other types of functional plans are set to support the organization's strategic plan.  "},{"question":"All of the following are true of technology audits except","choices":["A. Technology audits exist to limit the risk of technology adoption. ","  B. Technology auditors must be familiar with the technologies being audited but need no specific industry knowledge. ","  C. Technology audits help to keep the company ahead of the technology curve. ","  D. Technology audits are best performed by independent outside parties. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Technology auditors should be familiar both with the technology being audited and with the capabilities of the company and the supply chain being audited.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of RosettaNet?","choices":["A. RosettaNet is a proprietary set of standards, and some businesses avoid it because they are competitors with the owners. ","  B. RosettaNet works best when paired with LINUX, the open operating system standard. ","  C. RosettaNet is a horizontal exchange that works to increase adoption of standards across industries. ","  D. RosettaNet can be complex and expensive to implement."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"RosettaNet sometimes deters smaller businesses from using it because of its expense and complexity. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a reason some large firms resist using a consortium-based exchange and instead form their own private exchanges?","choices":["A. Private exchanges generate a larger supplier base than a consortium. ","  B. Consortia entail greater setup expense than a private exchange. ","  C. A consortium's pooling efforts reduce the firm's power in the industry. ","  D. Group purchases that consolidate buying power are available only on private exchanges."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Some large firms feel that the pooling of efforts that is integral to consortium-based exchanges dilutes their industry influence, and they instead form private exchanges to maintain their independence. "},{"question":"Most traditional ERP systems send data in which of the following formats?","choices":["A. WML ","  B. ANSI X12 for EDI ","  C. Flat files ","  D. XML"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Most ERP systems currently in use generate and send flat files, which are proprietary files in the native language of the application that created them.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be the least likely reason to implement RFID at a company?","choices":["A. Decreasing already low error rates on baggage handling for an airline where each error has a high cost ","  B. Automated service scheduling for a fleet of cars with details stored dynamically on the tag ","  C. Automated door openings and closings at a steam energy plant to save on energy costs ","  D. Increasing internal inventory accuracy in a make-to-order, low stock environment "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Although all of the examples listed could have other factors that would recommend the use of RFID, inventory accuracy in a situation where the inventory is already very low and therefore likely very accurate is the least likely of the scenarios listed to provide a return in excess of the costs of the implementation. RFID implementations should be performed only if they provide benefits in excess of their costs over their life.  "},{"question":"Of the following employee skill sets, which is considered the primary skill set for departmental leaders prior to reaching Stage 3 of supply chain development?","choices":["A. Knowledge of other functional areas ","  B. Conceptual model building skills ","  C. Ability to come to consensus ","  D. Deep functional expertise "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Deep functional expertise is considered the primary employee skill set at Stages 1 and 2 of supply chain development.  "},{"question":"In an advanced supply chain, which of the following would be the best data to send to a sheet metal producer from its various buyers?","choices":["A. Sheets of steel and plates of glass needed for metal-edged window construction for the month ","  B. Sheets of steel required for metal door construction company for the month ","  C. Real-time point-of-sale (POS) data and profit margins for every buyer ","  D. Number of tin cans needed for canned vegetable production for the month "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Providing access to data involves not only sharing of data but sharing of data in the right format for the user: in this case, sheets of steel rather than number of finished products. The visibility should also not contain too much information, such as plates of glass or profit margins, both to keep extraneous data to a minimum and to protect each partner's private information.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is often included in supply chain management (SCM) software as the highest level analytical system that often displaces or replaces current ERP scheduling functions?","choices":["A. Supply chain planning and design ","  B. Advance planning and scheduling (APS) ","  C. Product life cycle management ","  D. Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR) "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"APS is often grouped within SCM as its highest level planning system, coordinating the work of multiple plants for overall optimization.  "},{"question":"Which of the following will generate the greatest return on investment (ROI) for a comprehensive supply chain management system?","choices":["A. Imposing tactical limits on future decisions ","  B. Performing each of a massive number of transactions more efficiently ","  C. Optimizing operational planning processes to match supply with demand on a daily basis ","  D. Determining the right business model "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Choosing the right business model at the strategic level will have a cascading effect on all other choices made for the business. Therefore strategic level systems have the highest ROI.  "},{"question":"A marketplace for the chemical industry requires membership but is semipublic because it allows all members to trade with one another and enables collaboration and data sharing without needing to include the owners of the site. Which of the following is this type of site?","choices":["A. Private horizontal marketplace ","  B. Private vertical marketplace ","  C. Consortia-based vertical marketplace ","  D. Consortia-based horizontal marketplace "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Most consortia-based marketplaces serve an industry vertical, and the ownership consortium makes up the primary players in the market. Unlike private marketplaces, consortia-based marketplaces allow members to trade and collaborate privately in a secure environment without necessarily involving the members of the consortium.  "},{"question":"Which of the following describes when multiple portals are combined in one site so that multiple buyer bases can interact with multiple seller bases?","choices":["A. Trading exchanges or online marketplaces ","  B. Horizontal portals ","  C. Integrated trading community networks ","  D. Vertical portals"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An integrated network or trading community network involves the combination of several horizontal portals and an industry vertical portal to pool the powers of each portal into a larger and more powerful trading community. "},{"question":"A local area network (LAN) exists at which of the following IT infrastructure levels?","choices":["A. Operating system (O/S) and computer networking level ","  B. Database level ","  C. Presentation level ","  D. Application level"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A LAN is a common computer networking method.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the next step in an intraenterprise strategy development process after the first step of determining goals and the desired end state of the supply chain?","choices":["A. Design in change management and training for all parties and set performance metrics. ","  B. Create cross-functional and cross-business teams to guide the transformation. ","  C. Semantically organize the supply chain's operational processes and IT's mission. ","  D. Create a conceptual model that will explain the process to all involved parties. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Cross-functional and cross-business teams must be formed to involve all parties in the other steps.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a primary goal of companies at higher stages of development regarding the acquisition and use of data?","choices":["A. Putting all data collected to use ","  B. Making forecasting become completely accurate ","  C. Getting analytical systems to make decisions for management ","  D. Getting access to data outside the company "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Getting access to pertinent data from suppliers and customers is a primary goal of information collection in advanced supply chains. The other answers are not possible or desired.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements best describes the relative care a warehouse manager should take in securing A, B, and C inventory items?","choices":["A. Provide best protection for A items. ","  B. Provide best protection for B items. ","  C. Provide best protection for C items. ","  D. Provide the same level of protection to all items"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While protecting all items is obviously important, the most cost-effective approach may be to spend relatively more resources on A items than on the less valuable, but larger, percentage of inventory. "},{"question":"Which one of the following would appear in the route file?","choices":["A. Assembly instructions for a finished product  ","  B. Mechanical drawings of a finished product ","  C. Work center ID ","  D. List of component items for one end item"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The route file identifies the work center where a particular process will take place.  "},{"question":"Considering the types of cargo typically carried over long distances by inland water carrier and the rates per ton-mile, which of the following modes of transportation is the barge's closest competitor?","choices":["A. Trucking ","  B. Rail ","  C. Pipeline ","  D. Piggyback "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Railroad and barges both specialize in carrying very heavy, dense, low-value cargo over long distances. A rail line laid along a waterway would make a potent rival for the water carrier.  "},{"question":"Which of the following production strategies is sometimes called mass customization?","choices":["A. Lean production ","  B. Assemble-to-order ","  C. Make-to-stock ","  D. Make-to-order"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The assemble-to-order strategy incorporates some of the benefits of mass production and some of the benefits of true customization by mass-producing components that can be assembled into one of several different versions of a product after receipt of an order.  "},{"question":"When deciding whether to acquire a component from a domestic or foreign source, which of the following comparisons provides the most accurate assessment of their relative value?","choices":["A. Simple price comparison ","  B. Relative price plus transportation ","  C. Relative price adjusted for currency exchange and import duties ","  D. Landed cost of each"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed cost includes every expense involved in acquiring a component (or any item of value) and bringing it to your dock, including price, transportation, fees and commissions, import duties, etc. "},{"question":"How often, under normal circumstances, does a pre-S\u0026OP meeting take place?","choices":["A. Weekly ","  B. Monthly ","  C. Quarterly ","  D. Annually"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Sales and operations planning (S\u0026OP) is a monthly process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following types of warehouse ownership might a firm choose to minimize storage costs when adding distribution capacity for a new product with a highly seasonal demand pattern?","choices":["A. Public warehousing ","  B. New construction private warehousing ","  C. Contract warehousing ","  D. Remodeled and expanded private warehousing "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"All other factors being equal, public warehousing is a good choice to accommodate short-term spikes in demand. The other choices require longer-term commitments of resources. (In actual practice, \"other factors\" may be unlikely to remain equal, and all choices have to be made with an eye to unplanned consequences for the system as a whole.)  "},{"question":"If you know the available time at a work center and want to calculate its rated capacity, you also need to know which of the following?","choices":["A. Utilization and number of workers/machines ","  B. Efficiency and utilization ","  C. Efficiency and manufacturing lead time ","  D. Efficiency and number of workers/machines "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"To calculate rated capacity, you multiply the number of available hours by the efficiency and utilization. Essentially, that tells you how much of the available time is being used and how efficiently it's being used. "},{"question":"A demand forecast determined by a panel of all the salespeople in an organization may reach an exaggerated, false conclusion by relying on which of the following?","choices":["A. Personal experience ","  B. Bandwagon effect ","  C. Intuition ","  D. Collective view of their markets"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The \"bandwagon effect\" (also called \"groupthink\") can distort the conclusions of a panel if a strong leader emerges with a convincing but wrong-headed view, or if all participants reinforce one another in reaching an exaggerated conclusion. An entire sales force acting in concert may, however, benefit from experience, collective knowledge of the broad market served by the organization, and even intuition.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the cost structure of trucking?","choices":["A. Low fixed costs, low variable costs ","  B. Low fixed costs, high variable costs ","  C. High fixed costs, high variable costs ","  D. High fixed costs, low variable costs"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The public builds and maintains the infrastructure used by trucks, so they have low fixed costs. But they have relatively high variable costs for operation and maintenance. "},{"question":"A logistics manager concerned to avoid breakage of cargo would be least inclined to choose which of the following modes of transportation (ignoring tradeoffs)?","choices":["A. Truck transport ","  B. Air transport ","  C. Rail transport ","  D. Water transport "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Rail provides a rough ride for cargo, resulting in more breakage than occurs in cargo transported by truck, water, or air.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements identifies the financial consequences to a U.S. firm under NAFTA when it transfers assembled materials from a maquiladora subcontractor back into the United States?","choices":["A. It pays a tax based on the value added in Mexico. ","  B. It pays no duty or tax. ","  C. It pays a duty but receives a duty drawback. ","  D. It pays use (sales) tax on the value of the finished goods. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Under NAFTA, U.S. firms that subcontract work to maqualidoras in Mexico pay only a tax based on the value added in Mexico, which is primarily attributable to low-wage labor. "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes the primary reason for a supplier to agree to sell goods on consignment rather than selling to its customers for resale to the customer's customers?","choices":["A. Decreased inventory holding costs ","  B. Decreased labor costs ","  C. Decreased setup costs ","  D. Greater visibility of inventory management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In VMI, both partners benefit from increased visibility of the inventory management process, because they share information about retail demand on the one hand and supplier processes on the other. Setup and holding costs increase for the supplier, however, though they should decrease overall as forecasting improves. "},{"question":"Which of the following forecast methods predicts demand for one product by looking at data from a different product?","choices":["A. Personal insight ","  B. Historical analogy ","  C. Visionary method ","  D. Market research "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Historical analogy forecasts use demand data from one product to forecast demand for a different but similar product, such as a new product for which no past data exist. "},{"question":"Piggyback service refers to which of the following types of cargo transport?","choices":["A. Combined truck and train transport ","  B. Combined train and ship transport ","  C. Combined plane and truck transport ","  D. Any intermodal method of transport "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In piggyback service either a truck trailer or a container travels part of the way over the road and part of the way on a railroad flatcar. All the other intermodal methods mentioned in the options are available, and intermodal transport is an important option for the logistics manager to consider when navigating long logistics supply chains.  "},{"question":"Which of the following approaches to product design is compatible with the requirement that German brewers use refillable bottles?","choices":["A. Design for production ","  B. Design for logistics ","  C. Over-the-wall design ","  D. Design for reverse logistics"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Design for reverse logistics looks for ways to make products that can be easily reused, returned, or recycled. (Whether the beer bottles can be reused or not has no effect upon logistics in the forward chain, only in the reverse chain that brings the product back at the end of its life cycle.) "},{"question":"Which of the following would be subject to alteration as the result of decisions made in an executive S\u0026OP meeting?","choices":["A. Product features ","  B. Product pricing ","  C. Weekly production schedules ","  D. Business plan"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The monthly S\u0026OP meeting deals with aggregate-level information about product families and output. The S\u0026OP executive committee can make changes in either the operations plan or the business plan if they get out of synch with one another. "},{"question":"The forecasting method known as the pyramid technique specifically incorporates which one of the following principles of forecasting?","choices":["A. Forecasts are always wrong. ","  B. Short-range forecasts are more reliable than long-range forecasts. ","  C. Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts. ","  D. Quantitative data are preferable to qualitative estimates. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts, so the pyramid technique begins by forecasting demand for the product family and then disaggregates the demand to generate single-product demand forecasts. This ensures alignment between forecasts for the group and the components of the group. (This is not to imply that the technique ignores other principles, only that it specifically relies upon the superior reliability of group forecasting.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following pieces of warehouse equipment provides maximum flexibility in the movement, placement, and retrieval of pallets?","choices":["A. Forklift truck ","  B. Tow tractor with trailer ","  C. Crane ","  D. Roller-type conveyer "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The forklift truck is designed specifically for moving, placing, and retrieving pallets. The other options either have less flexibility or are not especially suitable for moving small loads.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would not be an acceptable measurement of output for use in production planning?","choices":["A. Tons ","  B. Numbers ","  C. Euros ","  D. Liters "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The production plan focuses on the output of product (or services); pricing takes place elsewhere in the planning process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an input to the material requirements plan (MRP)?","choices":["A. Make/buy action plan ","  B. Rough-cut capacity planning ","  C. Resource requirements planning ","  D. Input/output control"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Make/buy action plans concern matters such as what to order, cancel, and expedite. With the information from this and other sources, it is possible to develop the MRP.  "},{"question":"According to the ABC system of classifying inventory, an application of the Pareto principle, the greatest share of revenue will be generated by which of the following numbers of inventory items (approximately)?","choices":["A. 80 percent ","  B. 55 percent ","  C. 30 percent ","  D. 15 percent "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The ABC system of classifying inventory asserts that the A items in your inventory will constitute only about 15 percent of the total number of items but will create 70 to 80 percent of value. This is an approximate application of the Pareto principle, or 80-20 rule, which holds that about 20 percent of possible causes account for about 80 percent of outcomes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following provides a point of reference for formulating the sales and operations plan?","choices":["A. Production forecast ","  B. Financial plan ","  C. Marketing plan ","  D. Business plan "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The sales and operations plan takes the business plan as its point of reference for developing a plan that balances supply and demand by merging input from sales and marketing on the one hand and operations on the other. "},{"question":"Pegging refers to the ability to make a connection between the required numbers of a specific component and which of the following?","choices":["A. Capacity plan ","  B. Demand forecast ","  C. Specific work center ","  D. Demand for the parent according to the MRP "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Pegging is the ability to track dependent demand for a component back to demand for the parent by referring to the material requirements plan (MRP).  "},{"question":"Which one of the following Incoterms indicates that the exporter has the most responsibility for transporting a shipment of cargo from the exporter's dock to the importer's dock?","choices":["A. DDP ","  B. FOB ","  C. CIP ","  D. EXW"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While it's not necessary to memorize the meanings of Incoterms, the important point to recall is that they exist to clarify the responsibilities of exporter and importer in a carriage contract. Of the four groups of terms, the E group (comprising only the single term EXW) puts the most responsibility on the importer, while the D group assigns almost all responsibility to the exporter. DDP, for example, means \"Delivered Duty Paid\" (that is, paid by the exporter).  "},{"question":"If you were able to get a 20 percent discount on any of the following logistics expenses, which would you choose to receive the maximum cost savings?","choices":["A. Transportation ","  B. Materials handling ","  C. Compliance ","  D. Warehousing "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Transportation expenses make up the largest portion of the logistics budget, so taking the discount on transportation costs would give you the largest cost reduction. (Of course, you would have to consider possible tradeoffs if discounting transportation caused cost increases elsewhere in the system.) "},{"question":"For which of the following items should demand be calculated rather than forecast?","choices":["A. All Chevrolets ","  B. All Chevrolet Cobalts ","  C. All steering wheels for new Chevrolet Cobalts ","  D. All Chevrolet replacement parts"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Steering wheels are a dependent demand item; the demand for dependent items should be calculated from the forecast of demand for their parent items. Steering wheels are a component; the new cars they go into are the parents. Replacement parts are sold, manufactured, and forecast as independent items, not as dependent components. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a type of supply chain collaboration formalized by the Voluntary Interindustry Commerce Standards Association (VICS)?","choices":["A. Vendor-managed inventory ","  B. Continuous replenishment ","  C. Collective planning, forecasting, and replenishment ","  D. Quick response "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR®) is a formal description of best practices developed and maintained by VICS to help supply chain partners develop successful collaborations.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the primary focus of the master production schedule?","choices":["A. Weekly production amounts for individual products ","  B. Weekly aggregate production amounts for product families ","  C. Monthly aggregate production amounts for end items ","  D. Monthly aggregate production amounts for product families "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The focus of MPS is on weekly scheduling for individual products. You could derive the other amounts from the master schedule.  "},{"question":"Which of the following transportation stakeholders is most likely to be in agreement with the government about the need for market regulation?","choices":["A. The public ","  B. Recipients ","  C. Carriers ","  D. Shippers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"All market participants can benefit from well-crafted regulations regarding such matters as fairness and safety, but the public at large is most likely to be in synch with the government on the broad spectrum of regulations, from pricing through access to safety and environmental stewardship. (This assumes a government that is responsive to public demands.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a standardized, nonnegotiable form listing items being shipped directly to the titleholder?","choices":["A. Ship's manifest ","  B. Order B/L ","  C. Air waybill ","  D. Ocean bill"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The air waybill is a nonnegotiable standardized form used by all air carriers.  "},{"question":"The sales and operations plan would include which of the following?","choices":["A. Monthly production figures for individual SKUs ","  B. Weekly production figures by individual SKU ","  C. Monthly production figures by product family ","  D. Monthly production figures by individual manufacturing center "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"S\u0026OP focuses on monthly production amounts for product families. Scheduling for individual products (SKUs) comes later in the planning process.  "},{"question":"In the economic order quantity calculation, which one of the following statements most accurately identifies the effect of increasing order sizes on inventory holding and order costs?","choices":["A. Total costs drop up to a point and then rise steadily. ","  B. Setup and order costs remain constant while holding costs drop steadily. ","  C. Economies of scale lower all holding and ordering/setup costs equally and steadily. ","  D. Holding costs remain constant while setup costs rise steadily. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The larger the order, the higher the holding costs, because there is more inventory to hold. Setup costs tend to go down as orders grow larger because of economies of scale. (Larger orders can be placed less frequently than smaller orders, thus reducing the number of setups.) "},{"question":"Which one of the following is the most compelling reason for a manufacturer to own its own warehouses rather than using a contractor's warehouses?","choices":["A. To increase control over warehouse design decisions ","  B. To benefit from economies of scale in transportation ","  C. To increase flexibility to test new geographic markets ","  D. To increase flexibility of budgeting for warehousing expenses "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A firm can build or remodel its own warehouses with no needs in mind other than its own. Contractors offer flexibility and economies of scale. "},{"question":"Which of the following changes tend to occur as a result of adding warehouses to a logistics network (assuming no other changes)?","choices":["A. Inventory increases while the ratio of storage space to total warehouse square feet decreases. ","  B. Inventory decreases while the ratio of storage space to square feet increases. ","  C. Inventory increases and the ratio of storage space to total square feet increases. ","  D. Inventory decreases and the ratio of storage space to total square feet decreases"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Increasing the number of warehouses tends to cause an increase in inventory as each adds a buffer of supply stock. On the other hand, the ratio of storage space to total square feet tends to decrease as each facility contains nonstorage areas that could be consolidated in a single warehouse. "},{"question":"The marketing department's involvement with product management includes which of the following phases of the product's life cycle?","choices":["A. Development through introduction ","  B. Introduction only ","  C. Conception through maturity ","  D. All phases, from conception through withdrawal "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Marketing can play a useful role in planning, tracking, and managing demand from the beginning to the end of the life cycle.  "},{"question":"Expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain may be offset by which of the following?","choices":["A. Sale of service contracts ","  B. Rebates from landfills ","  C. More efficient use of warehouses set up for forward logistics ","  D. Freight discounts on shipments of returned items"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Revenue from the sale of service contracts can offset some of the expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain, including higher transportation fees for small, sporadic shipments; the addition of transportation lanes to reach specialized warehouses; and, of course, the costs to the company of making warranty repairs.  "},{"question":"When engaging the services of a fourth-party logistics provider, a logistics manager should be careful to minimize the effects of which of the following potential risks?","choices":["A. Less rapid adjustment to new customer technologies ","  B. Reduction in flexible deployment of resources ","  C. Reduction in control ","  D. Reduced economies of scale "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Transferring responsibility for logistics to a 4PL involves loss of control, so a manager may want to compensate with frequent reviews (at least at first). The upside of giving control of logistics to a specialist should be an increase in flexibility, greater economies of scale, and more advanced logistics technology.  "},{"question":"Which of the following strategies represents the traditional \"over the wall\" approach to product design?","choices":["A. Supplier plays no role in design. ","  B. Formal design team includes supplier. ","  C. Supplier informally makes recommendations to design engineers. ","  D. Supplier creates the design. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In the traditional design process, the supplier plays no role in design. The design is created by design engineers and passed \"over the wall,\" figuratively, to manufacturing and other stakeholders.  "},{"question":"When a logistics manager removes a complete echelon from the distribution chain to reduce overall expenses, there may be a tradeoff for expenses in which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Increased transportation costs for extra miles of carriage ","  B. Increased taxes on property and equipment ","  C. Increased inventory handling costs ","  D. Increased inventory holding costs"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Removing an echelon from the network should reduce all the costs specified in the options except for transportation costs. Removing one level of warehousing, for example, will most likely increase the number of miles goods are carried from the points upstream from the echelon to the points downstream.  "},{"question":"In the CPFR model, which of the following corresponds to the order-to-cash cycle?","choices":["A. Demand and supply management ","  B. Logistics/distribution ","  C. Execution ","  D. Order fulfillment"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The area of CPFR that corresponds to the order-to-cash cycle is execution, which includes the collaboration tasks of order generation and order fulfillment. Order fulfillment includes the enterprise task of logistics/distribution.  "},{"question":"According to the World Trade Organization, which of the following is the right amount to use when declaring the value of imported goods?","choices":["A. Exporter's cost plus transaction expenses ","  B. Actual price to the importer ","  C. Calculated market value ","  D. Amount stated in the harmonized code for the goods in the cargo "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The price paid (or scheduled to be paid) by the importer is the right amount to use when declaring the value of an import. The WTO does permit other \"reasonable\" methods of valuation if circumstances warrant.  "},{"question":"An importer will often give which one of the following independent operators power of attorney to pay import duties on its behalf?","choices":["A. Foreign carrier ","  B. ETC ","  C. Customs house broker ","  D. Ship broker "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The customs house broker specializes in moving imported goods through customs, expediting paperwork (which now takes place electronically), and paying the import duties under a power of attorney from the importer. "},{"question":"In a multiple-echelon distribution network where each warehouse orders independently based on local demand, where in the chain do you find the most variance in order quantity?","choices":["A. Variability tends to increase toward the raw materials end of the chain. ","  B. Variability tends to increase toward the customer end of the chain. ","  C. Variability tends to remain constant along the chain. ","  D. Variability tend to be greatest in the middle of the chain, diminishing toward either end."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In many chains, variance in order quantity tends to increase as you move upstream away from the end customer. This is the bullwhip effect. "},{"question":"Place the following modes of transportation in order of rate per ton-mile for carrying cargo, with I being the lowest rates and IV being the highest.","choices":["I. ","\tRail ","\tII. ","\tAir "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Water transport offers the lowest rates per ton, much lower even than rail, which is second. Trucking is considerably more expensive than rail but substantially less expensive than air.  "},{"question":"\tIV. ","choices":["\tTruck","A. I, III, IV, II ","  B. III, I, IV, II ","  C. III, IV, II, I "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"\tWater "},{"question":"Risk pooling is a means of reducing the risk of stockouts by consolidating inventory in a central warehouse. With a larger store of goods in the central warehouse, even the largest, unexpected order will have less chance of exhausting the inventory, as it might in a smaller warehouse. With fewer facilities adding safety stock to their orders (plus the lower stockout risk), the total amount of inventory can be reduced, and less inventory means lower holding and handling expenses. Lead times may go up, however, for deliveries made to customers that are more distant from the central warehouse than from the smaller facilities it replaced. ","choices":["Which of the following may increase as a tradeoff when a logistics chain institutes risk pooling by moving inventory from several smaller warehouses to a larger central storage facility?","A. Delivery lead times ","  B. Number of stockouts ","  C. Total amount of inventory held at one time "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"46.  The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"With their intermodal networks, FedEx, UPS, and DHL offer door-to-door delivery on rapid timetables, but they are not inexpensive. As delivery services, they are perhaps best used when speed is more important than price. Many express services offer logistics consultation and total logistics management (4PL) and are capable of providing small businesses the benefit of economies of scale and deep logistics expertise.  ","choices":["Which one of the following is the most significant drawback of specialized package carriers such as FedEx and DHL?","A. Too expensive for small businesses to use economically ","  B. Lack of multimodal capability ","  C. Lack of flexibility in pickup and delivery locations "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"47. The correct answer is D. "},{"question":"Product families for purposes of the operations plan are best chosen by similar manufacturing requirements to facilitate other planning processes, such as production scheduling. (Marketing can group products in other ways for its purposes.)  ","choices":["Which of the following would provide a sound method for grouping products into product families for the operations plan?","A. Similarity of manufacturing processes ","  B. National market destination ","  C. Similar seasonality "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"48.  The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"The average demand for the three months from January through March is 20 (21 + 17 + 22 = 60; 60 / 3 = 20), so the forecast for April is 20, which is two less than the actual demand. ","choices":["Referring to the table below, calculate a forecast for April using the three-month moving average method. Based on your calculation, which of the following statements correctly relates the forecast to the actual April demand of 22? ","A. Demand and forecast are the same. ","  B. Demand exceeds forecast by 1. ","  C. Demand exceeds forecast by 2. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"49. The correct answer is C. "},{"question":"The seller (exporter) sends a draft to its banker, who honors it based upon its assurance of reimbursement by the buyer's bank, which in its turn depends upon reimbursement by the buyer (whose money it may already hold on account).  ","choices":["When international trade is financed with a letter of credit, which of the following entities actually makes the final payment to the seller?","A. Buyer's bank ","  B. Inland export carrier ","  C. Buyer "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"50.  The correct answer is D. "},{"question":"The sales and marketing area is responsible and accountable for forecasting. Someone has to be responsible for the forecast for assessment purposes, but this does not mean that other areas cannot contribute to the forecast or that the forecast cannot be shared with other functional areas and supply chain partners. Information sharing is key to supply chain management.  ","choices":["Which one of the following functional areas is responsible for demand forecasting?","A. Sales and marketing ","  B. Purchasing ","  C. IT "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"51. The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"Fixed quantity ordering is generally used to fill containers, qualify for quantity discounts, or both. The model works best when demand is known and stable with predictable lead times. ","choices":["Use of a fixed order quantity model is most likely to be effective in which of the following cases?","A. Lead time is highly variable. ","  B. Shipper is looking for quantity discounts. ","  C. Demand is highly unpredictable and light. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"52. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"If a work center has more load than capacity, shifting work to another center is one possible way to restore the balance (if another center is available and has excess capacity). You can also increase available time (more workers, machines, or hours of work) or increase efficiency.  ","choices":["Which one of the following actions would be appropriate if the load scheduled for a work site exceeds its rated capacity?","A. Shift work to another work center with available capacity. ","  B. Lay off workers. ","  C. Reduce workers' hours to save money. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"53.  The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"Freight forwarders function like \"travel agents for cargo,\" arranging for transport but not operating their own carriers.  ","choices":["Which one of the following types of third-party logistics firms schedules cargo transport but operates no carriers?","A. Consolidator ","  B. Export trading company (ETC) ","  C. Freight forwarder "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"54.  The correct answer is C. "},{"question":"In break-bulk operations, the incoming shipment moves straight through the warehouse to be broken down on the dock and reshipped.  ","choices":["Which one of the following warehouse operations assumes no storage of incoming goods before reshipping?","A. Break-bulk ","  B. Assembly-to-order ","  C. Spot stocking "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"55.  The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"Incoterms were first issued in 1936 by the International Chamber of Commerce, which has updated them several times since then to reflect the changing conditions of international trade. ","choices":["Which one of the following entities is responsible for issuing and updating Incoterms?","A. World Trade Organization ","  B. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) ","  C. United Nations "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"56.  The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"The chase production strategy, also called demand matching, attempts to match production to demand in each period of the schedule. If the strategy succeeds, inventory costs can be kept to a minimum. The tradeoffs include possibilities of extra hiring (or layoffs) if demand and production don't match, plus a need to ramp up capacity to match peak demand.  ","choices":["The S\u0026OP planning team might decide to adopt a chase production strategy because it offers which of the following benefits?","A. Protection against a sudden need to hire temp workers in production ","  B. More predictable production scheduling ","  C. Reduction of resource costs during demand periods "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"57.  The correct answer is D. "},{"question":"The exporter bears responsibility for determining the classification of the goods it sells in international transactions. It does so by reference to the harmonized tariff codes.  ","choices":["Which of the following parties determines the tariff classification of an import?","A. World Trade Organization inspectors ","  B. Customs ","  C. Exporter "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"58.  The correct answer is C. "},{"question":"The air waybill is a nonnegotiable standardized form used by all air carriers.  ","choices":["Which of the following is a standardized, nonnegotiable form listing items being shipped directly to the titleholder?","A. Air waybill ","  B. Ocean bill ","  C. Ship's manifest "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"59. The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"Pipelines are considered a very secure way to convey liquid cargo. Except for earthquakes or terrorist attacks, pipelines will carry appropriate freight with almost no risk of loss or damage.  ","choices":["Which of the following offers the greatest security against loss of cargo when transporting petroleum?","A. Water ","  B. Pipelines ","  C. Road "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"60. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"The risk of having inventory items become obsolete increases when amounts ordered exceed the forecast significantly. Economies of scale in transport and purchase are potential benefits of larger orders, as is decoupling from the supplier.  ","choices":["Which of the following identifies a risk of ordering more inventory than required to fill forecast orders?","A. Higher per-car costs for transporting the inventory ","  B. Increased obsolescence ","  C. Higher per-item costs for purchasing the inventory "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"61. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"In seller's credit financing, the seller (exporter) accepts the importer's credit card (or other promise to pay) and thus takes the most financial risk involved in any of options described.  ","choices":["The exporter takes the most risk in which of the following export-import financing arrangements?","A. Letter of credit ","  B. Buyer's payment from an open account ","  C. Consignment of goods "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"62. The correct answer is D. "},{"question":"Spot stocking is used for limited product lines and highly seasonal products that can be centrally stored during most of the year and spot-stocked in season at warehouses near the places where they will be purchased and used. Manufacturers use spot stocking for agricultural products used only during one limited operation, such as harvesting.  ","choices":["Which one of the following types of warehousing is most appropriate for agricultural supplies that might be used only once during the year?","A. Spot stocking ","  B. Stockpiling ","  C. Assortment "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"63. The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"A full truck qualifies for a per-pound (kilogram) discount, since the carrier benefits from being able to charge more per unit of weight. Similarly, heavier loads (subject to limits) and greater density yield economies of scale. \"Lane density\" refers to the amount of cargo traffic around the destination; greater density means more potential business for the carrier on the return trip. Low lane density can lead to a return trip with an empty vehicle, at the expense of the shipper.  ","choices":["If you're planning to ship goods over the road, which of the following represents a strategy for lowering your per-pound costs for the trip?","A. Fill up the trucks. ","  B. Ship to destinations with low lane volume. ","  C. Keep the weight down in each truck. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"64.  The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"Consolidation is the process of breaking down incoming shipments from a variety of sources to mix the various products together in combinations specified by a number of recipients. (The process is also called mixing.) The mix of products may include items from storage as well as those just received. ","choices":["Which one of the following warehouse operations resembles break-bulk, except that it combines products from more than one manufacturer and may also involve product storage?","A. Stockpiling ","  B. Cross-docking ","  C. Consolidation "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"65. The correct answer is C. "},{"question":"The strong suit of trucking is accessibility, since trucks can go to virtually any commercial location. This along with size and weight limits makes trucking most appropriate for carrying high-value items of smaller size for short hauls.  ","choices":["Which of the following constitutes the most appropriate shipment to send by truck?","A. Heavy, low-value items traveling long distances ","  B. Small, high-value items traveling a short distance ","  C. Bulky items traveling between cities "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"66. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"Spot stocking is used for limited product lines and highly seasonal products that can be centrally stored during most of the year and spot-stocked in season at warehouses near the places where they will be purchased and used. Manufacturers use spot stocking for agricultural products used only during one limited operation, such as harvesting.  ","choices":["Which one of the following types of warehousing is most appropriate for agricultural supplies that might be used only once during the year?","A. Stockpiling ","  B. Postponement ","  C. Assortment "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"67. The correct answer is D. "},{"question":"The forecast accuracy is likely to be greatest for all DaimlerChrysler models (and then for all Dodges, all Dodge Stratuses, and all Dodge Stratus SEs, in descending order of accuracy). The larger the aggregate, the more accurate the forecast. ","choices":["Demand forecasts are likely to be most accurate for which of the following items?","A. All Dodge Models ","  B. All DaimlerChrysler cars ","  C. All Dodge Stratus models "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"68. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"Dividing the total time available during a scheduled period at the site by the lead time tells you how many operations can be produced at the site in the period.  ","choices":["Which of the following (assuming site- and period-specific data) would provide the number of operations that can be produced at a site during a single period of time?","A. Lead time available divided by load ","  B. Lead time available divided by total time ","  C. Total time available divided by lead time "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"69. The correct answer is C. "},{"question":"Pipelines are costly in other ways, but their operating costs are relatively low (no drivers or pilots, for one thing).  ","choices":["Which of the following modes of transporting petroleum involves the lowest operating costs?","A. Rail ","  B. Pipeline ","  C. Tanker truck "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"70. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"In the model, certain tasks are performed by the buyer/retailer (POS forecasting in this case), certain tasks are performed by the seller/manufacturer (market analysis in this case), and those tasks are reconciled in a joint session. The joint session to reconcile POS forecasting and market analysis results in a shared sales forecast.  ","choices":["In the CPFR model, which of the following tasks would be performed jointly by the manufacturer (seller) and the retailer (buyer)?","A. POS (point-of-sale) forecasting ","  B. Market data analysis ","  C. Sales forecasting "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"71. The correct answer is C. "},{"question":"The three-month moving average forecast for May is 20.33, which is the average monthly demand for the months from February through April (17 + 22 + 22 = 61 / 3 = 20.33); the naive forecast is taken from the period preceding the forecast period, which in this case is 22, the actual demand for May. Note that the naive forecast (22) is more nearly accurate in this case, because it adjusts faster than the moving average. However, it could just as easily have been less accurate if demand had changed in a different direction or by a different amount.  ","choices":["Referring to the demand table below, calculate forecasts for May using both the three-month moving average (MA) and the naive forecasting methods. Which of the following statements correctly identifies the two forecasts? ","A. MA forecast = 20.33; naive forecast = 22 ","  B. MA forecast = 20.67; naive forecast = 20 ","  C. MA forecast = 21.33; naive forecast = 22 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"72. The correct answer is A. "},{"question":"The commercial invoice is the document that states the value of commodities in a shipment. (It does not include other amounts, such as freight.)  ","choices":["Which of the following documents would a banker consult for information about the value of export-import cargo in connection with a letter of credit?","A. Order bill of lading ","  B. Commercial invoice ","  C. Ship's manifest "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"73. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"Rail provides a rough ride for cargo, resulting in more breakage than occurs in cargo transported by truck, water, or air.  ","choices":["A logistics manager concerned to avoid breakage of cargo would be least inclined to choose which of the following modes of transportation (ignoring tradeoffs)?","A. Air transport ","  B. Truck transport ","  C. Water transport "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"74. The correct answer is D. "},{"question":"Steering wheels are a dependent demand item; the demand for dependent items should be calculated from the forecast of demand for their parent items. Steering wheels are a component; the new cars they go into are the parents. Replacement parts are sold, manufactured, and forecast as independent items, not as dependent components.  ","choices":["For which of the following items should demand be calculated rather than forecast?","A. All Chevrolets ","  B. All Chevrolet Cobalts ","  C. All steering wheels for new Chevrolet Cobalts "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"75. The correct answer is C. "},{"question":"The deseasonalized demand is the sum of the seasonal averages divided by the number of \"seasons\" (or months) listed: (100 + 102 + 105 + 106 + 107 + 110) / 6 = 630 / 6 = 105. ","choices":["Which of the following correctly identifies the deseasonalized monthly demand (to the nearest whole number) for the first half of the calendar year in the example shown in the table below? ","A. 100 ","  B. 105 ","  C. 186 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"76. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"Water transport offers the lowest rates per ton, much lower even than rail, which is second. Trucking is considerably more expensive than rail but substantially less expensive than air ","choices":["Place the following modes of transportation in order of rate per ton-mile for carrying cargo, with I being the lowest rates and IV being the highest.","I. ","\tRail ","\tII. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"77. The correct answer is B. "},{"question":"\tWater ","choices":["\tIV. ","\tTruck","A. I, III, IV, II ","  B. III, I, IV, II "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"\tIII. "},{"question":"78. The correct answer is C. ","choices":["An assemble-to-order strategy may require warehouse or sales personnel to complete the final stages of finishing a product, thus requiring workers to acquire new skills and, in some cases, the facility to expand capacity to accommodate the finishing operations.  ","Which one of the following production strategies sometimes meets resistance from distribution centers because of the increased demands for skill training and capacity expansion?","A. Make-to-order ","  B. JIT "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"  D. IV, I, II, III "},{"question":"79. The correct answer is D. ","choices":["Reducing use of resources ranks highest in the reverse logistics hierarchy. The other strategies mentioned are also responsible and should be used when options higher up the pyramid are not feasible.  ","Which of the following is generally considered to be the most responsible strategy for managing reverse logistics?","A. Accepting product returns for recycling by the manufacturer ","  B. Breaking down returned goods to reuse undamaged components "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  D. Make-to-stock "},{"question":"80. The correct answer is C. ","choices":["Revenue from the sale of service contracts can offset some of the expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain, including higher transportation fees for small, sporadic shipments; the addition of transportation lanes to reach specialized warehouses; and, of course, the costs to the company of making warranty repairs. ",". ","Expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain may be offset by which of the following?","A. Rebates from landfills "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  D. Reduction of resources used in extraction, manufacture, and packaging "},{"question":"  D. More efficient use of warehouses set up for forward logistics ","choices":["81.  The correct answer is C. ","The business cycle correlates with alternating medium-term advances and declines in consumer buying patterns. Cycles are not short-term fluctuations related to holidays or random events, nor are they steady trends in only one direction, such as might be caused by factors such as a product cycle or demographics.  ","Which of the following might cause cyclical movements in a time series of demand data?","A. Random changes in consumer sentiment "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Sale of service contracts "},{"question":"  D. Holiday shopping","choices":["82. The correct answer is C. ","Naive forecasting assumes that demand in the next period will equal demand in the last period. It is a form of quantitative forecasting but lacks any analysis.  ","Which of the following forms the basis for a naive demand forecast?","A. Market analysis "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Recession "},{"question":"  D. Analogy ","choices":["83. The correct answer is C. ","Retail trade is forbidden inside a foreign trade zone. All the other activities are specifically permitted.  ","Which one of the following is not allowed in a foreign trade zone?","A. Performing break-bulk operations to reduce import duties owed "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Data from the last demand period "},{"question":"  D. Repackaging or otherwise altering cargo to remedy potential customs violations ","choices":["84. The correct answer is C. ","Basing a forecast for a product on data about economic indicators such as housing starts, population trends, or employment statistics is called extrinsic forecasting to distinguish it from intrinsic forecasting based on data about the product itself. Historical analogy bases forecasts for one product on data from a similar (analogous) product, not on data about economic trends. ","Basing a demand forecast for kitchen appliances on housing start data is an example of which of the following?","A. Dependent demand forecasting "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Retail trade "},{"question":"  D. Pyramid forecasting","choices":["85.  The correct answer is B. ","When all capacity and materials have been committed to specific orders, a demand time fence may be placed on the MPS, marking off a frozen zone in which no orders can be filled without permission from senior management.  ","Capacity and materials are committed to specific orders inside which of the following zones on the master production schedule?","A. Slushy zone "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Extrinsic forecasting "},{"question":"  D. Planning zone","choices":["86. The correct answer is C. ","The seller (exporter) sends a draft to its banker, who honors it based upon its assurance of reimbursement by the buyer's bank, which in its turn depends upon reimbursement by the buyer (whose money it may already hold on account).  ","When international trade is financed with a letter of credit, which of the following entities actually makes the final payment to the seller?","A. Buyer's bank "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Liquid zone "},{"question":"  D. Inland export carrier ","choices":["87. The correct answer is D. ","All shipments intended to cross a border are initiated by a bill of lading (B/L). The B/L constitutes the carrier's contract and receipt for the goods to be transported.  ","Which of the following is the type of contract that initiates all foreign shipments?","A. Export license "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Seller's bank "},{"question":"  D. Bill of lading","choices":["88. The correct answer is D. ","The chase production strategy, also called demand matching, attempts to match production to demand in each period of the schedule. If the strategy succeeds, inventory costs can be kept to a minimum. The tradeoffs include possibilities of extra hiring (or layoffs) if demand and production don't match, plus a need to ramp up capacity to match peak demand.  ","The S\u0026OP planning team might decide to adopt a chase production strategy because it offers which of the following benefits?","A. Protection against a sudden need to hire temp workers in production "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Certificate of origin "},{"question":"  D. Reduced inventory holding costs ","choices":["89. The correct answer is C. ","The business plan provides a long-range view of strategy and guidance for developing tactical plans for sales, marketing, and operations.  ","A business plan would typically include which of the following?","A. Definition of sales territories "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. More predictable production scheduling "},{"question":"  D. Monthly production figures for each product family ","choices":["90. The correct answer is D. ","Assortment planning in industries in which demand and product styles change with each season present a special challenge to forecasters. The constant rotation through different styles or models means there is little historical demand data for particular products. VICS CPFR includes a scenario with guidelines for assortment planning based on graphic presentations of new models along with financial models.  ","CPFR includes formal guidelines for a growing number of scenarios. Which of the following CPFR scenarios includes such methods as graphical presentations of new products to help make merchandizing decisions in the absence of solid historical data on demand?","A. Store replenishment collaboration "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Long-term guidance for developing tactical production plans "},{"question":"  D. Collaborative assortment planning","choices":["91.  The correct answer is C. ","Expenses related to construction, right of way, and pumping capacity give pipelines the highest fixed costs of any mode of transporting freight.  ","Which of the following has the highest fixed cost of any means of transporting petroleum?","A. Ships "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Retail event collaboration "},{"question":"  D. Trains ","choices":["92. The correct answer is A. ","Capacity control takes place in the very short term in the context of daily production. ","Capacity control takes place against which of the following time horizons?","A. Everyday activity "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Pipelines "},{"question":"  D. Long term ","choices":["93.  The correct answer is D. ","The ABC system of classifying inventory asserts that the A items in your inventory will constitute only about 15 percent of the total number of items but will create 70 to 80 percent of value. This is an approximate application of the Pareto principle, or 80-20 rule, which holds that about 20 percent of possible causes account for about 80 percent of outcomes.  ","According to the ABC system of classifying inventory, an application of the Pareto principle, the greatest share of revenue will be generated by which of the following numbers of inventory items (approximately)?","A. 80 percent "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Annual horizon "},{"question":"  D. 15 percent","choices":["94.  The correct answer is B. ","The \"Orange Book\" is published by the United Nations; its first edition came out in 1956. It contains the United Nations Recommendations on the Transport of Dangerous Goods (UNRMTDG), in which all national controls are grounded. The UN recommendations do not have the force of law, but national regulations based on them may.  ","Which of the following institutions publishes the \"Orange Book\" containing recommendations that form the basis of international dangerous goods (hazardous materials) laws and regulations?","A. World Court "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 30 percent "},{"question":"  D. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) ","choices":["95. The correct answer is A. ","Lot-for-lot sizing is typically used with small, frequent deliveries of dependent demand items. Longer time buckets and larger order sizes are more likely to require a buffer of safety stock.  ","Which of the following conditions is generally associated with lot-for-lot order sizing?","A. Small, frequent orders "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. International Maritime Association "},{"question":"  D. Safety stock buffers","choices":["96. The correct answer is C. ","Designing products in kit form makes them easier to transport, store, and package, all aspects of logistics. ","Which of the following design philosophies is most responsible for furniture that comes in kit form to be assembled by the retail customer at home?","A. Concurrent engineering "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Large batches "},{"question":"  D. Design for manufacture ","choices":["97. The correct answer is C. ","Air transport subjects cargo to the least likelihood of damage en route. It places the most restrictions on the weight of packaging, so it both allows and requires the least durable packaging ","Which of the following modes of carrying cargo requires the least durable packaging?","A. Inland water carriage "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Design for logistics "},{"question":"  D. Rail ","choices":["98. The correct answer is A. ","A hard drive is a module that, along with other modules, can be mixed and matched to assemble computers with many different features.  ","A hard drive that can be used in many different kinds of computers is an example of which of the following design strategies?","A. Modular design "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Air "},{"question":"  D. Universality ","choices":["99. The correct answer is D. ","Pipeline inventory is stock kept on hand to fill orders while the next lot is in transit. It is also known as transportation inventory.  ","Inventory held to cover transit time is called which of the following?","A. Work-in-process inventory "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Integral design "},{"question":"  D. Pipeline inventory","choices":["100. The correct answer is B. ","Periodic inventory counts provide a value for inventory at one point in time, but they disrupt business, are relatively expensive, are prone to inaccuracy, and don't promote accurate ordering policies (because they are infrequent and tend to be inaccurate).  ","Which of the following correctly describes the benefit of conducting periodic inventory counts?","A. Periodic counting is inexpensive. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Fluctuation inventory "},{"question":"  D. Periodic counting promotes accurate ordering. ","choices":["101. The correct answer is D. ","The routing and work center files contain all the times necessary to calculate the total lead time. ","Lead time can be determined from the information in which of the following?","A. Work center file "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Periodic counts don't disrupt the ordinary flow of business. "},{"question":"  D. Both a and b","choices":["102. The correct answer is D. ","As a demand planning concept, \"seasonality\" refers to demand patterns influenced by time, not just by the four seasons of the year. The restaurant business varies with the calendar, the day of the week, and the time of day.  ","The impact of seasonality on demand in a fast-food restaurant might be measured in which of the following ways?","A. Time of year "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Open order file "},{"question":"  D. All of the above","choices":["103. The correct answer is A. ","Typically used with JIT, lot-for-lot sizing delivers the exact amount needed when it is needed, thereby eliminating inventory buffers. Frequent delivery of small lots requires more setups.  ","Which one of the following conditions is a potential drawback of lot-for-lot order sizing?","A. High setup costs "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Hour of the day "},{"question":"  D. Inventory build-up ","choices":["104. The correct answer is B. ","Automated guided vehicle systems (AGVS) ride along magnetic wire or optical tape. They are fully programmable, require no rider, and can be equipped with forks. ","Which of the following is a riderless material-handling device that moves along optical tape or magnetic wire in the floor?","A. Automated storage and retrieval system (AS/RS) "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. High inventory costs "},{"question":"  D. Radio-controlled crane truck","choices":["105. The correct answer is D. ","Smoothing constants are generally chosen between 0.05 and 0.50. A constant of 0 would give the same forecast as for the previous month, because it would eliminate the portion of the equation including the forecast error. A constant of 1.0 would yield a forecast equal to the current month's demand; in the equation, the forecast numbers would cancel out, leaving only the actual demand amount. In between 0 and 1, the constant determines how much weight you give to the forecast error.  ","Which of the following smoothing constants would yield the same result as a naive forecast?","A. 0.01 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Automated sorting device "},{"question":"  D. 1.0","choices":["106. The correct answer is A. ","Break-bulk operations break an incoming shipment from one source into smaller lots for reshipping to specific customers. ","Which one of the following warehouse operations would take place at a manufacturer's centralized warehouse to facilitate delivery of one product to many retailers?","A. Break-bulk "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 0.50 "},{"question":"  D. Mixing","choices":["107. The correct answer is C. ","The MAD (mean absolute deviation) is the average amount by which the forecast differs from the actual demand (Deviation = Demand - Forecast). It is \"absolute\" because it takes into account only the amount of the deviation, not the direction. Tracking the absolute deviation provides information for use in assessing the reliability of forecasts.  ","Which of the following correctly identifies the MAD for the six months in the example shown in the table below? ","A. -8.00 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Consolidation "},{"question":"  D. 12.00","choices":["108. The correct answer is C. ","The master production schedule includes dates of production for make-to-stock end items. (This can be either finished products or, in a modular approach, components.)  ","For make-to-stock production of an integral design, the master production schedule includes production dates for which of the following?","A. Components "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 2.00 "},{"question":"  D. Product families ","choices":["109. The correct answer is B. ","The risk of having inventory items become obsolete increases when amounts ordered exceed the forecast significantly. Economies of scale in transport and purchase are potential benefits of larger orders, as is decoupling from the supplier.  ","Which of the following identifies a risk of ordering more inventory than required to fill forecast orders?","A. Higher per-car costs for transporting the inventory "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. End items "},{"question":"  D. Decoupling from supplier","choices":["110. The correct answer is D. ","Risk pooling is a means of reducing the risk of stockouts by consolidating inventory in a central warehouse. With a larger store of goods in the central warehouse, even the largest, unexpected order will have less chance of exhausting the inventory, as it might in a smaller warehouse. With fewer facilities adding safety stock to their orders (plus the lower stockout risk), the total amount of inventory can be reduced, and less inventory means lower holding and handling expenses. Lead times may go up, however, for deliveries made to customers that are more distant from the central warehouse than from the smaller facilities it replaced.  ","Which of the following may increase as a tradeoff when a logistics chain institutes risk pooling by moving inventory from several smaller warehouses to a larger central storage facility?","A. Total amount of inventory held at one time "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Higher per-item costs for purchasing the inventory "},{"question":"  D. Delivery lead times","choices":["111. The correct answer is B. ","The MRP schedules delivery of dependent demand items (which are in turn based upon independent demand forecasts). The other processes work with independent demand or product families.  ","Which one of the following processes results in production numbers driven by dependent demand?","A. Master production scheduling process "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Number of stockouts "},{"question":"  D. Sales and operations planning process","choices":["112. The correct answer is C. ","A planning bill of materials includes small items intended for use in a variety of finished items. They are ordered in bulk for convenience and economies of scale even though they have no one parent to list on a regular bill of materials.  ","Which of the following could appear in a planning bill of materials?","A. All the #10 nails intended for delivery to a chain of home improvement stores "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Market planning process "},{"question":"  D. All the parts necessary to manufacture one car radio ","choices":["113. The correct answer is D. ","Disaggregation takes place during the development of the master production schedule.  ","Which of the following processes includes the disaggregation of product families?","A. Operations planning "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. All the transistors to be used in assembling a variety of electronics components "},{"question":"  D. Master production scheduling ","choices":["114. The correct answer is B. ","To achieve economies of scale in transportation, consolidation combines shipments from many incoming sources when loading outbound vehicles headed for a single location.  ","Which one of the following warehouse operations is most appropriate for a manufacturer that receives components from many suppliers and wants to achieve economies of scale when transporting those components to one plant?","A. Cross-dock "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Sales planning "},{"question":"  D. Break-bulk","choices":["115. The correct answer is D. ","With their intermodal networks, FedEx, UPS, and DHL offer door-to-door delivery on rapid timetables, but they are not inexpensive. As delivery services, they are perhaps best used when speed is more important than price. Many express services offer logistics consultation and total logistics management (4PL) and are capable of providing small businesses the benefit of economies of scale and deep logistics expertise.  ","Which one of the following is the most significant drawback of specialized package carriers such as FedEx and DHL?","A. Lack of multimodal capability "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Mixing "},{"question":"  D. Price","choices":["116. The correct answer is A. ","RCCP determines if resources are available (or can be made available) in the network to achieve the goals in the master schedule.  ","Which of the following is an input to rough-cut capacity planning (RCCP)?","A. Master schedule "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Lack of flexibility in pickup and delivery locations "},{"question":"  D. Aggregate output per product family ","choices":["117. The correct answer is A. ","Forecast data should include demand for all product options as well as total demand for the product. You want to know when items were in demand, not when they were shipped. Competitors' product introductions are likely to affect your forecasts. Returns and cancellations should be subtracted from orders when calculating actual demand.  ","Which one of the following represents a sound approach to tracking data to use in demand forecasting?","A. Include all product options. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Weekly output per component "},{"question":"  D. Exclude cancellations and returns. ","choices":["118. The correct answer is A. ","The three-month weighted moving average forecast for April is 20.17 (3 x 22 = 66; 2 x 17 = 34; 1 x 21 = 21; 66 + 34 + 21 = 121; 121 / 6 = 20.17). Did you remember to divide by the sum of the weights (6) instead of by 3?  ","Referring to the demand table below, calculate a three-month weighted moving average forecast for April using a 3-2-1 weighting for March, February, and January, respectively. Which of the following identifies the correct forecast for April using this method? ","A. 20.17 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Include data by ship date, not order date. "},{"question":"  D. 40.33","choices":["119. The correct answer is D. ","Market segmentation and the deployment of the sales force can be based upon any of a number of criteria, including but by no means limited to geography, market potential, or age.  ","Which of the following constitutes a potentially appropriate way to segment a market?","A. Geography "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 20.67 "},{"question":"  D. Any of the above can be appropriate.","choices":["120. The correct answer is C. ","Transferring responsibility for logistics to a 4PL involves loss of control, so a manager may want to compensate with frequent reviews (at least at first). The upside of giving control of logistics to a specialist should be an increase in flexibility, greater economies of scale, and more advanced logistics technology. ","When engaging the services of a fourth-party logistics provider, a logistics manager should be careful to minimize the effects of which of the following potential risks?","A. Reduction in flexible deployment of resources "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Age "},{"question":"  D. Less rapid adjustment to new customer technologies ","choices":["121. The correct answer is B. ","Product families for purposes of the operations plan are best chosen by similar manufacturing requirements to facilitate other planning processes, such as production scheduling. (Marketing can group products in other ways for its purposes.)  ","Which of the following would provide a sound method for grouping products into product families for the operations plan?","A. Similar seasonality "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Reduction in control "},{"question":"  D. Appeal to a particular age group ","choices":["122. The correct answer is A. ","Removing an echelon from the network should reduce all the costs specified in the options except for transportation costs. Removing one level of warehousing, for example, will most likely increase the number of miles goods are carried from the points upstream from the echelon to the points downstream.  ","When a logistics manager removes a complete echelon from the distribution chain to reduce overall expenses, there may be a tradeoff for expenses in which of the following areas?","A. Increased transportation costs for extra miles of carriage "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. National market destination "},{"question":"  D. Increased inventory holding costs ","choices":["123. The correct answer is A. ","Using common components for a variety of purposes provides economies of scale in purchasing and manufacture but can limit design flexibility and reduce quality.  ","Which of the following design strategies offers streamlined production and lower purchasing costs with a possible tradeoff against reduced design flexibility and lower quality?","A. Component commonality "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Increased taxes on property and equipment "},{"question":"  D. Integral design ","choices":["124. The correct answer is C. ","The sales and operations plan takes the business plan as its point of reference for developing a plan that balances supply and demand by merging input from sales and marketing on the one hand and operations on the other.  ","Which of the following provides a point of reference for formulating the sales and operations plan?","A. Production forecast "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Mass customization "},{"question":"  D. Marketing plan ","choices":["125. The correct answer is D. ","Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR®) is a formal description of best practices developed and maintained by VICS to help supply chain partners develop successful collaborations. ","Which of the following is a type of supply chain collaboration formalized by the Voluntary Interindustry Commerce Standards Association (VICS)?","A. Quick response "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Business plan "},{"question":"  D. Collective planning, forecasting, and replenishment","choices":["126. The correct answer is A. ","The exporter determines the tariff classification using the harmonized code when packaging the goods for export. The importer (usually through the customs house broker) pays the duty when goods come through customs.  ","Which one of the following describes the typical situation in regards to payment of import duties?","A. The exporter determines the tariff classification and the importer pays the duty. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Vendor-managed inventory "},{"question":"  D. The exporter determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. ","choices":["127. The correct answer is D. ","A certificate of origin states that the cargo originated in the exporter's country and is therefore eligible for the favorable import duty granted to goods originating in that country. To qualify for the lowest rates, importers sometimes have their purchases shipped from the country of origin through a country qualifying for more favorable rates and then reexported to their own country. The country of origin is the place in which the goods in question last underwent a significant transformation, not the country from which they were shipped.  ","Which of the following documents is used to bolster an importer's claims for favorable import duty rates granted by treaty to the exporter's country?","A. Export B/L "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. The importer determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. "},{"question":"  D. Certificate of origin","choices":["128. The correct answer is C. ","The sales and operations plan typically extends out at least a year and no more than 18 months and involves both short- and medium-term planning.  ","Which of the following would be a typical time horizon for sales and operations planning?","A. One week to one month "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Consular invoice "},{"question":"  D. 18 months to three years ","choices":["129. The correct answer is B. ","Order B/Ls can be used to transfer ownership of cargo. Straight B/Ls (including air bills) document cargo intended for delivery straight to the buyer without intermediate title transfers.  ","Which one of the following is a negotiable certificate of ownership?","A. Straight B/L "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 12 to 18 months "},{"question":"  D. Air waybill ","choices":["130. The correct answer is B. ","If a work center has more load than capacity, shifting work to another center is one possible way to restore the balance (if another center is available and has excess capacity). You can also increase available time (more workers, machines, or hours of work) or increase efficiency.  ","Which one of the following actions would be appropriate if the load scheduled for a work site exceeds its rated capacity?","A. Reduce workers' hours to save money. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Dock receipt "},{"question":"  D. Lay off workers.","choices":["131. The correct answer is B. ","The conveyer belt has no operator, so it not only minimizes operator costs, it eliminates them. Automated towlines are not likely to appeal to the cost-conscious manager.  ","Which one of the following would you select to move pallets through warehouse aisles while minimizing costs?","A. Automated towlines "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Order more safety stock. "},{"question":"  D. Forklift truck","choices":["132. The correct answer is B. ","Coal makes up the bulk of rail cargo in both the United States and Great Britain. Rail transport is most appropriate for heavy, durable items of low value like raw materials, agricultural products, chemicals, construction materials, and industrial metals.  ","Which of the following items makes up the majority of rail cargo in the United States and Great Britain?","A. Heavy industrial products, such as automobiles and equipment "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Tow tractors with trailers "},{"question":"  D. Forest products ","choices":["133. The correct answer is C. ","The sales and operations plan reconciles the business plans of all units of the firm, including finance, sales and marketing, and operations; the unified set of numbers has the approval of senior management. It is neither a contract between sales and operations nor a balance of end item supply and demand.  ","Which of the following statements correctly identifies the major purpose of the sales and operations plan (S\u0026OP)?","A. S\u0026OP represents the firm's essential planning document for use in securing startup financing from bankers and investors. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Agricultural commodities "},{"question":"  D. S\u0026OP represents the essence of a contract between sales and operations.","choices":["134. The correct answer is C. ","The seasonal average demand for February is the monthly average demand for the three Februarys listed: (101 + 101 + 105) / 3 = 102.  ","Which of the following numbers is the correct seasonal average demand for February in the example shown in the table below (rounded to the nearest whole number)? ","A. 99 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. S\u0026OP represents the mutual agreement of finance, sales, marketing, operations, and senior management on a single set of supply/demand numbers. "},{"question":"  D. 105 ","choices":["135. The correct answer is A. ","The exporter bears responsibility for determining the classification of the goods it sells in international transactions. It does so by reference to the harmonized tariff codes.  ","Which of the following parties determines the tariff classification of an import?","A. Exporter "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 102 "},{"question":"  D. Importer","choices":["136. The correct answer is C. ","In seller's credit financing, the seller (exporter) accepts the importer's credit card (or other promise to pay) and thus takes the most financial risk involved in any of options described.  ","The exporter takes the most risk in which of the following export-import financing arrangements?","A. Buyer's payment from an open account "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. World Trade Organization inspectors "},{"question":"  D. Letter of credit","choices":["137. The correct answer is B. ","Available-to-promise equals the inventory on hand plus scheduled production reduced by orders already on the books. The ATP continues to decline as orders come in during the period. ","The master schedule shows inventory on hand of 150 items, scheduled production of 500 items, and booked orders of 400 items. Which of the following is the correct number of available-to-promise items?","A. 150 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Seller's credit "},{"question":"  D. 650 ","choices":["138. The correct answer is B. ","The larger the order, the higher the holding costs, because there is more inventory to hold. Setup costs tend to go down as orders grow larger because of economies of scale. (Larger orders can be placed less frequently than smaller orders, thus reducing the number of setups.)  ","In the economic order quantity calculation, which one of the following statements most accurately identifies the effect of increasing order sizes on inventory holding and order costs?","A. Holding costs remain constant while setup costs rise steadily. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 500 "},{"question":"  D. Setup and order costs remain constant while holding costs drop steadily. ","choices":["139. The correct answer is C. ","S\u0026OP focuses on monthly production amounts for product families. Scheduling for individual products (SKUs) comes later in the planning process.  ","The sales and operations plan would include which of the following?","A. Monthly production figures by individual manufacturing center "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Economies of scale lower all holding and ordering/setup costs equally and steadily. "},{"question":"  D. Monthly production figures for individual SKUs","choices":["140. The correct answer is D. ","The sales and marketing area is responsible and accountable for forecasting. Someone has to be responsible for the forecast for assessment purposes, but this does not mean that other areas cannot contribute to the forecast or that the forecast cannot be shared with other functional areas and supply chain partners. Information sharing is key to supply chain management.  ","Which one of the following functional areas is responsible for demand forecasting?","A. Purchasing "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Monthly production figures by product family "},{"question":"  D. Sales and marketing ","choices":["141. The correct answer is D. ","VMI, a more sophisticated partnership than CR (also known as RR) and QR, has increasingly tended to involve consignment sales.  ","Which of the following collaborations has increasingly evolved from the traditional relationship of supplier as seller and retailer as buyer into a consignment-sales arrangement in which the supplier owns the goods until the end customer buys them?","A. Continuous replenishment "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. IT "},{"question":"  D. Vendor-managed inventory (VMI)","choices":["142. The correct answer is C. ","A make-to-stock strategy \"pushes\" materials and products through the system in accordance with preset schedules rather than letting them be \"pulled\" through by actual orders ","If you favored a push approach to managing a supply chain, which of the following production strategies would you be most likely to adopt?","A. JIT "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Quick replenishment "},{"question":"  D. Make-to-order","choices":["143. The correct answer is D. ","In VMI, both partners benefit from increased visibility of the inventory management process, because they share information about retail demand on the one hand and supplier processes on the other. Setup and holding costs increase for the supplier, however, though they should decrease overall as forecasting improves.  ","Which of the following constitutes the primary reason for a supplier to agree to sell goods on consignment rather than selling to its customers for resale to the customer's customers?","A. Decreased setup costs "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Make-to-stock "},{"question":"  D. Greater visibility of inventory management","choices":["144. The correct answer is A. ","Once the cargo has \"passed over the ship's rail\" (to use the original terms), the importer takes title and is responsible for insurance, etc. The Incoterm stands for \"Free on Board\" (free, that is, from the exporter's point of view).  ","According to the familiar Incoterm FOB, which one of the following entities holds title to export/import cargo once it has \"passed over the ship's rail\"?","A. Importer "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Decreased inventory holding costs "},{"question":"  D. Insurance company ","choices":["145. The correct answer is A. ","VMI (vendor-managed inventory) is a form of collaboration in which a supplier performs some or all of the inventory operations traditionally handled by a retailer, including display design, replenishment, inventory counting, record keeping, and so on. (VMI can overlap with other systems.)  ","Which of the following identifies a type of collaboration in which a manufacturer of razor blades determines how its product is displayed on a retailer's shelves and performs cycle counting at the store?","A. Vendor-managed inventory (VMI) "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Exporter "},{"question":"  D. Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR)","choices":["146. The correct answer is B. ","Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts, so the pyramid technique begins by forecasting demand for the product family and then disaggregates the demand to generate single-product demand forecasts. This ensures alignment between forecasts for the group and the components of the group. (This is not to imply that the technique ignores other principles, only that it specifically relies upon the superior reliability of group forecasting.)  ","The forecasting method known as the pyramid technique specifically incorporates which one of the following principles of forecasting?","A. Short-range forecasts are more reliable than long-range forecasts. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Continuous replenishment (CR) "},{"question":"  D. Quantitative data are preferable to qualitative estimates. ","choices":["147. The correct answer is D. ","Marketing can play a useful role in planning, tracking, and managing demand from the beginning to the end of the life cycle.  ","The marketing department's involvement with product management includes which of the following phases of the product's life cycle?","A. Development through introduction "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Forecasts are always wrong. "},{"question":"  D. All phases, from conception through withdrawal","choices":["148. The correct answer is A. ","Modular design creates mix-and-match components that can be combined into different products, whereas integral design creates one product from a unique set of components.  ","Which of the following design strategies is the polar opposite of integral design?","A. Modular design "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Conception through maturity "},{"question":"  D. Mass customization","choices":["149. The correct answer is A. ","Marketing concerns drove the traditional warehousing strategy of placing a warehouse near each market and stocking it with sufficient inventory to ensure uninterrupted order fulfillment. Postwar growth of sophisticated logistics has added the other objectives.  ","Which of the following objectives was most important in traditional warehousing (before World War II)?","A. Market presence "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Universality "},{"question":"  D. Full support throughout product life cycles","choices":["150. The correct answer is D. ","Exempt carriers are (as the name suggests) granted exemption from economic regulation if they carry certain types of products, including unprocessed agricultural products and raw materials. They generally operate locally and charge relatively low rates based on the going rates in their markets. ","Which of the following might a logistics manager choose to carry raw materials in local markets at a relatively low rate determined by the market?","A. Contract carrier "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Minimizing inventory amounts "},{"question":"  D. Exempt carrier","choices":["151. The correct answer is D. ","In break-bulk operations, the incoming shipment moves straight through the warehouse to be broken down on the dock and reshipped. ","Which one of the following warehouse operations assumes no storage of incoming goods before reshipping?","A. Mixing "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Common carrier "},{"question":"  D. Break-bulk","choices":["152. The correct answer is A. ","Pick-to-light systems add lights to carousels to provide information such as the location and number of items to retrieve.  ","Pick-to-light systems speed inventory retrieval when used in conjunction with which of the following material-handling equipment?","A. Carousels "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Spot stocking "},{"question":"  D. Automated conveyers","choices":["153. The correct answer is B. ","An ETC (export trading company) buys goods domestically to sell into foreign markets. Such firms are especially significant in Japan, where they may own steamship lines, warehouses, insurance services, and so forth.  ","Which one of the following firms, known in Japan as sogo shosha, may be a large conglomerate that actually buys goods in one country for sale in a foreign market?","A. Ship broker "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Automated storage and retrieval system (AS/RS) "},{"question":"  D. Foreign carrier ","choices":["154. The correct answer is B. ","The earliest versions of MRP software assumed infinite capacity and therefore would sometimes create impossible schedules.  ","Which of the following features was a drawback in the early versions of MRP software?","A. Failed to include component lead times "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Consolidator "},{"question":"  D. Lacked an automated bill of materials","choices":["155. The correct answer is D. ","Component commonality is the design strategy of substituting one common component for a variety of similar components.  ","Which of the following design strategies would most likely be responsible for the fact that only one screwdriver is needed to remove all the screws securing a computer case and to unfasten all components from the motherboard inside?","A. Design for manufacture "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Made extra work for the scheduler "},{"question":"  D. Component commonality","choices":["156. The correct answer is A. ","In the United States, trucks move the largest amount of commercial cargo as measured by ton-miles per year. Trucks also move the most cargo as measured by tons and cargo value.  ","As measured by ton-miles per years, which of the following modes of transportation moves the most cargo in the United States?","A. Truck "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Design for logistics "},{"question":"  D. Rail ","choices":["157. The correct answer is B. ","The route sheet lists the work centers a component passes through in temporal order along with the operations performed at each work center and the time spent in queues, etc.  ","Which of the following would contain information such as queue time and machine setup time?","A. Component bill of materials "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Pipeline "},{"question":"  D. Order release form ","choices":["158. The correct answer is B. ","As much as 70 percent of a product's delivery cost is attributable to its design.  ","In general, the largest portion of a product's delivery cost can be attributed to which of the following?","A. Transportation "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Master production schedule "},{"question":"  D. Handling","choices":["159. The correct answer is D. ","Landed cost includes every expense involved in acquiring a component (or any item of value) and bringing it to your dock, including price, transportation, fees and commissions, import duties, etc.  ","When deciding whether to acquire a component from a domestic or foreign source, which of the following comparisons provides the most accurate assessment of their relative value?","A. Simple price comparison "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Production/assembly "},{"question":"  D. Landed cost of each","choices":["160. The correct answer is D. ","The focus of MPS is on weekly scheduling for individual products. You could derive the other amounts from the master schedule.  ","Which of the following is the primary focus of the master production schedule?","A. Monthly aggregate production amounts for end items "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Relative price adjusted for currency exchange and import duties "},{"question":"  D. Weekly production amounts for individual products ","choices":["161. The correct answer is B. ","Dependent demand items are components delivered for installation in finished products. The same items may also be subject to independent demand when, like hard drives in the option above, they are sold separately for purchase in repair operations or as upgrades. If the item is ordered directly by the consumer, it is part of independent demand; if it is ordered for installation in a parent product only, it is the subject of dependent demand.  ","Which of the following would be included in a list of dependent demand items?","A. Shirts delivered to a retailer for stocking on shelves "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Monthly aggregate production amounts for product families "},{"question":"  D. GPS systems delivered to an auto production plant for installation in new cars ","choices":["162. The correct answer is B. ","The ship agent issues a dock certificate to signify that the steamship company has received cargo brought to port by the inland carrier.  ","A dock receipt is issued by which of the following?","A. Importer (or banker) receiving a shipment "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Computer audio subsystems delivered to a computer superstore for sale as upgrade items "},{"question":"  D. Customs house agent ","choices":["163. The correct answer is D. ","Consolidators specialize in filling trucks for backhaul journeys from import destinations to port when the importer provides no goods for carriage. The consolidator may have to consolidate small shipments from a number of exporters to fill the carriers.  ","A shipper whose exports are carried from the foreign port to the importer's dock by trucks that return empty to the port might hire which one of the following firms to find goods to carry on the backhaul route?","A. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC) "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Customs officer "},{"question":"  D. Consolidator ","choices":["164. The correct answer is D. ","Shippers and consignees both want scheduling that suits their particular timing needs, whereas carriers tend to value stability. Hence the higher prices for services such as next-day air. ","Flexible scheduling is most likely to be a priority for which of the following transportation stakeholders?","A. Carrier "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Export packager "},{"question":"  D. Both shipper and consignee ","choices":["165. The correct answer is A. ","Crane trucks (or stacker cranes) are capital-intensive purchases, but they are available in driverless models to eliminate operator costs. They offer similar flexibility to forklifts and can move through narrow aisles. ","Which one of the following describes the main drawback of the crane truck?","A. High fixed cost "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Consignee "},{"question":"  D. Requirement of wide aisles for maneuverability ","choices":["166. The correct answer is D. ","An NVOCC (non-vessel operating common carrier) buys cargo space on a carrier to resell to shippers.  ","A logistics manager might approach which one of the following intermediaries to purchase cargo space that the firm purchased elsewhere and marked up for resale?","A. Export trading company (ETC) "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. High operator costs "},{"question":"  D. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC)","choices":["167. The correct answer is B. ","A major contributor to the bullwhip effect is inaccuracy in demand forecasting, which can lead to ordering too much or too little stock, thus contributing to the effect's exaggerated peaks and valleys of demand.  ","Which one of the following conditions contributes to the supply chain phenomenon known as the bullwhip effect?","A. JIT production strategies "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Consolidator "},{"question":"  D. Insufficient batch sizes ","choices":["168. The correct answer is C. ","Air transport is especially appropriate for high-value items because it is relatively secure, smooth, and rapid.  ","Which of the following modes of transportation is most appropriate for carrying small, highly valuable, fragile or perishable cargo?","A. Water "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Shortened lead times  "},{"question":"  D. Rail ","choices":["169. The correct answer is B. ","Sales and operations planning (S\u0026OP) is a monthly process.  ","How often, under normal circumstances, does a pre-S\u0026OP meeting take place?","A. Weekly "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Air "},{"question":"  D. Annually","choices":["170. The correct answer is B. ","In a lot-for-lot schedule, the planned order release is equal to net requirements (gross requirement reduced by any inventory on hand). There is unlikely to be inventory on hand except at the beginning of an order period.  ","If you are making up a production schedule using the lot-for-lot sizing method, which of the following equations would you use to determine the planned order receipt (assuming you know the gross amount required)?","A. Gross requirement alone "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Quarterly "},{"question":"  D. Gross requirement minus projected on hand minus scheduled receipts ","choices":["171. The correct answer is C. ","Shipping associations are groups of smaller exporters seeking to negotiate favorable rates with carriers. Since deregulation, carriers and larger shippers have been able to negotiate private rate agreements that are not disclosed for other exporters' information. Smaller shippers want to benefit from the same discounts but lack the size to negotiate successfully on their own.  ","Which one of the following correctly identifies the membership of shipping associations?","A. Small ship owners seeking to compete with larger carriers "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Gross requirement minus scheduled receipts "},{"question":"  D. Ocean carriers of all sizes seeking benefits from membership in an industry association ","choices":["172. The correct answer is C. ","The \"bandwagon effect\" (also called \"groupthink\") can distort the conclusions of a panel if a strong leader emerges with a convincing but wrong-headed view, or if all participants reinforce one another in reaching an exaggerated conclusion. An entire sales force acting in concert may, however, benefit from experience, collective knowledge of the broad market served by the organization, and even intuition.  ","A demand forecast determined by a panel of all the salespeople in an organization may reach an exaggerated, false conclusion by relying on which of the following?","A. Collective view of their markets "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Smaller export firms seeking discounted rates "},{"question":"  D. Intuition","choices":["173. The correct answer is A. ","Transportation expenses make up the largest portion of the logistics budget, so taking the discount on transportation costs would give you the largest cost reduction. (Of course, you would have to consider possible tradeoffs if discounting transportation caused cost increases elsewhere in the system.)  ","If you were able to get a 20 percent discount on any of the following logistics expenses, which would you choose to receive the maximum cost savings?","A. Transportation "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Bandwagon effect "},{"question":"  D. Warehousing","choices":["174. The correct answer is A. ","The forecast is 10,100 if you use the exponential smoothing equation as follows: Forecast = Previous Forecast + α (Demand - Forecast), where α is the smoothing constant, or, in this instance, the forecast = 10,150 + .20 (9,900 - 10,150) = 10,100. (Demand for February is 9,900, or sales minus refunds.)  ","Which of the following numbers gives the correct March forecast using the data below and the exponential smoothing approach? ","A. 10,100 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Materials handling "},{"question":"  D. 10,150 ","choices":["175. The correct answer is C. ","Including more periods in the calculation (six or 12 months instead of three, for example) further reduces the effects of random variation. This is the only benefit. Otherwise, the data gathering and calculations become more difficult and the forecasts lag farther behind changes in demand, making the forecasts less sensitive to trends and cycles.  ","Which one of the following statements identifies a beneficial result of including more periods in a moving average?","A. Forecasting becomes more sensitive to cyclical changes. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 10,120 "},{"question":"  D. Forecasts are more sensitive to trends in demand. ","choices":["176. The correct answer is A. ","Product design should take reverse logistics into account by considering use of resources, potential for reuse, recycling, etc.  ","To be most effective, design of a reverse logistics chain should begin during which of the following phases of the product life cycle?","A. Product design "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. The impact of random variations is reduced. "},{"question":"  D. Decline","choices":["177. The correct answer is B. ","The automated storage and retrieval system (AS/RS) moves both horizontally and vertically, and it can make the maximum use of floor space by lifting items into (and out of) very high storage racks.  ","Which one of the following material-handling devices would you purchase to get the maximum storage density per square foot of warehouse space?","A. Forklift "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Maturity "},{"question":"  D. Automated guided vehicle system (AGVS)","choices":["178. The correct answer is C. ","The efficiency of a work center is the ratio of actual output to standard expected output; in other words, it's a measure of how well the work center is producing in relation to what it can reasonably be expected to produce.  ","If you know the actual output of a work center and want to calculate its efficiency, you also need to know which of the following?","A. Available time "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Bridge crane "},{"question":"  D. Utilization","choices":["179. The correct answer is C. ","Railroad and barges both specialize in carrying very heavy, dense, low-value cargo over long distances. A rail line laid along a waterway would make a potent rival for the water carrier.  ","Considering the types of cargo typically carried over long distances by inland water carrier and the rates per ton-mile, which of the following modes of transportation is the barge's closest competitor?","A. Piggyback "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Standard expected hours of output "},{"question":"  D. Trucking","choices":["180. The correct answer is C. ","Backflushing is the use of the bill of materials to eliminate a component from inventory as soon as the parent unit has been manufactured. Backflushing is used in connection with JIT, and it does assume the reduction or elimination of time buckets in scheduling.  ","Using the bill of materials to deduct component quantities from inventory as soon as a unit has been manufactured is called which of the following?","A. Offsetting "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Rail "},{"question":"  D. Bucket reduction","choices":["181. The correct answer is C. ","The price paid (or scheduled to be paid) by the importer is the right amount to use when declaring the value of an import. The WTO does permit other \"reasonable\" methods of valuation if circumstances warrant.  ","According to the World Trade Organization, which of the following is the right amount to use when declaring the value of imported goods?","A. Amount stated in the harmonized code for the goods in the cargo "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Backflushing "},{"question":"  D. Exporter's cost plus transaction expenses ","choices":["182. The correct answer is A. ","A weighted moving average puts more emphasis than a simple moving average does on the most recent demand numbers. Because of the weighting, it doesn't lag as far behind demand data as a simple moving average. Its focus, therefore, is on recent trends, not the long term. It isn't simpler. ","Which of the following statements correctly identifies the purpose of the weights in a weighted moving average?","A. To be more sensitive to recent trends in demand "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Actual price to the importer "},{"question":"  D. To take account of mean average deviation","choices":["183. The correct answer is A. ","The Delphi method uses information from a panel of experts who respond anonymously to questionnaires. After several rounds of responses and critiques, a moderator produces a report expressing the collective opinion of the group.  ","Which of the following forecast techniques relies upon an expert panel that responds to questionnaires and never meets face to face?","A. Delphi method "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. To make data gathering and forecasting calculations simpler "},{"question":"  D. Sales force consensus forecasting","choices":["184. The correct answer is C. ","Data are updated as quickly as possible after the end of the month as part of the regular S\u0026OP process.  ","How frequently does a firm update S\u0026OP data?","A. Continuously "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Pyramid forecasting "},{"question":"  D. Quarterly ","choices":["185.. The correct answer is A. ","A pro forma commercial invoice, constituting a price quote, may be filled out and sent before a deal has been struck between an exporter and a potential buyer. The buyer (importer) can use the pro forma commercial invoice when securing a letter of credit with its banker.  ","Which of the following documents constitutes a price quote in export-import trade?","A. Pro forma commercial invoice "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Monthly "},{"question":"  D. Commercial invoice","choices":["186. The correct answer is A. ","The assemble-to-order strategy incorporates some of the benefits of mass production and some of the benefits of true customization by mass-producing components that can be assembled into one of several different versions of a product after receipt of an order.  ","Which of the following production strategies is sometimes called mass customization?","A. Assemble-to-order "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Dock receipt "},{"question":"  D. Lean production","choices":["187. The correct answer is A. ","Fixed quantity ordering is generally used to fill containers, qualify for quantity discounts, or both. The model works best when demand is known and stable with predictable lead times.  ","Use of a fixed order quantity model is most likely to be effective in which of the following cases?","A. Shipper is looking for quantity discounts. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Make-to-stock "},{"question":"  D. Demand is highly unpredictable and light.","choices":["188. The correct answer is B. ","The Carnet, or ATA Carnet, was originally intended for goods en route to events like tradeshows, where they would be used for demonstration rather than for sale. The \"ATA\" indicates that the goods are not imports but will be admitted only temporarily.  ","Which of the following often accompanies goods that are intended to travel in sealed containers across borders, including goods intended only to be admitted temporarily for use in events such as tradeshows?","A. Bill of lading "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Production is run on lean assumptions. "},{"question":"  D. Order waybill ","choices":["189. The correct answer is C. ","While it's not necessary to memorize the meanings of Incoterms, the important point to recall is that they exist to clarify the responsibilities of exporter and importer in a carriage contract. Of the four groups of terms, the E group (comprising only the single term EXW) puts the most responsibility on the importer, while the D group assigns almost all responsibility to the exporter. DDP, for example, means \"Delivered Duty Paid\" (that is, paid by the exporter).  ","Which one of the following Incoterms indicates that the exporter has the most responsibility for transporting a shipment of cargo from the exporter's dock to the importer's dock?","A. FOB "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Consular invoice "},{"question":"  D. CIP ","choices":["190. The correct answer is D. ","In many chains, variance in order quantity tends to increase as you move upstream away from the end customer. This is the bullwhip effect.  ","In a multiple-echelon distribution network where each warehouse orders independently based on local demand, where in the chain do you find the most variance in order quantity?","A. Variability tends to remain constant along the chain. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. DDP "},{"question":"  D. Variability tends to increase toward the raw materials end of the chain. ","choices":["191. The correct answer is B. ","Reducing storage time by cross-docking can reduce delivery lead times, thus removing one of the factors that lead to forecast error and excess safety stock. The other options listed are likely to increase variability rather than reduce it.  ","Which one of the following actions is most likely to mitigate the negative consequences of the bullwhip effect?","A. Rationing "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Variability tend to be greatest in the middle of the chain, diminishing toward either end. "},{"question":"  D. Multiple demand forecasts along the chain ","choices":["192. The correct answer is A. ","Design for reverse logistics looks for ways to make products that can be easily reused, returned, or recycled. (Whether the beer bottles can be reused or not has no effect upon logistics in the forward chain, only in the reverse chain that brings the product back at the end of its life cycle.)  ","Which of the following approaches to product design is compatible with the requirement that German brewers use refillable bottles?","A. Design for reverse logistics "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Increasing sales and special offers "},{"question":"  D. Design for logistics","choices":["193. The correct answer is D. ","Marketing can play a useful role in planning, tracking, and managing demand from the beginning to the end of the life cycle.  ","The marketing department's involvement with product management includes which of the following phases of the product's life cycle?","A. Development through introduction "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Design for production "},{"question":"  D. All phases, from conception through withdrawal ","choices":["194. The correct answer is C. ","The MRP schedules delivery of dependent demand items (which are in turn based upon independent demand forecasts). The other processes work with independent demand or product families.  ","Which one of the following processes results in production numbers driven by dependent demand?","A. Master production scheduling process "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Conception through maturity "},{"question":"  D. Market planning process","choices":["195. The correct answer is B. ","The deseasonalized demand is the sum of the seasonal averages divided by the number of \"seasons\" (or months) listed: (100 + 102 + 105 + 106 + 107 + 110) / 6 = 630 / 6 = 105.  ","Which of the following correctly identifies the deseasonalized monthly demand (to the nearest whole number) for the first half of the calendar year in the example shown in the table below? ","A. 100 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Material requirements planning process "},{"question":"  D. 630 ","choices":["196. The correct answer is B. ","NAFTA eliminated many tariffs on imports originating from within the region and scheduled elimination of the rest. Other barriers, such as access to roads on either side of the U.S.-Mexican border, remain troublesome. Imports originating from countries within the region are granted favorable duties compared to goods from outside, but documenting country of origin can be troublesome. ","Which one of the following benefits has been realized under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)?","A. Elimination of barriers to transportation across the U.S.-Mexican border "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 186 "},{"question":"  D. Simplified documentation to qualify for lower tariffs on regional goods ","choices":["197. The correct answer is A. ","The commercial invoice is the document that states the value of commodities in a shipment. (It does not include other amounts, such as freight.)  ","Which of the following documents would a banker consult for information about the value of export-import cargo in connection with a letter of credit?","A. Commercial invoice "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Easier access to competitively priced goods from outside the region "},{"question":"  D. Order bill of lading ","choices":["198. The correct answer is A. ","An export management company (EMC) may actually engage in trade but generally as a long-term consultant to a shipper. The shipper benefits from the EMC's special knowledge of a foreign country's regulations, customs, and politics.  ","Which of the following firms generally acts as a shipper's long-term consulting partner, smoothing the way through foreign customs and politics but not buying or selling cargo?","A. Export management company "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Ship's manifest "},{"question":"  D. Customs house broker ","choices":["199. The correct answer is C. ","As much as 70 percent of a product's delivery cost is attributable to its design.  ","In general, the largest portion of a product's delivery cost can be attributed to which of the following?","A. Handling "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Export trading company "},{"question":"  D. Transportation","choices":["200. The correct answer is D. ","To calculate rated capacity, you multiply the number of available hours by the efficiency and utilization. Essentially, that tells you how much of the available time is being used and how efficiently it's being used.  ","If you know the available time at a work center and want to calculate its rated capacity, you also need to know which of the following?","A. Utilization and number of workers/machines "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Product design "},{"question":"  D. Efficiency and utilization ","choices":["201. The correct answer is A. ","The Carnet, or ATA Carnet, was originally intended for goods en route to events like tradeshows, where they would be used for demonstration rather than for sale. The \"ATA\" indicates that the goods are not imports but will be admitted only temporarily.  ","Which of the following often accompanies goods that are intended to travel in sealed containers across borders, including goods intended only to be admitted temporarily for use in events such as tradeshows?","A. ATA Carnet "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Efficiency and manufacturing lead time "},{"question":"  D. Consular invoice ","choices":["202. The correct answer is C. ","Common carriers are subject to the most regulation, including the requirement to serve all customers within the scope of their license, practice nondiscrimination, and charge rates that are neither too high nor too low as to distort the market (reasonable rates). They also bear considerable responsibility for protecting the cargo that they carry.  ","Which of the following types of carriers is required to serve the public, practice nondiscrimination, charge reasonable rates, and assume many of the risks of transport?","A. Contract carrier "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Bill of lading "},{"question":"  D. All of the above","choices":["204. The correct answer is B. ","RCCP determines if resources are available (or can be made available) in the network to achieve the goals in the master schedule.  ","Which of the following is an input to rough-cut capacity planning (RCCP)?","A. Aggregate output per product family "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Common carrier "},{"question":"  D. Weekly output per end item ","choices":["205. The correct answer is B. ","Pipeline inventory is stock kept on hand to fill orders while the next lot is in transit. It is also known as transportation inventory.  ","Inventory held to cover transit time is called which of the following?","A. Work-in-process inventory "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Weekly output per component "},{"question":"  D. Anticipatory inventory ","choices":["206. The correct answer is B. ","Risk pooling is a means of reducing the risk of stockouts by consolidating inventory in a central warehouse. With a larger store of goods in the central warehouse, even the largest, unexpected order will have less chance of exhausting the inventory, as it might in a smaller warehouse. With fewer facilities adding safety stock to their orders (plus the lower stockout risk), the total amount of inventory can be reduced, and less inventory means lower holding and handling expenses. Lead times may go up, however, for deliveries made to customers that are more distant from the central warehouse than from the smaller facilities it replaced.  ","Which of the following may increase as a tradeoff when a logistics chain institutes risk pooling by moving inventory from several smaller warehouses to a larger central storage facility?","A. Inventory handling costs "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Fluctuation inventory "},{"question":"  D. Total amount of inventory held at one time","choices":["207. The correct answer is D. ","Retail trade is forbidden inside a foreign trade zone. All the other activities are specifically permitted.  ","Which one of the following is not allowed in a foreign trade zone?","A. Repackaging or otherwise altering cargo to remedy potential customs violations "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Number of stockouts "},{"question":"  D. Retail trade  ","choices":["208. The correct answer is D. ","The routing and work center files contain all the times necessary to calculate the total lead time.  ","Lead time can be determined from the information in which of the following?","A. Work center file "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Performing break-bulk operations to reduce import duties owed "},{"question":"  D. Both a and b ","choices":["209. The correct answer is C. ","The public builds and maintains the infrastructure used by trucks, so they have low fixed costs. But they have relatively high variable costs for operation and maintenance.  ","Which of the following correctly identifies the cost structure of trucking?","A. Low fixed costs, low variable costs "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Open order file "},{"question":"  D. High fixed costs, high variable costs ","choices":["210. The correct answer is B. ","Historical analogy forecasts use demand data from one product to forecast demand for a different but similar product, such as a new product for which no past data exist.  ","Which of the following forecast methods predicts demand for one product by looking at data from a different product?","A. Personal insight "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Low fixed costs, high variable costs "},{"question":"  D. Market research ","choices":["211. The correct answer is D. ","Forecast data should include demand for all product options as well as total demand for the product. You want to know when items were in demand, not when they were shipped. Competitors' product introductions are likely to affect your forecasts. Returns and cancellations should be subtracted from orders when calculating actual demand.  ","Which one of the following represents a sound approach to tracking data to use in demand forecasting?","A. Exclude cancellations and returns. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Visionary method "},{"question":"  D. Include all product options. ","choices":["212. The correct answer is C. ","Incoterms were first issued in 1936 by the International Chamber of Commerce, which has updated them several times since then to reflect the changing conditions of international trade.  ","Which one of the following entities is responsible for issuing and updating Incoterms?","A. World Trade Organization "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Include data by ship date, not order date. "},{"question":"  D. U.S. Department of Commerce","choices":["213. The correct answer is A. ","The three-month moving average forecast for May is 20.33, which is the average monthly demand for the months from February through April (17 + 22 + 22 = 61 / 3 = 20.33); the naive forecast is taken from the period preceding the forecast period, which in this case is 22, the actual demand for May. Note that the naive forecast (22) is more nearly accurate in this case, because it adjusts faster than the moving average. However, it could just as easily have been less accurate if demand had changed in a different direction or by a different amount.  ","Referring to the demand table below, calculate forecasts for May using both the three-month moving average (MA) and the naive forecasting methods. Which of the following statements correctly identifies the two forecasts? ","A. MA forecast = 20.33; naive forecast = 22 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) "},{"question":"  D. MA forecast = 22.00; naive forecast = 17","choices":["214. The correct answer is A. ","The seasonal index is the seasonal average demand divided by the deseasonalized average. The seasonal index for June is 1.05. The June forecast in the upcoming year would be the deseasonalized average of 115 multiplied by the June seasonal index: 115 x 1.05 = 120.75 (rounds to 121).  ","Referring to the table below, calculate a seasonal forecast for the month of June (round to two decimal places). If the deseasonalized forecast for January to June in a future year is 115, which of the following correctly identifies the seasonalized forecast for June of that year? ","A. 121 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. MA forecast = 21.33; naive forecast = 22 "},{"question":"  D. 109 ","choices":["215. The correct answer is C. ","Steering wheels are a dependent demand item; the demand for dependent items should be calculated from the forecast of demand for their parent items. Steering wheels are a component; the new cars they go into are the parents. Replacement parts are sold, manufactured, and forecast as independent items, not as dependent components.  ","For which of the following items should demand be calculated rather than forecast?","A. All Chevrolets "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 110 "},{"question":"  D. All Chevrolet replacement parts ","choices":["216. The correct answer is D. ","Spot stocking is used for limited product lines and highly seasonal products that can be centrally stored during most of the year and spot-stocked in season at warehouses near the places where they will be purchased and used. Manufacturers use spot stocking for agricultural products used only during one limited operation, such as harvesting.  ","Which one of the following types of warehousing is most appropriate for agricultural supplies that might be used only once during the year?","A. Postponement "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. All steering wheels for new Chevrolet Cobalts "},{"question":"  D. Spot stocking","choices":["217. The correct answer is D. ","Transportation expenses make up the largest portion of the logistics budget, so taking the discount on transportation costs would give you the largest cost reduction. (Of course, you would have to consider possible tradeoffs if discounting transportation caused cost increases elsewhere in the system.)  ","If you were able to get a 20 percent discount on any of the following logistics expenses, which would you choose to receive the maximum cost savings?","A. Warehousing "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Stockpiling "},{"question":"  D. Transportation","choices":["218. The correct answer is C. ","The main benefit of the pull system of distribution is sensitivity to local customer demand, since orders begin near the customer and \"pull\" products from upstream. This approach does not facilitate communication, eliminate safety stock, or improve visibility down the chain because there is no central coordination and upstream partners have to depend upon forecasting to plan for future orders rather than upon (for example) a predetermined production schedule.  ","Using a pull system in the distribution network offers which one of the following benefits to the supply chain as a whole?","A. Enhanced visibility of future demand all along the chain "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Materials handling "},{"question":"  D. Enhanced communication up the chain","choices":["219. The correct answer is D. ","Smoothing constants are generally chosen between 0.05 and 0.50. A constant of 0 would give the same forecast as for the previous month, because it would eliminate the portion of the equation including the forecast error. A constant of 1.0 would yield a forecast equal to the current month's demand; in the equation, the forecast numbers would cancel out, leaving only the actual demand amount. In between 0 and 1, the constant determines how much weight you give to the forecast error. ","Which of the following smoothing constants would yield the same result as a naive forecast?","A. 0.01 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Sensitivity to demands of the final customer "},{"question":"  D. 1.0 ","choices":["220. The correct answer is B. ","Pipelines are costly in other ways, but their operating costs are relatively low (no drivers or pilots, for one thing).  ","Which of the following modes of transporting petroleum involves the lowest operating costs?","A. Ocean vessel "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 0.50 "},{"question":"  D. Tanker truck ","choices":["221. The correct answer is C. ","To achieve economies of scale in transportation, consolidation combines shipments from many incoming sources when loading outbound vehicles headed for a single location. ","Which one of the following warehouse operations is most appropriate for a manufacturer that receives components from many suppliers and wants to achieve economies of scale when transporting those components to one plant?","A. Mixing "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Rail "},{"question":"  D. Break-bulk","choices":["222. The correct answer is A. ","Standardization, also called universality, is the strategy of designing a product to work in multiple markets rather than in only one market. Modular design and mass customization may reach multiple market segments, but they do so by product differentiation, not standardization.  ","Which of the following is another name for the \"one size fits all\" type of design?","A. Standardization "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Consolidation "},{"question":"  D. Mass customization","choices":["223. The correct answer is D. ","Expenses related to construction, right of way, and pumping capacity give pipelines the highest fixed costs of any mode of transporting freight.  ","Which of the following has the highest fixed cost of any means of transporting petroleum?","A. Trains "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Component commonality "},{"question":"  D. Pipelines","choices":["224. The correct answer is C. ","In the model, certain tasks are performed by the buyer/retailer (POS forecasting in this case), certain tasks are performed by the seller/manufacturer (market analysis in this case), and those tasks are reconciled in a joint session. The joint session to reconcile POS forecasting and market analysis results in a shared sales forecast. ","In the CPFR model, which of the following tasks would be performed jointly by the manufacturer (seller) and the retailer (buyer)?","A. POS (point-of-sale) forecasting "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Ships "},{"question":"  D. All of the above would be performed jointly.  ","choices":["225. The correct answer is A. ","Assortment planning in industries in which demand and product styles change with each season present a special challenge to forecasters. The constant rotation through different styles or models means there is little historical demand data for particular products. VICS CPFR includes a scenario with guidelines for assortment planning based on graphic presentations of new models along with financial models.  ","CPFR includes formal guidelines for a growing number of scenarios. Which of the following CPFR scenarios includes such methods as graphical presentations of new products to help make merchandizing decisions in the absence of solid historical data on demand?","A. Collaborative assortment planning "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Sales forecasting "},{"question":"  D. Retail event collaboration ","choices":["226. The correct answer is C. ","The price paid (or scheduled to be paid) by the importer is the right amount to use when declaring the value of an import. The WTO does permit other \"reasonable\" methods of valuation if circumstances warrant. ","According to the World Trade Organization, which of the following is the right amount to use when declaring the value of imported goods?","A. Exporter's cost plus transaction expenses "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Store replenishment collaboration "},{"question":"  D. Calculated market value ","choices":["227. The correct answer is C. ","Order B/Ls can be used to transfer ownership of cargo. Straight B/Ls (including air bills) document cargo intended for delivery straight to the buyer without intermediate title transfers.  ","Which one of the following is a negotiable certificate of ownership?","A. Straight B/L "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Actual price to the importer "},{"question":"  D. Dock receipt","choices":["228. The correct answer is A. ","The risk of having inventory items become obsolete increases when amounts ordered exceed the forecast significantly. Economies of scale in transport and purchase are potential benefits of larger orders, as is decoupling from the supplier.  ","Which of the following identifies a risk of ordering more inventory than required to fill forecast orders?","A. Increased obsolescence "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. Order B/L "},{"question":"  D. Higher per-item costs for purchasing the inventory","choices":["229. The correct answer is C. ","Data are updated as quickly as possible after the end of the month as part of the regular S\u0026OP process.  ","How frequently does a firm update S\u0026OP data?","A. Continuously "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Decoupling from supplier "},{"question":"  D. Quarterly ","choices":["230. The correct answer is B. ","Rail provides a rough ride for cargo, resulting in more breakage than occurs in cargo transported by truck, water, or air.  ","A logistics manager concerned to avoid breakage of cargo would be least inclined to choose which of the following modes of transportation (ignoring tradeoffs)?","A. Water transport "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Monthly "},{"question":"  D. Air transport ","choices":["231. The correct answer is A. ","The exporter bears responsibility for determining the classification of the goods it sells in international transactions. It does so by reference to the harmonized tariff codes.  ","Which of the following parties determines the tariff classification of an import?","A. Exporter "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Truck transport "},{"question":"  D. Customs ","choices":["232. The correct answer is B. ","NAFTA eliminated many tariffs on imports originating from within the region and scheduled elimination of the rest. Other barriers, such as access to roads on either side of the U.S.-Mexican border, remain troublesome. Imports originating from countries within the region are granted favorable duties compared to goods from outside, but documenting country of origin can be troublesome.  ","Which one of the following benefits has been realized under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)?","A. Easier access to competitively priced goods from outside the region "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Importer "},{"question":"  D. Simplified documentation to qualify for lower tariffs on regional goods ","choices":["233. The correct answer is C. ","Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts, so the pyramid technique begins by forecasting demand for the product family and then disaggregates the demand to generate single-product demand forecasts. This ensures alignment between forecasts for the group and the components of the group. (This is not to imply that the technique ignores other principles, only that it specifically relies upon the superior reliability of group forecasting.)  ","The forecasting method known as the pyramid technique specifically incorporates which one of the following principles of forecasting?","A. Forecasts are always wrong. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Elimination of barriers to transportation across the U.S.-Mexican border "},{"question":"  D. Quantitative data are preferable to qualitative estimates.","choices":["234. The correct answer is D. ","In seller's credit financing, the seller (exporter) accepts the importer's credit card (or other promise to pay) and thus takes the most financial risk involved in any of options described.  ","The exporter takes the most risk in which of the following export-import financing arrangements?","A. Letter of credit "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts. "},{"question":"  D. Seller's credit","choices":["235. The correct answer is C. ","Contract carriers can generally offer lower rates and tailored services to select clients.  ","Which one of the following would a firm be most likely to choose to deliver goods in national markets if it is looking for tailored services and a relatively low negotiated rate?","A. Private carrier "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Buyer's payment from an open account "},{"question":"  D. Common carrier ","choices":["236. The correct answer is D. ","Periodic inventory counts provide a value for inventory at one point in time, but they disrupt business, are relatively expensive, are prone to inaccuracy, and don't promote accurate ordering policies (because they are infrequent and tend to be inaccurate).  ","Which of the following correctly describes the benefit of conducting periodic inventory counts?","A. Periodic counts don't disrupt the ordinary flow of business. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Contract carrier "},{"question":"  D. Periodic counting provides a financial value for all inventory at one point in time. ","choices":["237. The correct answer is A. ","The earliest versions of MRP software assumed infinite capacity and therefore would sometimes create impossible schedules.  ","Which of the following features was a drawback in the early versions of MRP software?","A. Assumed infinite capacity "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Periodic counting is inexpensive. "},{"question":"  D. Made extra work for the scheduler ","choices":["238. The correct answer is C. ","S\u0026OP focuses on monthly production amounts for product families. Scheduling for individual products (SKUs) comes later in the planning process.  ","The sales and operations plan would include which of the following?","A. Monthly production figures by individual manufacturing center "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Failed to include component lead times "},{"question":"  D. Monthly production figures for individual SKUs ","choices":["239. The correct answer is D. ","The larger the order, the higher the holding costs, because there is more inventory to hold. Setup costs tend to go down as orders grow larger because of economies of scale. (Larger orders can be placed less frequently than smaller orders, thus reducing the number of setups.)  ","In the economic order quantity calculation, which one of the following statements most accurately identifies the effect of increasing order sizes on inventory holding and order costs?","A. Economies of scale lower all holding and ordering/setup costs equally and steadily. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Monthly production figures by product family "},{"question":"  D. Total costs drop up to a point and then rise steadily. ","choices":["240. The correct answer is C. ","The sales and operations plan typically extends out at least a year and no more than 18 months and involves both short- and medium-term planning.  ","Which of the following would be a typical time horizon for sales and operations planning?","A. One week to one month "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Holding costs remain constant while setup costs rise steadily. "},{"question":"  D. 18 months to three years ","choices":["241. The correct answer is A. ","Including more periods in the calculation (six or 12 months instead of three, for example) further reduces the effects of random variation. This is the only benefit. Otherwise, the data gathering and calculations become more difficult and the forecasts lag farther behind changes in demand, making the forecasts less sensitive to trends and cycles. ","Which one of the following statements identifies a beneficial result of including more periods in a moving average?","A. The impact of random variations is reduced. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. 12 to 18 months "},{"question":"  D. Forecasting becomes more sensitive to cyclical changes. ","choices":["242. The correct answer is A. ","Modular design creates mix-and-match components that can be combined into different products, whereas integral design creates one product from a unique set of components.  ","Which of the following design strategies is the polar opposite of integral design?","A. Modular design "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Forecasts are more sensitive to trends in demand. "},{"question":"  D. Mass customization","choices":["243. The correct answer is C. ","Railroad and barges both specialize in carrying very heavy, dense, low-value cargo over long distances. A rail line laid along a waterway would make a potent rival for the water carrier.  ","Considering the types of cargo typically carried over long distances by inland water carrier and the rates per ton-mile, which of the following modes of transportation is the barge's closest competitor?","A. Piggyback "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Universality "},{"question":"  D. Pipeline","choices":["244. The correct answer is D. ","The exporter determines the tariff classification using the harmonized code when packaging the goods for export. The importer (usually through the customs house broker) pays the duty when goods come through customs.  ","Which one of the following describes the typical situation in regards to payment of import duties?","A. The importer determines the tariff classification and the exporter pays the duty. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Rail "},{"question":"  D. The exporter determines the tariff classification and the importer pays the duty.","choices":["245. The correct answer is C. ","Using common components for a variety of purposes provides economies of scale in purchasing and manufacture but can limit design flexibility and reduce quality.  ","Which of the following design strategies offers streamlined production and lower purchasing costs with a possible tradeoff against reduced design flexibility and lower quality?","A. Mass customization "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. The importer determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. "},{"question":"  D. Integral design","choices":["246. The correct answer is C. ","The \"bandwagon effect\" (also called \"groupthink\") can distort the conclusions of a panel if a strong leader emerges with a convincing but wrong-headed view, or if all participants reinforce one another in reaching an exaggerated conclusion. An entire sales force acting in concert may, however, benefit from experience, collective knowledge of the broad market served by the organization, and even intuition.  ","A demand forecast determined by a panel of all the salespeople in an organization may reach an exaggerated, false conclusion by relying on which of the following?","A. Intuition "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Component commonality "},{"question":"  D. Collective view of their markets","choices":["247. The correct answer is A. ","The business plan provides a long-range view of strategy and guidance for developing tactical plans for sales, marketing, and operations.  ","A business plan would typically include which of the following?","A. Long-term guidance for developing tactical production plans "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Bandwagon effect "},{"question":"  D. Monthly production figures for each product family ","choices":["248. The correct answer is A. ","The issuer of a letter of credit is the buyer/importer's bank, which attests in the letter to its faith that the importer can and will pay for the goods when certain conditions have been satisfied ","When an export-import transaction is financed by a letter of credit, which one of the following entities actually issues the letter?","A. Importer's bank "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Definition of sales territories "},{"question":"  D. Seller's bank","choices":["249. The correct answer is C. ","Make/buy action plans concern matters such as what to order, cancel, and expedite. With the information from this and other sources, it is possible to develop the MRP.   ","Which of the following is an input to the material requirements plan (MRP)?","A. Input/output control "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Buyer "},{"question":"  D. Rough-cut capacity planning","choices":["250. The correct answer is A. ","Railroads have maintained a fairly steady 40 percent share of the market among common carriers since the Staggers Act, but other results of deregulation include declines in the number of large rail carriers, in total miles of track, in rates, and in destinations served.  ","Which one of the following statements correctly identifies a consequence of the Staggers Act of 1980, which deregulated rail transport in the United States?","A. No significant change in share of commercial carriage (ton-mile/year) "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Make/buy action plan "},{"question":"  D. Steady increase in markets served by rail ","choices":["251. The correct answer is A. ","Backflushing is the use of the bill of materials to eliminate a component from inventory as soon as the parent unit has been manufactured. Backflushing is used in connection with JIT, and it does assume the reduction or elimination of time buckets in scheduling.  ","Using the bill of materials to deduct component quantities from inventory as soon as a unit has been manufactured is called which of the following?","A. Backflushing "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Steady increase in rates "},{"question":"  D. Offsetting ","choices":["252. The correct answer is D. ","A planning bill of materials includes small items intended for use in a variety of finished items. They are ordered in bulk for convenience and economies of scale even though they have no one parent to list on a regular bill of materials.  ","Which of the following could appear in a planning bill of materials?","A. All the parts necessary to manufacture one car radio "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"  C. Bucket reduction "},{"question":"  D. All the transistors to be used in assembling a variety of electronics components ","choices":["253. The correct answer is B. ","Water transport offers the lowest rates per ton, much lower even than rail, which is second. Trucking is considerably more expensive than rail but substantially less expensive than air.  ","Place the following modes of transportation in order of rate per ton-mile for carrying cargo, with I being the lowest rates and IV being the highest.","I. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  C. All the #10 nails intended for delivery to a chain of home improvement stores "},{"question":"\tAir ","choices":["\tIII. ","\tWater ","\tIV. ","\tTruck"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"\tII. "},{"question":"  C. III, IV, II, I ","choices":["  D. IV, I, II, III","254. The correct answer is D. ","An NVOCC (non-vessel operating common carrier) buys cargo space on a carrier to resell to shippers. ","A logistics manager might approach which one of the following intermediaries to purchase cargo space that the firm purchased elsewhere and marked up for resale?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. III, I, IV, II "},{"question":"  C. Consolidator ","choices":["  D. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC) ","255. The correct answer is C. ","Lot-for-lot sizing is typically used with small, frequent deliveries of dependent demand items. Longer time buckets and larger order sizes are more likely to require a buffer of safety stock.  ","Which of the following conditions is generally associated with lot-for-lot order sizing?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Freight forwarder "},{"question":"  C. Small, frequent orders ","choices":["  D. Independent demand items ","256. The correct answer is A. ","Product design should take reverse logistics into account by considering use of resources, potential for reuse, recycling, etc.  ","To be most effective, design of a reverse logistics chain should begin during which of the following phases of the product life cycle?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Safety stock buffers "},{"question":"  C. Maturity ","choices":["  D. Decline","257. The correct answer is D. ","Landed cost includes every expense involved in acquiring a component (or any item of value) and bringing it to your dock, including price, transportation, fees and commissions, import duties, etc.  ","When deciding whether to acquire a component from a domestic or foreign source, which of the following comparisons provides the most accurate assessment of their relative value?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Introduction "},{"question":"  C. Relative price adjusted for currency exchange and import duties ","choices":["  D. Landed cost of each ","258. The correct answer is D. ","In VMI, both partners benefit from increased visibility of the inventory management process, because they share information about retail demand on the one hand and supplier processes on the other. Setup and holding costs increase for the supplier, however, though they should decrease overall as forecasting improves.  ","Which of the following constitutes the primary reason for a supplier to agree to sell goods on consignment rather than selling to its customers for resale to the customer's customers?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Relative price plus transportation "},{"question":"  C. Decreased inventory holding costs ","choices":["  D. Greater visibility of inventory management ","259. The correct answer is A. ","All other factors being equal, public warehousing is a good choice to accommodate short-term spikes in demand. The other choices require longer-term commitments of resources. (In actual practice, \"other factors\" may be unlikely to remain equal, and all choices have to be made with an eye to unplanned consequences for the system as a whole.)  ","Which of the following types of warehouse ownership might a firm choose to minimize storage costs when adding distribution capacity for a new product with a highly seasonal demand pattern?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Decreased labor costs "},{"question":"  C. Remodeled and expanded private warehousing ","choices":["  D. New construction private warehousing ","260. The correct answer is A. ","Quick response (QR) is one of the earliest and most basic forms of customer-supplier partnerships, in which the retailer shares POS information with the supplier but doesn't collaborate on forecasting. ","Which of the following descriptions applies most accurately to quick response collaboration?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Contract warehousing "},{"question":"  C. Partnership in which a supplier and a retailer collaborate on development of shipping schedules ","choices":["  D. Arrangement in which a supplier may handle some aspects of inventory management for a retailer ","261. The correct answer is A. ","The monthly S\u0026OP meeting deals with aggregate-level information about product families and output. The S\u0026OP executive committee can make changes in either the operations plan or the business plan if they get out of synch with one another.  ","Which of the following would be subject to alteration as the result of decisions made in an executive S\u0026OP meeting?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Complex and evolving guidelines for coordinating multiple aspects of supply chain partnership "},{"question":"  C. Product pricing ","choices":["  D. Weekly production schedules ","262. The correct answer is C. ","Pick-to-light systems add lights to carousels to provide information such as the location and number of items to retrieve.  ","Pick-to-light systems speed inventory retrieval when used in conjunction with which of the following material-handling equipment?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Product features "},{"question":"  C. Carousels ","choices":["  D. Automated conveyers ","263. The correct answer is B. ","Moving averages are intended to even out random fluctuations, but they don't react quickly enough to changes to forecast cycles and trends.  ","Moving average forecasts are generally superior to naive forecasts in correcting for which of the following sources of variability?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Automatic sorting devices "},{"question":"  C. Cyclical movements correlated to economic indicators ","choices":["  D. Short- to medium-term trends related to the seasons of the year","264. The correct answer is A. ","The three-month weighted moving average forecast for April is 20.17 (3 x 22 = 66; 2 x 17 = 34; 1 x 21 = 21; 66 + 34 + 21 = 121; 121 / 6 = 20.17). Did you remember to divide by the sum of the weights (6) instead of by 3?  ","Referring to the demand table below, calculate a three-month weighted moving average forecast for April using a 3-2-1 weighting for March, February, and January, respectively. Which of the following identifies the correct forecast for April using this method? "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Very short-term fluctuations in demand attributable to no known cause "},{"question":"  C. 20.67 ","choices":["  D. 40.33 ","265. The correct answer is C. ","A make-to-stock strategy \"pushes\" materials and products through the system in accordance with preset schedules rather than letting them be \"pulled\" through by actual orders.  ","If you favored a push approach to managing a supply chain, which of the following production strategies would you be most likely to adopt?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. 20.33 "},{"question":"  C. Make-to-stock ","choices":["  D. Assemble-to-order","266. The correct answer is D. ","The seller (exporter) sends a draft to its banker, who honors it based upon its assurance of reimbursement by the buyer's bank, which in its turn depends upon reimbursement by the buyer (whose money it may already hold on account).  ","When international trade is financed with a letter of credit, which of the following entities actually makes the final payment to the seller?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Make-to-order "},{"question":"  C. Buyer's bank ","choices":["  D. Seller's bank ","267. The correct answer is C. ","Reducing use of resources ranks highest in the reverse logistics hierarchy. The other strategies mentioned are also responsible and should be used when options higher up the pyramid are not feasible.  ","Which of the following is generally considered to be the most responsible strategy for managing reverse logistics?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Inland export carrier "},{"question":"  C. Reduction of resources used in extraction, manufacture, and packaging ","choices":["  D. Accepting product returns for efficient delivery to a clean landfill ","268. The correct answer is C. ","The assemble-to-order strategy incorporates some of the benefits of mass production and some of the benefits of true customization by mass-producing components that can be assembled into one of several different versions of a product after receipt of an order.  ","Which of the following production strategies is sometimes called mass customization?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Accepting product returns for recycling by the manufacturer "},{"question":"  C. Assemble-to-order ","choices":["  D. Lean production","269. The correct answer is A. ","A hard drive is a module that, along with other modules, can be mixed and matched to assemble computers with many different features.  ","A hard drive that can be used in many different kinds of computers is an example of which of the following design strategies?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Make-to-order "},{"question":"  C. Integral design ","choices":["  D. Universality","270. The correct answer is B. ","A pro forma commercial invoice, constituting a price quote, may be filled out and sent before a deal has been struck between an exporter and a potential buyer. The buyer (importer) can use the pro forma commercial invoice when securing a letter of credit with its banker.  ","Which of the following documents constitutes a price quote in export-import trade?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Standardization "},{"question":"  C. Consular invoice ","choices":["  D. Commercial invoice ","271. The correct answer is B. ","To calculate rated capacity, you multiply the number of available hours by the efficiency and utilization. Essentially, that tells you how much of the available time is being used and how efficiently it's being used. ","If you know the available time at a work center and want to calculate its rated capacity, you also need to know which of the following?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Pro forma commercial invoice "},{"question":"  C. Utilization and number of workers/machines ","choices":["  D. Efficiency and manufacturing lead time","272. The correct answer is D. ","Dividing the total time available during a scheduled period at the site by the lead time tells you how many operations can be produced at the site in the period.  ","Which of the following (assuming site- and period-specific data) would provide the number of operations that can be produced at a site during a single period of time?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Efficiency and utilization "},{"question":"  C. Lead time available divided by load ","choices":["  D. Total time available divided by lead time","273. The correct answer is C. ","The master production schedule includes dates of production for make-to-stock end items. (This can be either finished products or, in a modular approach, components.)  ","For make-to-stock production of an integral design, the master production schedule includes production dates for which of the following?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Lead time available divided by total time "},{"question":"  C. End items ","choices":["  D. Orders","274. The correct answer is C. ","VMI, a more sophisticated partnership than CR (also known as RR) and QR, has increasingly tended to involve consignment sales.  ","Which of the following collaborations has increasingly evolved from the traditional relationship of supplier as seller and retailer as buyer into a consignment-sales arrangement in which the supplier owns the goods until the end customer buys them?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Components "},{"question":"  C. Vendor-managed inventory (VMI) ","choices":["  D. Continuous replenishment ","275. The correct answer is B. ","A firm can build or remodel its own warehouses with no needs in mind other than its own. Contractors offer flexibility and economies of scale.  ","Which one of the following is the most compelling reason for a manufacturer to own its own warehouses rather than using a contractor's warehouses?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Rapid replenishment "},{"question":"  C. To increase flexibility of budgeting for warehousing expenses ","choices":["  D. To benefit from economies of scale in transportation ","276. The correct answer is A. ","With their intermodal networks, FedEx, UPS, and DHL offer door-to-door delivery on rapid timetables, but they are not inexpensive. As delivery services, they are perhaps best used when speed is more important than price. Many express services offer logistics consultation and total logistics management (4PL) and are capable of providing small businesses the benefit of economies of scale and deep logistics expertise.  ","Which one of the following is the most significant drawback of specialized package carriers such as FedEx and DHL?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. To increase control over warehouse design decisions "},{"question":"  C. Too expensive for small businesses to use economically ","choices":["  D. Lack of multimodal capability ","277. The correct answer is D. ","Design for reverse logistics looks for ways to make products that can be easily reused, returned, or recycled. (Whether the beer bottles can be reused or not has no effect upon logistics in the forward chain, only in the reverse chain that brings the product back at the end of its life cycle.)  ","Which of the following approaches to product design is compatible with the requirement that German brewers use refillable bottles?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Lack of flexibility in pickup and delivery locations "},{"question":"  C. Design for production ","choices":["  D. Design for reverse logistics","278. The correct answer is C. ","Although CPFR is enhanced by software, it is fundamentally a set of business practices for synchronizing the operations of buyer and seller. It depends for success upon a willingness to share data for forecasting, execution, assessments, and other functions. The data may be shared on peer-to-peer networks, extranets, or third-party servers, and the Internet is generally involved as the medium for accessing the shared data. But technology is not at the heart of the matter; sharing data in joint operations is.  ","In regard to technology, CPFR may be said to depend fundamentally upon which of the following?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Over-the-wall design "},{"question":"  C. Shared data in any technological format ","choices":["  D. World Wide Web","279. The correct answer is C. ","Crane trucks (or stacker cranes) are capital-intensive purchases, but they are available in driverless models to eliminate operator costs. They offer similar flexibility to forklifts and can move through narrow aisles.  ","Which one of the following describes the main drawback of the crane truck?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Third-party host "},{"question":"  C. High fixed cost ","choices":["  D. Requirement of wide aisles for maneuverability","280. The correct answer is B. ","An assemble-to-order strategy may require warehouse or sales personnel to complete the final stages of finishing a product, thus requiring workers to acquire new skills and, in some cases, the facility to expand capacity to accommodate the finishing operations.  ","Which one of the following production strategies sometimes meets resistance from distribution centers because of the increased demands for skill training and capacity expansion?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Lack of flexibility compared to forklifts "},{"question":"  C. JIT ","choices":["  D. Make-to-order","281. The correct answer is A. ","Trains are hindered in traveling across borders in Europe because of incompatible infrastructure and regulations. Rail freight carriage in Europe dropped steadily in the latter decades of the 20th century as other modes of freight carriage have increased in market share. At the same time, passenger use of trains also declined. Rail rates are relatively low, and rail transport has historically received strong government support in EU countries.  ","Which one of the following has constituted the greatest historical impediment to efficient use of railroads to carry freight in Europe?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Assemble-to-order "},{"question":"  C. Increasing pressure for space on trains from commuters ","choices":["  D. High rates relative to other modes of carriage ","282. The correct answer is A. ","The route sheet lists the work centers a component passes through in temporal order along with the operations performed at each work center and the time spent in queues, etc.  ","Which of the following would contain information such as queue time and machine setup time?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Lack of government support "},{"question":"  C. Component bill of materials ","choices":["  D. Order release form","283. The correct answer is B. ","The efficiency of a work center is the ratio of actual output to standard expected output; in other words, it's a measure of how well the work center is producing in relation to what it can reasonably be expected to produce.  ","If you know the actual output of a work center and want to calculate its efficiency, you also need to know which of the following?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Master production schedule "},{"question":"  C. Available time ","choices":["  D. Number of workers or machines","284. The correct answer is A. ","In the traditional design process, the supplier plays no role in design. The design is created by design engineers and passed \"over the wall,\" figuratively, to manufacturing and other stakeholders.  ","Which of the following strategies represents the traditional \"over the wall\" approach to product design?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Standard expected hours of output "},{"question":"  C. Supplier informally makes recommendations to design engineers. ","choices":["  D. Supplier creates the design.","285. The correct answer is D. ","Shippers and consignees both want scheduling that suits their particular timing needs, whereas carriers tend to value stability. Hence the higher prices for services such as next-day air.  ","Flexible scheduling is most likely to be a priority for which of the following transportation stakeholders?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Formal design team includes supplier. "},{"question":"  C. Consignee ","choices":["  D. Both shipper and consignee ","286. The correct answer is B. ","Pegging is the ability to track dependent demand for a component back to demand for the parent by referring to the material requirements plan (MRP).  ","Pegging refers to the ability to make a connection between the required numbers of a specific component and which of the following?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Shipper "},{"question":"  C. Specific work center ","choices":["  D. Capacity plan ","287. The correct answer is D. ","The material requirements plan works off the master production schedule to ensure that all components are delivered on time to meet production schedules.  ","Which of the following constitutes a major, direct input into a material requirements plan?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Demand for the parent according to the MRP "},{"question":"  C. Input/output tracking reports ","choices":["  D. Master production schedule","288. The correct answer is D. ","Reducing storage time by cross-docking can reduce delivery lead times, thus removing one of the factors that lead to forecast error and excess safety stock. The other options listed are likely to increase variability rather than reduce it.  ","Which one of the following actions is most likely to mitigate the negative consequences of the bullwhip effect?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Marketing plan "},{"question":"  C. Rationing ","choices":["  D. Cross-docking to reduce inventory storage time ","289. The correct answer is A. ","The strong suit of trucking is accessibility, since trucks can go to virtually any commercial location. This along with size and weight limits makes trucking most appropriate for carrying high-value items of smaller size for short hauls.  ","Which of the following constitutes the most appropriate shipment to send by truck?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Increasing sales and special offers "},{"question":"  C. Heavy, low-value items traveling long distances ","choices":["  D. Small, high-value items traveling a long distance ","290. The correct answer is D. ","The air waybill is a nonnegotiable standardized form used by all air carriers.  ","Which of the following is a standardized, nonnegotiable form listing items being shipped directly to the titleholder?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Bulky items traveling between cities "},{"question":"  C. Ship's manifest ","choices":["  D. Air waybill","291. The correct answer is C. ","Typically used with JIT, lot-for-lot sizing delivers the exact amount needed when it is needed, thereby eliminating inventory buffers. Frequent delivery of small lots requires more setups.  ","Which one of the following conditions is a potential drawback of lot-for-lot order sizing?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Order B/L "},{"question":"  C. High setup costs ","choices":["  D. High inventory costs ","292. The correct answer is D. ","Marketing concerns drove the traditional warehousing strategy of placing a warehouse near each market and stocking it with sufficient inventory to ensure uninterrupted order fulfillment. Postwar growth of sophisticated logistics has added the other objectives.  ","Which of the following objectives was most important in traditional warehousing (before World War II)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Incompatibility with JIT "},{"question":"  C. Rapid response ","choices":["  D. Market presence","293. The correct answer is A. ","The focus of MPS is on weekly scheduling for individual products. You could derive the other amounts from the master schedule.  ","Which of the following is the primary focus of the master production schedule?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Full support throughout product life cycles "},{"question":"  C. Monthly aggregate production amounts for product families ","choices":["  D. Weekly aggregate production amounts for product families ","294. The correct answer is B. ","A major contributor to the bullwhip effect is inaccuracy in demand forecasting, which can lead to ordering too much or too little stock, thus contributing to the effect's exaggerated peaks and valleys of demand.  ","Which one of the following conditions contributes to the supply chain phenomenon known as the bullwhip effect?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Monthly aggregate production amounts for end items "},{"question":"  C. Insufficient batch sizes ","choices":["  D. Shortened lead times ","295. The correct answer is A. ","Product families for purposes of the operations plan are best chosen by similar manufacturing requirements to facilitate other planning processes, such as production scheduling. (Marketing can group products in other ways for its purposes.) ","Which of the following would provide a sound method for grouping products into product families for the operations plan?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Inaccurate demand forecasting "},{"question":"  C. Appeal to a particular age group ","choices":["  D. National market destination ","296. The correct answer is B. ","In many chains, variance in order quantity tends to increase as you move upstream away from the end customer. This is the bullwhip effect.  ","In a multiple-echelon distribution network where each warehouse orders independently based on local demand, where in the chain do you find the most variance in order quantity?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Similar seasonality "},{"question":"  C. Variability tend to be greatest in the middle of the chain, diminishing toward either end. ","choices":["  D. Variability tends to remain constant along the chain. ","297. The correct answer is A. ","In piggyback service either a truck trailer or a container travels part of the way over the road and part of the way on a railroad flatcar. All the other intermodal methods mentioned in the options are available, and intermodal transport is an important option for the logistics manager to consider when navigating long logistics supply chains.  ","Piggyback service refers to which of the following types of cargo transport?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Variability tends to increase toward the raw materials end of the chain. "},{"question":"  C. Combined plane and truck transport ","choices":["  D. Any intermodal method of transport","298. The correct answer is A. ","Adding safety stock can achieve the goals of improved customer service, reduced stockouts, and anticipation of demand spikes; it is more likely to increase overall costs than reduce them. (Cost savings from reducing safety stock must, however, be balanced against the potential costs of increased stockouts.)  ","By ordering extra stock (safety stock), a purchasing manager might reasonably expect to benefit the supply chain in all the following ways except"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Combined train and ship transport "},{"question":"  C. improving customer service. ","choices":["  D. anticipating unpredicted demand spikes.","299. The correct answer is C. ","Disaggregation takes place during the development of the master production schedule.  ","Which of the following processes includes the disaggregation of product families?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. reducing the likelihood of stockouts. "},{"question":"  C. Master production scheduling ","choices":["  D. Sales planning","300. The correct answer is B. ","Basing a forecast for a product on data about economic indicators such as housing starts, population trends, or employment statistics is called extrinsic forecasting to distinguish it from intrinsic forecasting based on data about the product itself. Historical analogy bases forecasts for one product on data from a similar (analogous) product, not on data about economic trends.  ","Basing a demand forecast for kitchen appliances on housing start data is an example of which of the following?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Operations planning "},{"question":"  C. Market analysis ","choices":["  D. Pyramid forecasting","301. The correct answer is D. ","The \"Orange Book\" is published by the United Nations; its first edition came out in 1956. It contains the United Nations Recommendations on the Transport of Dangerous Goods (UNRMTDG), in which all national controls are grounded. The UN recommendations do not have the force of law, but national regulations based on them may.  ","Which of the following institutions publishes the \"Orange Book\" containing recommendations that form the basis of international dangerous goods (hazardous materials) laws and regulations?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Extrinsic forecasting "},{"question":"  C. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) ","choices":["  D. United Nations","302. The correct answer is D. ","A full truck qualifies for a per-pound (kilogram) discount, since the carrier benefits from being able to charge more per unit of weight. Similarly, heavier loads (subject to limits) and greater density yield economies of scale. \"Lane density\" refers to the amount of cargo traffic around the destination; greater density means more potential business for the carrier on the return trip. Low lane density can lead to a return trip with an empty vehicle, at the expense of the shipper.  ","If you're planning to ship goods over the road, which of the following represents a strategy for lowering your per-pound costs for the trip?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. International Maritime Association "},{"question":"  C. Ship to destinations with low lane volume. ","choices":["  D. Fill up the trucks.","303. The correct answer is A. ","Component commonality is the design strategy of substituting one common component for a variety of similar components.  ","Which of the following design strategies would most likely be responsible for the fact that only one screwdriver is needed to remove all the screws securing a computer case and to unfasten all components from the motherboard inside?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Keep the weight down in each truck. "},{"question":"  C. Green engineering ","choices":["  D. Design for logistics ","304. The correct answer is B. ","The sales and operations plan reconciles the business plans of all units of the firm, including finance, sales and marketing, and operations; the unified set of numbers has the approval of senior management. It is neither a contract between sales and operations nor a balance of end item supply and demand.  ","Which of the following statements correctly identifies the major purpose of the sales and operations plan (S\u0026OP)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Design for manufacture "},{"question":"  C. S\u0026OP represents the firm's essential planning document for use in securing startup financing from bankers and investors. ","choices":["  D. S\u0026OP represents the essence of a contract between sales and operations. ","305. The correct answer is D. ","Fixed quantity ordering is generally used to fill containers, qualify for quantity discounts, or both. The model works best when demand is known and stable with predictable lead times.  ","Use of a fixed order quantity model is most likely to be effective in which of the following cases?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. S\u0026OP represents the mutual agreement of finance, sales, marketing, operations, and senior management on a single set of supply/demand numbers. "},{"question":"  C. Lead time is highly variable. ","choices":["  D. Shipper is looking for quantity discounts","306. The correct answer is B. ","A letter of credit typically requires that payment be contingent upon receipt of an invoice (which states the value of the cargo) and a bill of lading (which indicates that the cargo has been delivered to the carrier for transport). A description of the goods and their origin appears already in the L/C.  ","In a letter of credit financing, which of the following documents must accompany a seller's draft to trigger payment?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Production is run on lean assumptions. "},{"question":"  C. Dock receipt and bill of lading ","choices":["  D. Certificate of origin and dock receipt ","307. The correct answer is A. ","Once the cargo has \"passed over the ship's rail\" (to use the original terms), the importer takes title and is responsible for insurance, etc. The Incoterm stands for \"Free on Board\" (free, that is, from the exporter's point of view).  ","According to the familiar Incoterm FOB, which one of the following entities holds title to export/import cargo once it has \"passed over the ship's rail\"?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Commercial invoice and bill of lading "},{"question":"  C. Exporter ","choices":["  D. Insurance company","308. The correct answer is C. ","The production plan focuses on the output of product (or services); pricing takes place elsewhere in the planning process.  ","Which of the following would not be an acceptable measurement of output for use in production planning?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Carrier "},{"question":"  C. Euros ","choices":["  D. Numbers ","309. The correct answer is D. ","Increasing the number of warehouses tends to cause an increase in inventory as each adds a buffer of supply stock. On the other hand, the ratio of storage space to total square feet tends to decrease as each facility contains nonstorage areas that could be consolidated in a single warehouse.  ","Which of the following changes tend to occur as a result of adding warehouses to a logistics network (assuming no other changes)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Tons "},{"question":"  C. Inventory decreases and the ratio of storage space to total square feet decreases. ","choices":["  D. Inventory increases while the ratio of storage space to total warehouse square feet decreases","310. The correct answer is D. ","As a demand planning concept, \"seasonality\" refers to demand patterns influenced by time, not just by the four seasons of the year. The restaurant business varies with the calendar, the day of the week, and the time of day.  ","The impact of seasonality on demand in a fast-food restaurant might be measured in which of the following ways?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Inventory decreases while the ratio of storage space to square feet increases. "},{"question":"  C. Hour of the day ","choices":["  D. All of the above","311. The correct answer is C. ","The MAD (mean absolute deviation) is the average amount by which the forecast differs from the actual demand (Deviation = Demand - Forecast). It is \"absolute\" because it takes into account only the amount of the deviation, not the direction. Tracking the absolute deviation provides information for use in assessing the reliability of forecasts. ","Which of the following correctly identifies the MAD for the six months in the example shown in the table below? "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Day of the week "},{"question":"  C. 2.00 ","choices":["  D. 12.00","312. The correct answer is D. ","The customs house broker specializes in moving imported goods through customs, expediting paperwork (which now takes place electronically), and paying the import duties under a power of attorney from the importer.  ","An importer will often give which one of the following independent operators power of attorney to pay import duties on its behalf?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. 1.67 "},{"question":"  C. Ship broker ","choices":["  D. Customs house broker","313. The correct answer is C. ","The seasonal average demand for February is the monthly average demand for the three Februarys listed: (101 + 101 + 105) / 3 = 102.  ","Which of the following numbers is the correct seasonal average demand for February in the example shown in the table below (rounded to the nearest whole number)? "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Foreign carrier "},{"question":"  C. 102 ","choices":["  D. 105 ","314. The correct answer is A. ","The forecast is 10,100 if you use the exponential smoothing equation as follows: Forecast = Previous Forecast + α (Demand - Forecast), where α is the smoothing constant, or, in this instance, the forecast = 10,150 + .20 (9,900 - 10,150) = 10,100. (Demand for February is 9,900, or sales minus refunds.)  ","Which of the following numbers gives the correct March forecast using the data below and the exponential smoothing approach? "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. 100 "},{"question":"  C. 10,120 ","choices":["  D. 10,150 ","315. The correct answer is A. ","Capacity control takes place in the very short term in the context of daily production.  ","Capacity control takes place against which of the following time horizons?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. 10,110 "},{"question":"  C. Annual horizon ","choices":["  D. Long term","316. The correct answer is C. ","Coal makes up the bulk of rail cargo in both the United States and Great Britain. Rail transport is most appropriate for heavy, durable items of low value like raw materials, agricultural products, chemicals, construction materials, and industrial metals.  ","Which of the following items makes up the majority of rail cargo in the United States and Great Britain?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Monthly horizon "},{"question":"  C. Coal ","choices":["  D. Agricultural commodities","317. The correct answer is A. ","Designing products in kit form makes them easier to transport, store, and package, all aspects of logistics.  ","Which of the following design philosophies is most responsible for furniture that comes in kit form to be assembled by the retail customer at home?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Forest products "},{"question":"  C. Design for the environment ","choices":["  D. Concurrent engineering","318. The correct answer is A. ","Pipelines are considered a very secure way to convey liquid cargo. Except for earthquakes or terrorist attacks, pipelines will carry appropriate freight with almost no risk of loss or damage.  ","Which of the following offers the greatest security against loss of cargo when transporting petroleum?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Design for manufacture "},{"question":"  C. Water ","choices":["  D. Rail","319. The correct answer is A. ","Using the economic order quantity effectively assumes a number of conditions, such as constant, known demand, constant lead times, and the simultaneous arrival of all items ordered. Order intervals may vary, but the quantity (EOQ) is fixed.  ","The EOQ ordering system will work adequately under which one of the following conditions?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Road "},{"question":"  C. Orders arrive in stages. ","choices":["  D. Lead times vary","320. The correct answer is D. ","Freight forwarders function like \"travel agents for cargo,\" arranging for transport but not operating their own carriers.  ","Which one of the following types of third-party logistics firms schedules cargo transport but operates no carriers?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Seasonal demand varies. "},{"question":"  C. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC) ","choices":["  D. Freight forwarder ","321. The correct answer is A. ","When all capacity and materials have been committed to specific orders, a demand time fence may be placed on the MPS, marking off a frozen zone in which no orders can be filled without permission from senior management.  ","Capacity and materials are committed to specific orders inside which of the following zones on the master production schedule?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Consolidator "},{"question":"  C. Slushy zone ","choices":["  D. Planning zone ","322. The correct answer is C. ","The forklift truck is designed specifically for moving, placing, and retrieving pallets. The other options either have less flexibility or are not especially suitable for moving small loads. ","Which of the following pieces of warehouse equipment provides maximum flexibility in the movement, placement, and retrieval of pallets?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Liquid zone "},{"question":"  C. Forklift truck ","choices":["  D. Crane","323.  The correct answer is C. ","Exempt carriers are (as the name suggests) granted exemption from economic regulation if they carry certain types of products, including unprocessed agricultural products and raw materials. They generally operate locally and charge relatively low rates based on the going rates in their markets.  ","Which of the following might a logistics manager choose to carry raw materials in local markets at a relatively low rate determined by the market?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Tow tractor with trailer "},{"question":"  C. Exempt carrier ","choices":["  D. Common carrier ","324. The correct answer is D. ","Pilferage is considered to be one of the potential costs of carrying inventory.  ","From the inventory manager's point of view, pilferage contributes to which of the following costs?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Contract carrier "},{"question":"  C. Logistics costs ","choices":["  D. Carrying costs ","325. The correct answer is C. ","Among the least desirable methods of product disposal, delivery to a landfill scores dead last behind incineration, energy recovery, and recycling. However, some landfills are more responsible than others, and a landfill is a better place to deposit products at the end of their useful lives than rivers, lakes, and untended dumps.  ","Of the following methods of treating obsolete goods, which is considered to be the least responsible?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Ordering costs "},{"question":"  C. Burial in a clean, responsible landfill ","choices":["  D. Disposal at a recycling center","326. The correct answer is C. ","The average demand for the three months from January through March is 20 (21 + 17 + 22 = 60; 60 / 3 = 20), so the forecast for April is 20, which is two less than the actual demand.  ","Referring to the table below, calculate a forecast for April using the three-month moving average method. Based on your calculation, which of the following statements correctly relates the forecast to the actual April demand of 22? "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Incineration "},{"question":"  C. Demand exceeds forecast by 2. ","choices":["  D. Demand exceeds forecast by 3. ","327. The correct answer is B. ","Transferring responsibility for logistics to a 4PL involves loss of control, so a manager may want to compensate with frequent reviews (at least at first). The upside of giving control of logistics to a specialist should be an increase in flexibility, greater economies of scale, and more advanced logistics technology. ","When engaging the services of a fourth-party logistics provider, a logistics manager should be careful to minimize the effects of which of the following potential risks?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Demand exceeds forecast by 1.  "},{"question":"  C. Less rapid adjustment to new customer technologies ","choices":["  D. Reduced economies of scale","328. The correct answer is C. ","Consolidation is the process of breaking down incoming shipments from a variety of sources to mix the various products together in combinations specified by a number of recipients. (The process is also called mixing.) The mix of products may include items from storage as well as those just received.  ","Which one of the following warehouse operations resembles break-bulk, except that it combines products from more than one manufacturer and may also involve product storage?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Reduction in control "},{"question":"  C. Consolidation ","choices":["  D. Assembly ","329. The correct answer is D. ","The ABC system of classifying inventory asserts that the A items in your inventory will constitute only about 15 percent of the total number of items but will create 70 to 80 percent of value. This is an approximate application of the Pareto principle, or 80-20 rule, which holds that about 20 percent of possible causes account for about 80 percent of outcomes.  ","According to the ABC system of classifying inventory, an application of the Pareto principle, the greatest share of revenue will be generated by which of the following numbers of inventory items (approximately)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Cross-docking "},{"question":"  C. 30 percent ","choices":["  D. 15 percent ","330. The correct answer is C. ","The forecast accuracy is likely to be greatest for all DaimlerChrysler models (and then for all Dodges, all Dodge Stratuses, and all Dodge Stratus SEs, in descending order of accuracy). The larger the aggregate, the more accurate the forecast.  ","Demand forecasts are likely to be most accurate for which of the following items?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. 55 percent "},{"question":"  C. All DaimlerChrysler cars ","choices":["  D. All Dodge Models","331. The correct answer is A. ","Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR®) is a formal description of best practices developed and maintained by VICS to help supply chain partners develop successful collaborations.  ","Which of the following is a type of supply chain collaboration formalized by the Voluntary Interindustry Commerce Standards Association (VICS)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. All Dodge Stratus models "},{"question":"  C. Continuous replenishment ","choices":["  D. Quick response","332. The correct answer is D. ","The area of CPFR that corresponds to the order-to-cash cycle is execution, which includes the collaboration tasks of order generation and order fulfillment. Order fulfillment includes the enterprise task of logistics/distribution.  ","In the CPFR model, which of the following corresponds to the order-to-cash cycle?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Vendor-managed inventory "},{"question":"  C. Logistics/distribution ","choices":["  D. Execution","333. The correct answer is A. ","Removing an echelon from the network should reduce all the costs specified in the options except for transportation costs. Removing one level of warehousing, for example, will most likely increase the number of miles goods are carried from the points upstream from the echelon to the points downstream. ","When a logistics manager removes a complete echelon from the distribution chain to reduce overall expenses, there may be a tradeoff for expenses in which of the following areas?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Demand and supply management "},{"question":"  C. Increased taxes on property and equipment ","choices":["  D. Increased inventory handling costs ","334. The correct answer is A. ","An ETC (export trading company) buys goods domestically to sell into foreign markets. Such firms are especially significant in Japan, where they may own steamship lines, warehouses, insurance services, and so forth.  ","Which one of the following firms, known in Japan as sogo shosha, may be a large conglomerate that actually buys goods in one country for sale in a foreign market?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Increased inventory holding costs "},{"question":"  C. Consolidator ","choices":["  D. Ship broker ","335. The correct answer is B. ","The route file identifies the work center where a particular process will take place.  ","Which one of the following would appear in the route file?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Foreign carrier "},{"question":"  C. List of component items for one end item ","choices":["  D. Mechanical drawings of a finished product","336. The correct answer is A. ","VMI (vendor-managed inventory) is a form of collaboration in which a supplier performs some or all of the inventory operations traditionally handled by a retailer, including display design, replenishment, inventory counting, record keeping, and so on. (VMI can overlap with other systems.)  ","Which of the following identifies a type of collaboration in which a manufacturer of razor blades determines how its product is displayed on a retailer's shelves and performs cycle counting at the store?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Work center ID "},{"question":"  C. Continuous replenishment (CR) ","choices":["  D. Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment","337. The correct answer is B. ","Available-to-promise equals the inventory on hand plus scheduled production reduced by orders already on the books. The ATP continues to decline as orders come in during the period.  ","The master schedule shows inventory on hand of 150 items, scheduled production of 500 items, and booked orders of 400 items. Which of the following is the correct number of available-to-promise items?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Quick response (QR) "},{"question":"  C. 500 ","choices":["  D. 650","338. The correct answer is D. ","Concurrent engineering (CE) is known by several other names, such as design for manufacture and participative design. Early instances in the 1980s focused on the importance of including manufacturing engineers in the design process to spot any design decisions that would make production more difficult and expensive. More stakeholders from suppliers, customers, and other functional areas may also participate.  ","Which of the following might participate on a team with design engineers in the process known as concurrent engineering?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. 250 "},{"question":"  C. Customer representatives ","choices":["  D. Any or all of the above","339. The correct answer is B. ","Sales and operations planning (S\u0026OP) is a monthly process.  ","How often, under normal circumstances, does a pre-S\u0026OP meeting take place?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Market researchers "},{"question":"  C. Quarterly ","choices":["  D. Annually ","340. The correct answer is D. ","The business cycle correlates with alternating medium-term advances and declines in consumer buying patterns. Cycles are not short-term fluctuations related to holidays or random events, nor are they steady trends in only one direction, such as might be caused by factors such as a product cycle or demographics. ","Which of the following might cause cyclical movements in a time series of demand data?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Monthly "},{"question":"  C. Random changes in consumer sentiment ","choices":["  D. Recession ","341. The correct answer is A. ","The sales and operations plan takes the business plan as its point of reference for developing a plan that balances supply and demand by merging input from sales and marketing on the one hand and operations on the other.  ","Which of the following provides a point of reference for formulating the sales and operations plan?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Holiday shopping "},{"question":"  C. Production forecast ","choices":["  D. Financial plan ","342. The correct answer is A. ","While protecting all items is obviously important, the most cost-effective approach may be to spend relatively more resources on A items than on the less valuable, but larger, percentage of inventory. ","Which of the following statements best describes the relative care a warehouse manager should take in securing A, B, and C inventory items?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Marketing plan "},{"question":"  C. Provide best protection for C items. ","choices":["  D. Provide the same level of protection to all items","343. The correct answer is D. ","Bridge cranes can lift very heavy objects and they operate from overhead, so they leave the floor free for other activities.  ","Which one of the following is most appropriate for lifting very heavy items while causing minimal disruption of floor activities in the area?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Provide best protection for B items. "},{"question":"  C. AGVS ","choices":["  D. Bridge crane ","344. The correct answer is D. ","The conveyer belt has no operator, so it not only minimizes operator costs, it eliminates them. Automated towlines are not likely to appeal to the cost-conscious manager.  ","Which one of the following would you select to move pallets through warehouse aisles while minimizing costs?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Forklift truck "},{"question":"  C. Forklift truck ","choices":["  D. Conveyer belt ","345. The correct answer is C. ","The sales and marketing area is responsible and accountable for forecasting. Someone has to be responsible for the forecast for assessment purposes, but this does not mean that other areas cannot contribute to the forecast or that the forecast cannot be shared with other functional areas and supply chain partners. Information sharing is key to supply chain management.  ","Which one of the following functional areas is responsible for demand forecasting?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Automated towlines "},{"question":"  C. Sales and marketing ","choices":["  D. Executive team ","346. The correct answer is B. ","Naive forecasting assumes that demand in the next period will equal demand in the last period. It is a form of quantitative forecasting but lacks any analysis.  ","Which of the following forms the basis for a naive demand forecast?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Purchasing "},{"question":"  C. Analogy ","choices":["  D. Intuition","347. The correct answer is B. ","The Delphi method uses information from a panel of experts who respond anonymously to questionnaires. After several rounds of responses and critiques, a moderator produces a report expressing the collective opinion of the group.  ","Which of the following forecast techniques relies upon an expert panel that responds to questionnaires and never meets face to face?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Data from the last demand period "},{"question":"  C. Pyramid forecasting ","choices":["  D. Historical analogy","348. The correct answer is C. ","Under NAFTA, U.S. firms that subcontract work to maqualidoras in Mexico pay only a tax based on the value added in Mexico, which is primarily attributable to low-wage labor.  ","Which of the following statements identifies the financial consequences to a U.S. firm under NAFTA when it transfers assembled materials from a maquiladora subcontractor back into the United States?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Delphi method "},{"question":"  C. It pays a tax based on the value added in Mexico. ","choices":["  D. It pays use (sales) tax on the value of the finished goods. ","349. The correct answer is D. ","Break-bulk operations break an incoming shipment from one source into smaller lots for reshipping to specific customers.  ","Which one of the following warehouse operations would take place at a manufacturer's centralized warehouse to facilitate delivery of one product to many retailers?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. It pays a duty but receives a duty drawback. "},{"question":"  C. Mixing ","choices":["  D. Break-bulk","350. The correct answer is D. ","Market segmentation and the deployment of the sales force can be based upon any of a number of criteria, including but by no means limited to geography, market potential, or age.  ","Which of the following constitutes a potentially appropriate way to segment a market?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Spot stocking "},{"question":"  C. Age ","choices":["  D. Any of the above can be appropriate. ","351. The correct answer is B. ","All market participants can benefit from well-crafted regulations regarding such matters as fairness and safety, but the public at large is most likely to be in synch with the government on the broad spectrum of regulations, from pricing through access to safety and environmental stewardship. (This assumes a government that is responsive to public demands.)  ","Which of the following transportation stakeholders is most likely to be in agreement with the government about the need for market regulation?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Market potential "},{"question":"  C. Carriers ","choices":["  D. Recipients ","352. The correct answer is B. ","Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts, so the pyramid technique begins by forecasting demand for the product family and then disaggregates the demand to generate single-product demand forecasts. This ensures alignment between forecasts for the group and the components of the group. (This is not to imply that the technique ignores other principles, only that it specifically relies upon the superior reliability of group forecasting.)  ","The forecasting method known as the pyramid technique specifically incorporates which one of the following principles of forecasting?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. The public "},{"question":"  C. Short-range forecasts are more reliable than long-range forecasts. ","choices":["  D. Quantitative data are preferable to qualitative estimates. ","353. The correct answer is A. ","Standardization, also called universality, is the strategy of designing a product to work in multiple markets rather than in only one market. Modular design and mass customization may reach multiple market segments, but they do so by product differentiation, not standardization.  ","Which of the following is another name for the \"one size fits all\" type of design?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts. "},{"question":"  C. Modular design ","choices":["  D. Component commonality ","354. The correct answer is A. ","Transferring responsibility for logistics to a 4PL involves loss of control, so a manager may want to compensate with frequent reviews (at least at first). The upside of giving control of logistics to a specialist should be an increase in flexibility, greater economies of scale, and more advanced logistics technology. ","When engaging the services of a fourth-party logistics provider, a logistics manager should be careful to minimize the effects of which of the following potential risks?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Mass customization "},{"question":"  C. Reduction in flexible deployment of resources ","choices":["  D. Reduced economies of scale","355. The correct answer is B. ","Assortment planning in industries in which demand and product styles change with each season present a special challenge to forecasters. The constant rotation through different styles or models means there is little historical demand data for particular products. VICS CPFR includes a scenario with guidelines for assortment planning based on graphic presentations of new models along with financial models.  ","CPFR includes formal guidelines for a growing number of scenarios. Which of the following CPFR scenarios includes such methods as graphical presentations of new products to help make merchandizing decisions in the absence of solid historical data on demand?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Less rapid adjustment to new customer technologies "},{"question":"  C. Store replenishment collaboration ","choices":["  D. DC replenishment collaboration","356. The correct answer is C. ","Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR®) is a formal description of best practices developed and maintained by VICS to help supply chain partners develop successful collaborations.  ","Which of the following is a type of supply chain collaboration formalized by the Voluntary Interindustry Commerce Standards Association (VICS)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Collaborative assortment planning "},{"question":"  C. Collective planning, forecasting, and replenishment ","choices":["  D. Continuous replenishment","357. The correct answer is B. ","The forklift truck is designed specifically for moving, placing, and retrieving pallets. The other options either have less flexibility or are not especially suitable for moving small loads.  ","Which of the following pieces of warehouse equipment provides maximum flexibility in the movement, placement, and retrieval of pallets?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Quick response "},{"question":"  C. Tow tractor with trailer ","choices":["  D. Crane ","358  The correct answer is C. ","Product families for purposes of the operations plan are best chosen by similar manufacturing requirements to facilitate other planning processes, such as production scheduling. (Marketing can group products in other ways for its purposes.)  ","Which of the following would provide a sound method for grouping products into product families for the operations plan?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Forklift truck "},{"question":"  C. Similarity of manufacturing processes ","choices":["  D. National market destination","359. The correct answer is C. ","Component commonality is the design strategy of substituting one common component for a variety of similar components.  ","Which of the following design strategies would most likely be responsible for the fact that only one screwdriver is needed to remove all the screws securing a computer case and to unfasten all components from the motherboard inside?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Similar seasonality "},{"question":"  C. Component commonality ","choices":["  D. Green engineering","360. The correct answer is C. ","Although CPFR is enhanced by software, it is fundamentally a set of business practices for synchronizing the operations of buyer and seller. It depends for success upon a willingness to share data for forecasting, execution, assessments, and other functions. The data may be shared on peer-to-peer networks, extranets, or third-party servers, and the Internet is generally involved as the medium for accessing the shared data. But technology is not at the heart of the matter; sharing data in joint operations is.  ","In regard to technology, CPFR may be said to depend fundamentally upon which of the following?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Design for logistics "},{"question":"  C. Shared data in any technological format ","choices":["  D. World Wide Web ","361. The correct answer is A. ","While protecting all items is obviously important, the most cost-effective approach may be to spend relatively more resources on A items than on the less valuable, but larger, percentage of inventory.  ","Which of the following statements best describes the relative care a warehouse manager should take in securing A, B, and C inventory items?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Third-party host "},{"question":"  C. Provide best protection for C items. ","choices":["  D. Provide the same level of protection to all items. ","362. The correct answer is A. ","The three-month moving average forecast for May is 20.33, which is the average monthly demand for the months from February through April (17 + 22 + 22 = 61 / 3 = 20.33); the naive forecast is taken from the period preceding the forecast period, which in this case is 22, the actual demand for May. Note that the naive forecast (22) is more nearly accurate in this case, because it adjusts faster than the moving average. However, it could just as easily have been less accurate if demand had changed in a different direction or by a different amount.  ","Referring to the demand table below, calculate forecasts for May using both the three-month moving average (MA) and the naive forecasting methods. Which of the following statements correctly identifies the two forecasts? "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Provide best protection for B items. "},{"question":"  C. MA forecast = 21.33; naive forecast = 22 ","choices":["  D. MA forecast = 22.00; naive forecast = 17","363. The correct answer is B. ","Typically used with JIT, lot-for-lot sizing delivers the exact amount needed when it is needed, thereby eliminating inventory buffers. Frequent delivery of small lots requires more setups.  ","Which one of the following conditions is a potential drawback of lot-for-lot order sizing?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. MA forecast = 20.67; naive forecast = 20 "},{"question":"  C. Incompatibility with JIT ","choices":["  D. High inventory costs ","364. The correct answer is D. ","A make-to-stock strategy \"pushes\" materials and products through the system in accordance with preset schedules rather than letting them be \"pulled\" through by actual orders.  ","If you favored a push approach to managing a supply chain, which of the following production strategies would you be most likely to adopt?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. High setup costs "},{"question":"  C. JIT ","choices":["  D. Make-to-stock","365. The correct answer is A. ","Railroads have maintained a fairly steady 40 percent share of the market among common carriers since the Staggers Act, but other results of deregulation include declines in the number of large rail carriers, in total miles of track, in rates, and in destinations served.  ","Which one of the following statements correctly identifies a consequence of the Staggers Act of 1980, which deregulated rail transport in the United States?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Assemble-to-order "},{"question":"  C. Steady increase in markets served by rail ","choices":["  D. Steady increase in rates","366. The correct answer is C. ","Pilferage is considered to be one of the potential costs of carrying inventory.  ","From the inventory manager's point of view, pilferage contributes to which of the following costs?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Steady increase in miles of track in service "},{"question":"  C. Carrying costs ","choices":["  D. Logistics costs ","367. The correct answer is A. ","A weighted moving average puts more emphasis than a simple moving average does on the most recent demand numbers. Because of the weighting, it doesn't lag as far behind demand data as a simple moving average. Its focus, therefore, is on recent trends, not the long term. It isn't simpler.  ","Which of the following statements correctly identifies the purpose of the weights in a weighted moving average?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Ordering costs "},{"question":"  C. To take account of mean average deviation ","choices":["  D. To make data gathering and forecasting calculations simpler ","368. The correct answer is C. ","The \"Orange Book\" is published by the United Nations; its first edition came out in 1956. It contains the United Nations Recommendations on the Transport of Dangerous Goods (UNRMTDG), in which all national controls are grounded. The UN recommendations do not have the force of law, but national regulations based on them may.  ","Which of the following institutions publishes the \"Orange Book\" containing recommendations that form the basis of international dangerous goods (hazardous materials) laws and regulations?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. To put more emphasis on long-term influences on demand "},{"question":"  C. United Nations ","choices":["  D. World Court ","369. The correct answer is C. ","In the model, certain tasks are performed by the buyer/retailer (POS forecasting in this case), certain tasks are performed by the seller/manufacturer (market analysis in this case), and those tasks are reconciled in a joint session. The joint session to reconcile POS forecasting and market analysis results in a shared sales forecast.  ","In the CPFR model, which of the following tasks would be performed jointly by the manufacturer (seller) and the retailer (buyer)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) "},{"question":"  C. Sales forecasting ","choices":["  D. All of the above would be performed jointly","370. The correct answer is A. ","Transportation expenses make up the largest portion of the logistics budget, so taking the discount on transportation costs would give you the largest cost reduction. (Of course, you would have to consider possible tradeoffs if discounting transportation caused cost increases elsewhere in the system.) ","If you were able to get a 20 percent discount on any of the following logistics expenses, which would you choose to receive the maximum cost savings?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Market data analysis "},{"question":"  C. Warehousing ","choices":["  D. Materials handling","371. The correct answer is A. ","Capacity control takes place in the very short term in the context of daily production.  ","Capacity control takes place against which of the following time horizons?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Compliance "},{"question":"  C. Annual horizon ","choices":["  D. Long term","372. The correct answer is B. ","The exporter determines the tariff classification using the harmonized code when packaging the goods for export. The importer (usually through the customs house broker) pays the duty when goods come through customs.  ","Which one of the following describes the typical situation in regards to payment of import duties?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Monthly horizon "},{"question":"  C. The importer determines the tariff classification and the exporter pays the duty. ","choices":["  D. The importer determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. ","373. The correct answer is B. ","To achieve economies of scale in transportation, consolidation combines shipments from many incoming sources when loading outbound vehicles headed for a single location.  ","Which one of the following warehouse operations is most appropriate for a manufacturer that receives components from many suppliers and wants to achieve economies of scale when transporting those components to one plant?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. The exporter determines the tariff classification and the importer pays the duty. "},{"question":"  C. Break-bulk ","choices":["  D. Mixing ","374. The correct answer is D. ","Break-bulk operations break an incoming shipment from one source into smaller lots for reshipping to specific customers.  ","Which one of the following warehouse operations would take place at a manufacturer's centralized warehouse to facilitate delivery of one product to many retailers?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Consolidation "},{"question":"  C. Spot stocking ","choices":["  D. Break-bulk","375. The correct answer is D. ","The sales and operations plan takes the business plan as its point of reference for developing a plan that balances supply and demand by merging input from sales and marketing on the one hand and operations on the other.  ","Which of the following provides a point of reference for formulating the sales and operations plan?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Mixing "},{"question":"  C. Marketing plan ","choices":["  D. Business plan","376. The correct answer is D. ","The sales and marketing area is responsible and accountable for forecasting. Someone has to be responsible for the forecast for assessment purposes, but this does not mean that other areas cannot contribute to the forecast or that the forecast cannot be shared with other functional areas and supply chain partners. Information sharing is key to supply chain management.  ","Which one of the following functional areas is responsible for demand forecasting?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Financial plan "},{"question":"  C. Purchasing ","choices":["  D. Sales and marketing ","377. The correct answer is D. ","The business plan provides a long-range view of strategy and guidance for developing tactical plans for sales, marketing, and operations.  ","A business plan would typically include which of the following?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. IT "},{"question":"  C. Monthly production figures for each product family ","choices":["  D. Long-term guidance for developing tactical production plans ","378. The correct answer is C. ","Consolidators specialize in filling trucks for backhaul journeys from import destinations to port when the importer provides no goods for carriage. The consolidator may have to consolidate small shipments from a number of exporters to fill the carriers. ","A shipper whose exports are carried from the foreign port to the importer's dock by trucks that return empty to the port might hire which one of the following firms to find goods to carry on the backhaul route?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Clearly defined marketing tactics "},{"question":"  C. Consolidator ","choices":["  D. Freight forwarder","379. The correct answer is B. ","Spot stocking is used for limited product lines and highly seasonal products that can be centrally stored during most of the year and spot-stocked in season at warehouses near the places where they will be purchased and used. Manufacturers use spot stocking for agricultural products used only during one limited operation, such as harvesting.  ","Which one of the following types of warehousing is most appropriate for agricultural supplies that might be used only once during the year?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Export packager "},{"question":"  C. Stockpiling ","choices":["  D. Postponement","380. The correct answer is A. ","The public builds and maintains the infrastructure used by trucks, so they have low fixed costs. But they have relatively high variable costs for operation and maintenance.  ","Which of the following correctly identifies the cost structure of trucking?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Spot stocking "},{"question":"  C. High fixed costs, low variable costs ","choices":["  D. Low fixed costs, low variable costs","381. The correct answer is B. ","In many chains, variance in order quantity tends to increase as you move upstream away from the end customer. This is the bullwhip effect.  ","In a multiple-echelon distribution network where each warehouse orders independently based on local demand, where in the chain do you find the most variance in order quantity?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. High fixed costs, high variable costs "},{"question":"  C. Variability tend to be greatest in the middle of the chain, diminishing toward either end. ","choices":["  D. Variability tends to increase toward the customer end of the chain.","382.  The correct answer is A. ","Using common components for a variety of purposes provides economies of scale in purchasing and manufacture but can limit design flexibility and reduce quality.  ","Which of the following design strategies offers streamlined production and lower purchasing costs with a possible tradeoff against reduced design flexibility and lower quality?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Variability tends to increase toward the raw materials end of the chain. "},{"question":"  C. Mass customization ","choices":["  D. Universality ","383. The correct answer is B. ","In a lot-for-lot schedule, the planned order release is equal to net requirements (gross requirement reduced by any inventory on hand). There is unlikely to be inventory on hand except at the beginning of an order period.  ","If you are making up a production schedule using the lot-for-lot sizing method, which of the following equations would you use to determine the planned order receipt (assuming you know the gross amount required)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Integral design "},{"question":"  C. Gross requirement minus scheduled receipts ","choices":["  D. Gross requirement minus projected on hand minus scheduled receipts ","384. The correct answer is A. ","Contract carriers can generally offer lower rates and tailored services to select clients.  ","Which one of the following would a firm be most likely to choose to deliver goods in national markets if it is looking for tailored services and a relatively low negotiated rate?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Gross requirement minus projected amounts on hand "},{"question":"  C. Common carrier ","choices":["  D. Private carrier ","385. The correct answer is C. ","NAFTA eliminated many tariffs on imports originating from within the region and scheduled elimination of the rest. Other barriers, such as access to roads on either side of the U.S.-Mexican border, remain troublesome. Imports originating from countries within the region are granted favorable duties compared to goods from outside, but documenting country of origin can be troublesome.  ","Which one of the following benefits has been realized under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Exempt carrier "},{"question":"  C. Elimination of many regional tariffs ","choices":["  D. Easier access to competitively priced goods from outside the region ","386. The correct answer is C. ","The average demand for the three months from January through March is 20 (21 + 17 + 22 = 60; 60 / 3 = 20), so the forecast for April is 20, which is two less than the actual demand.  ","Referring to the table below, calculate a forecast for April using the three-month moving average method. Based on your calculation, which of the following statements correctly relates the forecast to the actual April demand of 22? "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Simplified documentation to qualify for lower tariffs on regional goods "},{"question":"  C. Demand exceeds forecast by 2. ","choices":["  D. Demand exceeds forecast by 3.","387. The correct answer is D. ","Pipelines are considered a very secure way to convey liquid cargo. Except for earthquakes or terrorist attacks, pipelines will carry appropriate freight with almost no risk of loss or damage.  ","Which of the following offers the greatest security against loss of cargo when transporting petroleum?"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Demand exceeds forecast by 1. "},{"question":"  C. Road ","choices":["  D. Pipelines  ","388. The correct answer is B. ","Water transport offers the lowest rates per ton, much lower even than rail, which is second. Trucking is considerably more expensive than rail but substantially less expensive than air.  ","Place the following modes of transportation in order of rate per ton-mile for carrying cargo, with I being the lowest rates and IV being the highest."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"  B. Rail "},{"question":"\tII. ","choices":["\tAir ","\tIII. ","\tWater ","\tIV. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"\tRail "},{"question":"  B. III, I, IV, II ","choices":["  C. III, IV, II, I ","  D. IV, I, II, III","389. The correct answer is B. ","The monthly S\u0026OP meeting deals with aggregate-level information about product families and output. The S\u0026OP executive committee can make changes in either the operations plan or the business plan if they get out of synch with one another.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. I, III, IV, II "},{"question":"  B. Business plan ","choices":["  C. Product features ","  D. Product pricing ","390. The correct answer is C. ","The main benefit of the pull system of distribution is sensitivity to local customer demand, since orders begin near the customer and \"pull\" products from upstream. This approach does not facilitate communication, eliminate safety stock, or improve visibility down the chain because there is no central coordination and upstream partners have to depend upon forecasting to plan for future orders rather than upon (for example) a predetermined production schedule.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Weekly production schedules "},{"question":"  B. Enhanced communication up the chain ","choices":["  C. Sensitivity to demands of the final customer ","  D. Enhanced visibility of future demand all along the chain","391. The correct answer is D. ","All market participants can benefit from well-crafted regulations regarding such matters as fairness and safety, but the public at large is most likely to be in synch with the government on the broad spectrum of regulations, from pricing through access to safety and environmental stewardship. (This assumes a government that is responsive to public demands.)  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Elimination of safety stock "},{"question":"  B. Carriers ","choices":["  C. Recipients ","  D. The public ","392. The correct answer is B. ","Railroad and barges both specialize in carrying very heavy, dense, low-value cargo over long distances. A rail line laid along a waterway would make a potent rival for the water carrier.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Shippers "},{"question":"  B. Rail ","choices":["  C. Trucking ","  D. Pipeline","393. The correct answer is A. ","The three-month weighted moving average forecast for April is 20.17 (3 x 22 = 66; 2 x 17 = 34; 1 x 21 = 21; 66 + 34 + 21 = 121; 121 / 6 = 20.17). Did you remember to divide by the sum of the weights (6) instead of by 3?  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Piggyback "},{"question":"  B. 20.33 ","choices":["  C. 20.67 ","  D. 40.33","394. The correct answer is A. ","The master production schedule includes dates of production for make-to-stock end items. (This can be either finished products or, in a modular approach, components.)  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. 20.17 "},{"question":"  B. Product families ","choices":["  C. Orders ","  D. Components","395. The correct answer is C. ","Pipeline inventory is stock kept on hand to fill orders while the next lot is in transit. It is also known as transportation inventory.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. End items "},{"question":"  B. Fluctuation inventory ","choices":["  C. Pipeline inventory ","  D. Anticipatory inventory","396. The correct answer is C. ","The MRP schedules delivery of dependent demand items (which are in turn based upon independent demand forecasts). The other processes work with independent demand or product families.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Work-in-process inventory "},{"question":"  B. Sales and operations planning process ","choices":["  C. Material requirements planning process ","  D. Market planning process","397. The correct answer is B. ","Modular design creates mix-and-match components that can be combined into different products, whereas integral design creates one product from a unique set of components.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Master production scheduling process "},{"question":"  B. Modular design ","choices":["  C. Mass customization ","  D. Design for postponement","398. The correct answer is D. ","Revenue from the sale of service contracts can offset some of the expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain, including higher transportation fees for small, sporadic shipments; the addition of transportation lanes to reach specialized warehouses; and, of course, the costs to the company of making warranty repairs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Universality "},{"question":"  B. More efficient use of warehouses set up for forward logistics ","choices":["  C. Freight discounts on shipments of returned items ","  D. Sale of service contracts ","399. The correct answer is C. ","Rail provides a rough ride for cargo, resulting in more breakage than occurs in cargo transported by truck, water, or air.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Rebates from landfills "},{"question":"  B. Truck transport ","choices":["  C. Rail transport ","  D. Air transport ","400. The correct answer is A. ","The risk of having inventory items become obsolete increases when amounts ordered exceed the forecast significantly. Economies of scale in transport and purchase are potential benefits of larger orders, as is decoupling from the supplier.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Water transport "},{"question":"  B. Decoupling from supplier ","choices":["  C. Higher per-car costs for transporting the inventory ","  D. Higher per-item costs for purchasing the inventory","1.  The correct answer is D. ","CTMs can deliver all of these benefits by aligning transportation needs with transportation assets to eliminate inefficiencies, such as wait time, half-filled loads, or empty backhauls (\"deadheading\").  . "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Increased obsolescence "},{"question":"  B. Optimization of weight and volume capacity of network resources ","choices":["  C. Increase in backhaul opportunities for carriers ","  D. All of the above  ","2.  The correct answer is C. ","Cross-selling is a CRM tactic made possible by the accumulation of data about a customer's buying habits. Customers are offered related products in addition to their current purchase.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Reduction of carriers' wait time for loading and unloading "},{"question":"  B. a loyalty program. ","choices":["  C. cross-selling. ","  D. up-selling. ","3.  The correct answer is C. ","Before entering alliances, start identifying key issues and decisions and involving key stakeholders for fewer surprises and greater buy-in by key people.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a win-back program. "},{"question":"  B. establish ground rules for how partners will work together and resolve conflict. ","choices":["  C. align internally by identifying key issues and stakeholders. ","  D. appoint a dedicated alliance manager to oversee the partner relationship. ","4.  The correct answer is C. ","Before the rules, supervision, and improvement of the relationship can be pursued, a win-win deal must be negotiated. This sets the tone for the future alliance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. select the proper partners by evaluating corporate culture and operating style. "},{"question":"  B. engage in a collaborative corporate mindset. ","choices":["  C. negotiate a win-win deal. ","  D. establish ground rules. ","5. The correct answer is C. ","The company outsourcing CRM should be the one to define the performance standards against which the vendor will be measured at regular intervals. CRM, after all, remains the responsibility of the outsourcing business, since these are their customers. These businesses should also maintain an exit strategy in case the relationship with the CRM vendor falters.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. appoint an alliance manager. "},{"question":"  B. consider outsourcing core competencies. ","choices":["  C. develop an exit strategy. ","  D. encourage vendors to establish their own performance standards that will be meaningful to their own resources and culture. ","6. The correct answer is B. ","A product and service agreement does define specifications, but it does so in the context of segmenting customer groups. Customers are mapped and then aligned with different levels of customer service.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. transfer responsibility for CRM to vendors as a contractual obligation. "},{"question":"  B. aligns customer groups with certain service levels. ","choices":["  C. is part of a promotional strategy to win back customers. ","  D. defines product or service specifications.  ","7. The correct answer is B. ","SRM focuses on the supply side of the supply chain to ensure that customer demands can be met with a high degree of satisfaction but also with mutual profitability for all suppliers. Relationships using SRM are marked by a high degree of integration of processes and even information systems. SRM may not be appropriate in relationships with all suppliers but rather with suppliers considered key partners in maintaining the supply chain. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. is a type of customer communication. "},{"question":"  B. Way to ensure mutual profitability while meeting marketplace needs ","choices":["  C. Tool to align the customer voice with the product produced ","  D. Philosophy applied equally to all suppliers ","8. The correct answer is C. ","A cross-functional organization is one that enjoys cooperation between internal groups, especially IT and operations. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Provides fuller communication without actual integration "},{"question":"  B. change-oriented. ","choices":["  C. cross-functional. ","  D. able to lead. ","9. The correct answer is D. ","Both CRM and SRM focus on gathering information but for different purposes: CRM to understand customers better and support marketing, SRM to develop and manage relationships with key partners in the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. farseeing. "},{"question":"  B. choosing appropriate strategic partners. ","choices":["  C. providing superior marketing decision support. ","  D. gathering and sharing information.","10. The correct answer is A. ","SRM has been used in the parts or after-market industry to plan both strategy and tactics as well as to budget and manage specific business events, such as managing inventory.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. understanding buying habits of retail customers. "},{"question":"  B. gather information about customers. ","choices":["  C. retool aging technology. ","  D. select suppliers.","11. The correct answer is A. ","Because it allows a high degree of customization, one-to-one marketing programs cannot be implemented without using a CDW. CDWs are used for a variety of purposes, including segmentation, implementing different offers to customers, analyzing buying behaviors to detect preferences, and supporting strategic decisions, such as the allocation of human resources. They are usually used in conjunction with information from a company's other databases. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. implement both production and sales tactics. "},{"question":"  B. CDWs are primarily used as measurement tools. ","choices":["  C. CDWs are maintained as separate entities from a company's customer databases. ","  D. None of the above ","12.  The correct answer is C. ","It is reasonable to outsource transportation, especially in a global marketplace. And it is an especially sound practice to manage risks associated with this outsourcing by maintaining a redundant supplier in the event of disruptions with the primary outsourced transportation network. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. One-to-one marketing cannot be achieved without using a CDW. "},{"question":"  B. using an off-site delivery center. ","choices":["  C. managing possible risks of SRM outsourcing. ","  D. poor outsourcing practices. ","13.  The correct answer is B. ","Successful alliances begin from a position of mutual strength and excellence. In this case, one partner is driven primarily by a desire to escape the problem of looming competition. This will be a hard obstacle to overcome even though the partners have invested in the relationship and integrated their organizations.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. outsourcing transportation needs. "},{"question":"  B. individual excellence. ","choices":["  C. information. ","  D. investment. ","14. The correct answer is C. ","During the growth phase, the customer base increases and competitors begin to enter the market. Data on the growing customer base must be analyzed for new opportunities, and supply must be managed to meet growing demand.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. integration. "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity","15. The correct answer is B. ","From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider the strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. Surmounting limited availability of component suppliers. ","choices":["  C. Improving overall financial position. ","  D. Improving operations by lowering system costs. ","16.  The correct answer is B. ","Promotion comprises a variety of marketing activities, from customer research through strategy setting and advertising. CRM enhances both the gathering of information about customers and the use of that information in marketing activities. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Overcoming barriers to market entry. "},{"question":"  B. Promotion ","choices":["  C. Placement ","  D. Product ","17.  The correct answer is D. ","As with any technological solution, systems may be underpowered, overly complex, poorly designed, or just not right for the job at hand. In general, more systems today are designed to be open, information is more accessible, and software solutions are more easily customized to specific settings "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Price "},{"question":"  B. Difficulty in accessing information ","choices":["  C. Open system infrastructures ","  D. Underpowered, overly complex, or poorly designed solutions ","18.  The correct answer is D. ","EBS backbone applications focus on gathering, storing, and reporting information that is necessary to perform other functions in the SRM system, such as data on order history and accounting and information about suppliers and their performance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Inability to customize off-the-shelf solutions "},{"question":"  B. Managing EDI with suppliers ","choices":["  C. Product cataloging ","  D. Order history","19.  The correct answer is C. ","The company outsourcing CRM should be the one to define the performance standards against which the vendor will be measured at regular intervals. CRM, after all, remains the responsibility of the outsourcing business, since these are their customers. These businesses should also maintain an exit strategy in case the relationship with the CRM vendor falters. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A. Managing online bidding sessions "},{"question":"  B. encourage vendors to establish their own performance standards that will be meaningful to their own resources and culture. ","choices":["  C. develop an exit strategy. ","  D. transfer responsibility for CRM to vendors as a contractual obligation. ","20.  The correct answer is B. ","Segmentation by value shows a CRM business which groups are most profitable to them so that they can focus marketing efforts on those customers.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. consider outsourcing core competencies. "},{"question":"  B. Segmentation by value ","choices":["  C. Segmentation by channel ","  D. Segmentation by need ","21.  The correct answer is A. ","A product and service agreement does define specifications, but it does so in the context of segmenting customer groups. Customers are mapped and then aligned with different levels of customer service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Segmentation by demographics "},{"question":"  B. is a type of customer communication. ","choices":["  C. defines product or service specifications. ","  D. is part of a promotional strategy to win back customers.","22. The correct answer is D. ","Lifetime customers have a win-win relationship with the businesses they frequent. The customers gain greater satisfaction while the business enjoys decreased marketing costs and increased revenue and profit potential. Lifetime customers are not common in markets competing on price rather than added value.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. aligns customer groups with certain service levels. "},{"question":"  B. are common in commodity markets driven by price rather than value. ","choices":["  C. are increasingly more expensive for a business to maintain as they become more demanding. ","  D. have forged a win-win relationship with the business in question. ","23.  The correct answer is C. ","Every customer contact point must be analyzed to identify key players within the organization who can affect customer satisfaction and to determine what they can do to maximize the customer's experience. This requires a high level of collaboration across sections of the organization and a clear articulation throughout the organization, to every member, of this new priority. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. can increase revenue but have a neutral effect on profit. "},{"question":"  B. Replacing the chief operations officer (COO) with a chief customer officer (CCO) ","choices":["  C. Analyzing each customer contact point to determine how key players can maximize the customer's experience ","  D. Lowering production and distribution costs in order to increase customer support and marketing expenditures  ","24. The correct answer is A. ","Customer design groups are an example of open-ended information gathering used by VOC to make complex customer perceptions more visible to a business. A brief checkoff survey does not capture complex information. Analysis of behaviors and analysis by others do not present the customer's own voice.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Focusing all changes on how the sales and customer service departments, which come into direct customer contact, do business "},{"question":"  B. Collated comments of sales representatives calling on specific customer groups ","choices":["  C. Brief checkoff customer satisfaction surveys printed on invoices ","  D. Analysis of customer buying behaviors ","25. The correct answer is A. ","SRM helps ensure that demand created by CRM can be fulfilled in a manner profitable for all supply chain partners while maintaining customer satisfaction. Success of supplier relationships may be measured by various means, including time-to-market, cost efficiency, competitive advantage, and end customer satisfaction.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Customer design groups "},{"question":"  B. It focuses on gaining information about customers. ","choices":["  C. It measures success only by satisfaction of end customers. ","  D. It helps ensure the same profitability for all supply chain elements.","26.  The correct answer is A. ","Cross-selling is a CRM tactic made possible by the accumulation of data about a customer's buying habits. Customers are offered related products in addition to their current purchase.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. It focuses on meeting demand. "},{"question":"  B. a win-back program. ","choices":["  C. up-selling. ","  D. a loyalty program. ","27. The correct answer is A. ","A customer data warehouse (CDW) stores data about customers, products, and market trends, consolidating it in a manner that can facilitate future analysis to spot trends and relationships.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. cross-selling. "},{"question":"  B. Purchased data on specific customer segment ","choices":["  C. Repository of all data related to customer transactions ","  D. Current customer profiles stored in a database ","28. The correct answer is B. ","Automating business practices is typically expected to improve performance by eliminating manual processes. However, an organization will realize substantially more benefit if it first restructures its processes to best align with the supply chain network before automating.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Data about customers, products, and marketplace extracted from internal and external resources "},{"question":"  B. What business processes must change? ","choices":["  C. What application is optimal for all supply chain partners? ","  D. How will the supply chain partners collaborate? ","29.  The correct answer is D. ","Both CRM and SRM focus on gathering information but for different purposes: CRM to understand customers better and support marketing, SRM to develop and manage relationships with key partners in the supply chain. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. What type of information is to be shared? "},{"question":"  B. choosing appropriate strategic partners. ","choices":["  C. understanding buying habits of retail customers. ","  D. gathering and sharing information.","30. The correct answer is D. ","Workflow management systems automate a sequence of steps and communications that must be completed to handle a customer situation. This is especially valuable when resolving a customer's problem may involve multiple company employees. Workflow management systems allow the system users to visualize the entire relationship and share the same information about the customer at all critical service points.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. providing superior marketing decision support. "},{"question":"  B. They ensure consistency in implementing CRM policies. ","choices":["  C. They allow access to customer information and communications at critical service points. ","  D. All of the above","31. The correct answer is C. ","The key is collaborative planning across the supply chain rather than mere information sharing or single alliances.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They are a form of automated CRM. "},{"question":"  B. Creating an alliance with a key supplier ","choices":["  C. Collaborative planning across the entire supply chain ","  D. Information sharing with key partners","32.  The correct answer is A. ","A 'best cost\" analysis of risk is performed by multiplying the anticipated cost of the business disruption by the likelihood of its occurrence.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Creating individual partnerships "},{"question":"  B. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business. ","choices":["  C. adding accumulated risk associated with all strategic suppliers. ","  D. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business and dividing that by likelihood of the occurrence. ","33. The correct answer is D. ","Increased customer visibility is a benefit of CRM in that CRM helps businesses to see each point of the purchasing transaction from the customer's perspective and to understand what the customer needs and values.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. multiplying the expected cost of the risk by its likelihood. "},{"question":"  B. being aware of each point of contact between the customer and the business. ","choices":["  C. seeing the transaction from the customer's viewpoint. ","  D. all of the above. ","34.  The correct answer is C. ","The alliance manager is an individual whose job is to promote the alliance itself by sustaining relationships between partners, building joint initiatives, and bringing them to market to generate revenue and increase customers. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. knowing what each customer values. "},{"question":"  B. CEO ","choices":["  C. Alliance manager ","  D. Manager of purchasing ","35.  The correct answer is B. ","Segmenting customers is an essential part of creating a promotional strategy, one of the four Ps of traditional marketing and CRM strategies. The other choices reflect those other components of a CRM strategy: product, price, and placement.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Channel master "},{"question":"  B. Segmenting customers according to their value to the business ","choices":["  C. Creating a product and service agreement (PSA) ","  D. Deciding where to distribute one's products","36. The correct answer is A. ","Companies whose ability to meet customer demands rests on their control over the supply side of the supply chain model will be most interested in SRM. The other companies are primarily concerned with understanding and responding to customer needs and expectations.   "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Charging less if a customer orders through the Internet "},{"question":"  B. Company that performs market research for political candidates ","choices":["  C. Credit card company ","  D. Company that produces video games ","37. The correct answer is A. ","In a customer-focused world, the starting point for a product is often customer need.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Paint manufacturer that purchases chemicals and dyes from various suppliers "},{"question":"  B. identifying a price point most acceptable to lifetime customers. ","choices":["  C. identifying a new market niche. ","  D. evaluating current customer product complaints. ","38. The correct answer is B. ","Supply partners must accept and commit to the fact of change in their relationships. As conditions and individual priorities and strategies change, the processes that define the relationship should change as well. It is better if change can be accomplished incrementally.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. identifying customer need. "},{"question":"  B. No single restructuring of processes will be adequate. ","choices":["  C. Although marketplace change may be constant, the details of the relationship should not change. ","  D. The best change occurs in large movements that motivate the entire organization rather than in smaller increments.","39. The correct answer is D. ","Organizations implementing CRM and SRM must move toward greater collaboration and away from more hierarchical structures defined by task-focused responsibility centers and top-down decision making. They call for a new attitude and new skills in the existing workforce.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Relationships should not be affected by the shifting priorities of the partners. "},{"question":"  B. Greater emphasis on task-focused responsibility centers ","choices":["  C. A new workforce ","  D. New job definitions","40. The correct answer is A. ","An effective collaborative strategy must be measured to ensure its effectiveness. Processes and systems must be in place to monitor performance. Important measurements include supply chain sales, shipments, stockouts, invoicing, and payments.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Greater control from the top down "},{"question":"  B. Continuously improve. ","choices":["  C. Use supply chain assets collectively. ","  D. Understand the needs of the partners. ","41. The correct answer is B. ","External data networks are created through collaboration of partners in a supply chain and facilitate the exchange and analysis of information gathered at various points in the supply chain, from factory through distribution to call centers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Monitor performance. "},{"question":"  B. a network resulting from collaboration between the information and communication systems of a company and other members of its supply chain. ","choices":["  C. an information repository for purchased customer data. ","  D. any information system outside the business from which it may have to extract customer data. ","42. The correct answer is B. ","Traditional purchasing sees each purchase as a discrete transaction. Since strategic sourcing involves ongoing relationships, there is opportunity for collaboration between the purchaser and suppliers that can result in improving the profitability of the supply chain and adding value to the final product or service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. an outsourced CRM information management system. "},{"question":"  B. Transactional versus collaborative ","choices":["  C. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","  D. Purchase price versus true cost ","43. The correct answer is C. ","Consumers and competitors have more and faster access to information, causing market volatility. Supply chain integration provides comparable improvements in information access.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility "},{"question":"  B. Integration helps reduce conflicts of interest. ","choices":["  C. Integration helps counter consumers' and competitors' increased access to information. ","  D. Integration enables demand enhancement. ","44. The correct answer is C. ","In a dynamic marketplace, a static consultant contract without clear and flexible guidelines and processes to manage the relationship simply encourages consultants to break their connection with the company rather than redefine it.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Integration enables a global response to demands. "},{"question":"  B. preventing any sources of tension between participant organizations. ","choices":["  C. encouraging participants to redefine problematic connections rather than break them. ","  D. ensuring strict adherence to the established alliance contract by both participants","45.  The correct answer is B. ","Because of costs associated with marketing, establishing inventory, and developing the distribution system and because a customer base has not yet been acquired, the introduction phase of the product life cycle is marked by high costs but low sales.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. providing clear channels of legal redress for each participant. "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity","46. The correct answer is B. ","Commodity pricing has made it more important for businesses to streamline the supply chain and become more cost-effective. The supply chain has, in fact, consolidated rather than fragmented; global markets have grown rather than shrunk. Consolidation may necessitate strategic sourcing as the number of sources narrows. Growing global markets present opportunities but also costs and risks that must be managed.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. Commodity pricing ","choices":["  C. Greater fragmentation on both sides of the supply chain ","  D. Decreasing customer response time ","47. The correct answer is C. ","Collaborations or strategic alliances are long-term arrangements ruled more by agreements than contracts. The suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. Trust levels are high. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Shrinking global markets "},{"question":"  B. Ongoing relationship ","choices":["  C. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  D. Mergers and acquisitions","48. The correct answer is D. ","All of the answers are correct. Higher quality, made possible through technology, has created increased customer expectations, which has in turn led to price as a differentiating factor. This has created a downward pressure on profit margin. Greater customer focus helps counter this pressure  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Buy the market "},{"question":"  B. Advances in technology ","choices":["  C. Greater global competition ","  D. All of the above ","49. The correct answer is A. ","SRM focuses on identifying opportunities for strategic relationships between supply chain partners and on developing and managing those relationships. The Internet banking company is concerned primarily with customers rather than suppliers. The commodity-driven company may have some benefit, but it will be limited by the opportunities to add value. Similarly, the gift catalog company requires adequate supply at the right times but may rely on so many suppliers that strategic partnerships are not practical. The manufacturer of consumer goods will benefit from developing strategic relationships with suppliers that add value and make its products more competitive.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Higher quality of goods and services "},{"question":"  B. A gift catalog company that offers a large number of items from a wide variety of suppliers ","choices":["  C. A company competing in a commodity market with little opportunity for adding value ","  D. An Internet banking company seeking to expand use among high-value customers","50.  The correct answer is B. ","In SRM's collaborative relationships, suppliers can participate in improving the system, which results in better product, higher customer satisfaction, and better customer retention.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. A company that uses raw materials and prefabricated components to create consumer goods "},{"question":"  B. Higher customer satisfaction ","choices":["  C. Reduced marketing costs ","  D. Increased control by the alliance manager ","51. The correct answer is A. ","Customers demand a variety of products and features as well as low prices.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Cheaper products "},{"question":"  B. Manufacturers ","choices":["  C. Suppliers ","  D. Retailers ","52. The correct answer is D. ","While the computer, intranets, and advanced telephony have certainly enhanced both supplier and customer relationship management, the Internet has made the largest impact on communication with customers and between partners in the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Customers "},{"question":"  B. the intranet. ","choices":["  C. the computer. ","  D. the Internet. ","53. The correct answer is B. ","Implementing CRM and SRM does not require that companies change their core competencies, although employees may need to acquire new skills. Nor do organizations need to form common goals or mission statements. They will need, however, to revisit work processes, job definitions, and decision-making structures.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. advanced telephony features. "},{"question":"  B. revision of decision-making processes. ","choices":["  C. common business goals and mission statements for all supply chain members. ","  D. outsourcing to companies with special expertise. ","54.  The correct answer is B. ","Companies are responding to the forces of globalization, increased project complexity, and greater market volatility by investing in technology that will enable them to better manage knowledge both within and across organizations.   "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. redefinition of core competencies. "},{"question":"  B. Greater market volatility ","choices":["  C. Increased difficulties in communication and application sharing ","  D. Shrinking markets","55. The correct answer is A. ","The voice of the customer (VOC) is a customer research and measurement tool used to gain answers to complex marketing questions. VOC may include focus groups in which customers contribute to product or process design.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Increased influence of trade unions "},{"question":"  B. a method of determining customer value. ","choices":["  C. a method of customer segmentation. ","  D. including customers in key marketing decisions","56. The correct answer is A. ","Single sourcing of a key material or component is not a good example of risk management, even if the supplier is the lowest-cost provider. Good risk management may involve additional costs incurred through maintaining redundancy in the supply chain and requiring additional supplier performance or assumption of risk.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a method of customer research. "},{"question":"  B. This company sources a key raw material from one supplier who reliably provides the lowest price. ","choices":["  C. This company requires in its contracts that all suppliers use a defined third-party transportation provider for all shipments. ","  D. This company relies on the selection process as its only means of risk management. ","57. The correct answer is D. ","Many SRM tasks may be outsourced, from researching and contracting with alliance partners to development of technology. However, companies should never outsource strategic tasks or core competencies. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. This company develops detailed plans to shift work orders among several certified global suppliers in the event of labor disruptions in their countries. "},{"question":"  B. Setting corporate goals and developing strategy for alliances ","choices":["  C. Setting of procurement budgets ","  D. Contracting with strategic partners ","58. The correct answer is A. ","Before entering alliances, start identifying key issues and decisions and involving key stakeholders for fewer surprises and greater buy-in by key people. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Selection of strategic partners "},{"question":"  B. appoint a dedicated alliance manager to oversee the partner relationship. ","choices":["  C. select the proper partners by evaluating corporate culture and operating style. ","  D. establish ground rules for how partners will work together and resolve conflict.","59. The correct answer is D. ","Many suppliers feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity where price is emphasized rather than quality or the partnership.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. align internally by identifying key issues and stakeholders. "},{"question":"  B. Customer ","choices":["  C. Distributor ","  D. Supplier","60.  The correct answer is C. ","While CRM and SRM are not synonymous with technical tools (they are philosophies and competitive strategies), they are both greatly supported by technological solutions.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Internal "},{"question":"  B. The effects of technology are more significant in SRM than CRM. ","choices":["  C. Technology plays a supporting role in CRM and SRM. ","  D. All of the above","61. The correct answer is B. ","Using modern information and communication systems, distributor integration relationships allow distributors to share access to product and service.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Both CRM and SRM are essentially technological. "},{"question":"  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","choices":["  C. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  D. third-party logistics (3PL) company.","62. The correct answer is C. ","Suppliers of raw materials typically prefer flexible delivery times, large yet stable volume demands, and consistency in mix of materials.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. "},{"question":"  B. Retailers ","choices":["  C. Suppliers ","  D. Logistics managers","63. The correct answer is C. ","Pricing is influenced by many factors other than cost of production, including competitive positions, customers' willingness to pay for the value received, and consistency with the brand identity that has been created.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Warehouse managers "},{"question":"  B. Promotion ","choices":["  C. Price ","  D. Product ","64. The correct answer is A. ","Purchasing has, in fact, become more complex with the use of strategic sourcing. Roles have become more stratified, with senior-level managers focusing on strategic decisions and lower-level managers focusing on procurement and monitoring. They are aided by SRM technology, which has automated and supported many of their new tasks, such as partner research and contracting and invoice development.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Placement "},{"question":"  B. SRM technology has greatly complicated the tasks of purchasing managers and agents. ","choices":["  C. Under an SRM model, strategic decisions such as selection of alliance partners are pushed down to subordinate purchasing roles. ","  D. Strategic sourcing has greatly simplified the tasks associated with purchasing.","65. The correct answer is D. ","Good CRM technology is easy to use and meets customer expectations. Successful implementation of CRM technology rests on a clear, well-thought-out architecture. Rather than inhibiting change, good design enhances integration and lessens the chances of conflicts as the system evolves. Since it may involve redefining jobs, implementation teams should be cross-functional.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Purchasing roles have become more layered between strategic management and buying. "},{"question":"  B. If technology is optimal, job responsibilities may remain static in the new system. ","choices":["  C. Implementation teams should represent technological areas only. ","  D. Systems should be measured against whether they increase efficiency and meet customer expectations. ","66. The correct answer is A. ","Customer segmentation allows businesses to learn customer desires and habits and design more effective promotional programs. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Detailed architecture design at an early stage may lead to an inflexible system that is difficult to change. "},{"question":"  B. Shorter sales cycle ","choices":["  C. Lower production costs ","  D. Shorter time-to-market ","67. The correct answer is B. ","The Pareto principle posits that a small percentage of the customer base (usually about or less than 20 percent) accounts for a large proportion of a company's revenue or profit (80 percent or more).   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Better ROI on promotion budgets "},{"question":"  B. about or less than 20 percent of the customer base. ","choices":["  C. about or less than 40 percent of the customer base. ","  D. about or less than 80 percent of the customer base","68. The correct answer is A. ","Retailers need short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround times "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. less than 10 percent of the customer base. "},{"question":"  B. Suppliers ","choices":["  C. Manufacturers ","  D. Warehousers ","69. The correct answer is A. ","ISO certification is a globally recognized process that certifying companies must update every three years. Since it is industry- rather than business-specific, it often complements a business's own certification process. ISO certification may be a requirement for suppliers, but because of the certification's broad criteria it is usually not the only requirement in the certification process.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Retailers "},{"question":"  B. ISO certification is a one-time process. ","choices":["  C. Because of their depth, ISO standards can often be used in place of a company's own supplier criteria in the supplier certification process. ","  D. ISO certification has limited recognition globally.","70. The correct answer is A. ","A cross-functional organization is one that enjoys cooperation between internal groups, especially IT and operations.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. ISO certification may be one criterion a supplier must meet in a larger certification process. "},{"question":"  B. farseeing. ","choices":["  C. able to lead. ","  D. change-oriented","71. The correct answer is B. ","In a virtual organization, there is integration of many systems and extensive sharing of information, often proprietary information. Forming virtual organizations thus requires trust and a cultural shift that embraces the common identity of the virtual organization. At the same time, the member organizations must evaluate the risk of the relationship and preserve their own identity and integrity.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. cross-functional. "},{"question":"  B. Individual organizations must preserve their own identity and integrity. ","choices":["  C. Information belonging to member organizations remains proprietary. ","  D. Customers perceive the member organizations as distinct entities. ","72. The correct answer is D. ","Generally, customers who resort to this tactic feel that they have not been heard by the \"offending\" business and that attempts have not been made to address their problems. This is a failure of customer communication and customer care rather than brand identity, specific communication media, or competitors' activities.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Member organizations retain their original, distinctive cultures and values. "},{"question":"  B. development of brand identity. ","choices":["  C. monitoring of competitive activities. ","  D. none of the above. ","73．The correct answer is C. ","Data purchased from companies such as database marketing companies provide information about customers outside a company's own customer base. These data are useful in reaching new customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. managing media for customer communication. "},{"question":"  B. They can be very broad. ","choices":["  C. They may be more useful in new customer acquisition. ","  D. They are very useful in managing relationships with existing customers. ","74. The correct answer is A. ","Direct shipping from the warehouse to the customer's home lowers costs by storing inventory at a centrally located warehouse rather than at the retail location. Customer service is improved by allowing a larger selection of inventory and providing front-door delivery service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They paint a picture of a business's own customers. "},{"question":"  B. By enabling delayed differentiation ","choices":["  C. By supporting factory-distributor-retailer-customer distribution pathways ","  D. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","75. The correct answer is C. ","An ongoing relationship involves repeated transactions, perhaps regulated through medium-term contracts. Communication is funneled through an account manager, who adjusts in all interactions to the customer's culture and way of doing business.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By enabling direct shipping from warehouse to customer's home "},{"question":"  B. Mergers and acquisitions ","choices":["  C. Ongoing relationship ","  D. Buy the market ","76. The correct answer is B. ","Increased supply chain visibility can lessen the bullwhip effect and enable early problem detection, faster response and better contingency planning, and stronger relationships because of increased trust.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Collaborations/strategic alliance "},{"question":"  B. Enables faster response and better contingency planning ","choices":["  C. Lowers the number of required distributors ","  D. Reduces customer service calls","77. The correct answer is B. ","SFA tools assist sales representatives in various tasks from organizing contacts, tracking opportunities, and accessing product knowledge and details of current promotions (although not the analysis of promotion effects). Service cyber agents are an automated form of answering customer queries, and universal queue is a way of automating inbound customer contact.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Simplifies market segmentation "},{"question":"  B. Tracking applications for evolving sales opportunities ","choices":["  C. Promotional program analytics ","  D. Service cyber agents ","78. The correct answer is D. ","While the other options are also valuable SRM tools, data warehousing and mining allow sharing of information between applications and partners.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Universal queue "},{"question":"  B. Web-based procurement ","choices":["  C. Satellite-based tracking of transportation assets ","  D. Data warehousing and mining applications","79. The correct answer is A. ","\"Buy the market\" is a traditional approach to purchasing, in which organizations buy in response to immediate needs, choosing freely from among all the suppliers who can meet those needs and sharing technical purchasing requirements rather than strategies or plans.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Wireless communication "},{"question":"  B. Ongoing relationship ","choices":["  C. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  D. Mergers and acquisitions","80. The correct answer is D. ","A PSA between partners should be mutually beneficial. It may be customized, should precede pilot and full implementation, and should always be measured for improvement.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Buy the market "},{"question":"  B. PSAs should be standardized for all suppliers. ","choices":["  C. The PSA is crafted only after a carefully conducted pilot program. ","  D. The negotiated PSA must be mutually beneficial for both partners.","81. The correct answer is A. ","This company is probably a third-party logistics provider, a company that performs all or part of an organization's procurement of materials and distribution.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The PSA is not subject to standard strategic goal metrics. "},{"question":"  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","choices":["  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","82. The correct answer is B. ","While in the past the strategic focus for many organizations was to improve their internal quality and reduce costs, the new focus is on implementing total supply chain solutions that require collaboration from partner organizations both upstream and downstream.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. third-party logistics (3PL) company. "},{"question":"  B. The focus has shifted from internal quality improvement and cost reduction to collaborative solutions up and down the supply chain. ","choices":["  C. The focus has shifted from inventory management to demand enhancement. ","  D. The focus has shifted from brick-and-mortar solutions to Web-based solutions. ","83. The correct answer is C. ","Supplier rating systems take an approach similar to certification in setting supplier performance standards, measuring performance against those standards, and taking steps to improve supplier performance. However, they incorporate data from supply chain information systems and occur more frequently (sometimes in an ongoing, real-time manner) to paint a picture of ongoing performance levels.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The focus has shifted from human resource-based solutions to technology-driven solutions. "},{"question":"  B. Supplier rating systems measure performance at predefined intervals. ","choices":["  C. Supplier rating systems occur more frequently to capture ongoing performance levels. ","  D. Certification programs take steps to improve supplier performance. ","84. The correct answer is C. ","From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Certification programs incorporate data from supply chain information systems. "},{"question":"  B. Building organizational expertise ","choices":["  C. The number of suppliers able to provide the component ","  D. Opening new markets ","85. The correct answer is D. ","A virtual organization is a long-term strategic alliance of separate business entities that presents itself to third parties as a single entity.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Adding value to products "},{"question":"  B. Merger of two competitors ","choices":["  C. Company that sells only services, not products ","  D. Strategic alliance of four companies to develop a new drug product and market it under the name of one of the companies ","86. The correct answer is A. ","In a quick response model, the retailer continues to order from the supplier, although the supplier may collect POS data for the purposes of planning and forecasting.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Raw materials supplier that agrees to supply product for an upcoming production cycle "},{"question":"  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","choices":["  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above. ","87. The correct answer is A. ","Fourth-party logistics providers are often found in global markets where they can combine the resources of suppliers and often 3PLs to meet the challenges of time zone, geographical, and cultural differences.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a quick response inventory management model. "},{"question":"  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","choices":["  C. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","88. The correct answer is A. ","Lifetime customers increase the need for CRM, but they also make it a little easier as the business learns more about them over time. Total marketing costs decline, satisfaction increases with better customer understanding, and both revenue and profit increase.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. "},{"question":"  B. They increase total marketing costs. ","choices":["  C. They are more difficult to satisfy than first-time or short-term customers. ","  D. They tend to have a null effect on revenue but a positive effect on profit.","89. The correct answer is B. ","Alliance relationships are marked by organization integration at many points in the partners' organizations, from information systems through marketing and sales to finance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They increase the need for CRM activities. "},{"question":"  B. Alliances are relationships between two or more partners in the supply chain. ","choices":["  C. In alliance relationships, flexibility is not a good thing. Processes must be rigidly followed and enforced. ","  D. Despite potential benefits, there has been little growth in the development of strategic alliances","90. The correct answer is C. ","A loyalty program simultaneously rewards repeat or high-value customers and encourages continued business through special incentives.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Alliance relationships are marked by organizational integration at a few critical points. "},{"question":"  B. Introductory rates ","choices":["  C. Free shipping for high-volume customers ","  D. Customer profiling system ","91. The correct answer is D. ","Data mining is the process of studying data to search for previously unknown relationships.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. \"Buy one, get two\" offer "},{"question":"  B. developing a PSA. ","choices":["  C. data warehousing. ","  D. data mining.","92. The correct answer is C. ","In mergers and acquisitions, suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity. Business goals are shared; business areas participate in setting strategy and planning integration of capabilities, processes, and information. Competition has been eliminated.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. setting a channel strategy. "},{"question":"  B. Buy the market ","choices":["  C. Mergers and acquisitions ","  D. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","93. The correct answer is C. ","All those affected by the SRM strategy should be informed and trained before the program is piloted.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Ongoing relationship "},{"question":"  B. Developing a PSA to define deliverables ","choices":["  C. Delaying training and corporate communication of the strategy until after pilot program results are identified ","  D. Conducting a pilot study ","94. The correct answer is A. ","Customer segment mapping is a key component of implementing CRM strategy since it leads to a better understanding of customer values and needs and increased potential for success in responding to those values and needs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Performing a Pareto analysis of all suppliers "},{"question":"  B. demographic analysis. ","choices":["  C. market prioritization. ","  D. predictive analysis","95. The correct answer is D. ","Development of the PSA, procedures to handle all customer interactions, infrastructure (people and information) to perform the procedures, and metrics to measure success are all parts of a successful customer service management strategy. Customer interaction scenarios are determined by customer needs, not by existing infrastructure. Specific responses should be developed and followed. Service levels may be customized for different customer segments.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. customer segment mapping. "},{"question":"  B. Restricting customer interactions to a limited set of defined scenarios that may be performed within the existing infrastructure ","choices":["  C. Delivering consistent and identical customer service to all customer segments ","  D. Development of a product and service agreement (PSA) ","96. The correct answer is C. ","SRM focuses on the supply side of the supply chain to ensure that customer demands can be met with a high degree of satisfaction but also with mutual profitability for all suppliers. Relationships using SRM are marked by a high degree of integration of processes and even information systems. SRM may not be appropriate in relationships with all suppliers but rather with suppliers considered key partners in maintaining the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Developing a general system but allowing flexibility to customer service personnel to develop specific procedures "},{"question":"  B. Philosophy applied equally to all suppliers ","choices":["  C. Way to ensure mutual profitability while meeting marketplace needs ","  D. Provides fuller communication without actual integration ","97. The correct answer is A. ","Organizations' internal members are sometimes hesitant initially to trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share what they value as important internal information or data. While most organizations are open to receiving information regarding best practices from partner organizations, they are typically not willing to reciprocate by sharing equal information.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Tool to align the customer voice with the product produced "},{"question":"  B. Customer ","choices":["  C. Distributor ","  D. Supplier ","98. The correct answer is C. ","In general, CRM benefits the supply chain by creating and maintaining demand for products and services.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Internal "},{"question":"  B. eliminating volatility in orders of raw materials. ","choices":["  C. creating and maintaining demand. ","  D. ensuring supply at the retail level.","99. The correct answer is A. ","If CRM vendors train their employees in the client's business and products and if they have adequate resources, they can convey the impression of seamless customer service. CRM may be outsourced for various reasons. Cost is not the only consideration; vendors may offer advanced capabilities, for example. Information gained by one vendor should be shared with all vendors to create a learning organization.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. aligning distributors with retailers. "},{"question":"  B. The only good reason for outsourcing CRM is cost savings. ","choices":["  C. CRM should not be outsourced. ","  D. Separation of CRM vendors should be strictly enforced to protect the outsourcing business's autonomy.","100．The correct answer is B. ","The most accurate answer is that a vulnerable customer is one who is about to stop being a customer. This may be due to factors described in some of the incorrect choices. A vulnerable customer may perceive little value in the relationship, may have developed little loyalty, and may be willing to try a competitor. A customer with obsolete product who does not receive customer care may soon become vulnerable.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. CRM vendors may provide seamless customer service. "},{"question":"  B. is about to discontinue service or stop purchasing the brand products. ","choices":["  C. the competition has been selling intensively. ","  D. is segmented into a low-value group and offered little incentive. ","101. The correct answer is D. ","The five best practices for supply chains are strategic sourcing and supplier management, operations and logistics, customer relationship management and channels, information technology, and change management.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. has bought product that is becoming obsolete. "},{"question":"  B. Outsourcing operations and logistics ","choices":["  C. Maximizing profits ","  D. Strategic sourcing and supplier management ","102. The correct answer is B. ","To achieve certification's highest potential, companies must clearly communicate what they will be measuring and how. Criteria should be consistent from one supplier to the next. The outcome can be used not only for selection but also for supplier improvement. Companies usually opt to pursue the certification process only with actual or key suppliers.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Advertising and sales analysis "},{"question":"  B. Suppliers should be clearly informed of criteria and processes to be used in the certification process. ","choices":["  C. All potential suppliers should go through the certification process. ","  D. Certification is a supplier selection tool only. ","103. The correct answer is B. ","Pricing is generally a strategic decision, based on competition, perceived value, and brand identity. Strategic pricing must be carefully and frequently analyzed to ensure that the pricing structure is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Criteria should be adjusted to individual suppliers' capabilities. "},{"question":"  B. must be continually analyzed to ensure that it is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business. ","choices":["  C. must be consistent across targeted customer segments. ","  D. is calculated by adding a competitive profit margin to the total costs of creation, sales, and overhead.","104. The correct answer is C. ","A virtual organization is best described as a short-term alliance of independent businesses for a potentially long-term relationship. Businesses cooperate to design, create, and distribute product (including services) based on shared values and are perceived by third parties as a single entity.  . "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. is calculated by a sliding scale based upon customers' ability to pay. "},{"question":"  B. Merger of separate entities with common business values and goals to gain better market position ","choices":["  C. Potentially long-term relationship between separate business entities to design, produce, and distribute a product ","  D. Separate entities that collaborate to design and sell intangible products and services ","105. The correct answer is C. ","Forging supplier relationships represents an investment that must be protected by developing ways to identify potential and actual conflicts, resolve them without endangering the relationship, and learning from the conflict.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Short-term tactical alliance in which partnering companies remain distinct and visible to end users "},{"question":"  B. structuring communication and decision making so that conflicts do not occur. ","choices":["  C. a conflict resolution model. ","  D. maintaining separate decision-making structures to avoid conflicts. ","106. The correct answer is A. ","A collaborative transportation network allows trading partners to share their transportation assets through aligning transportation needs with assets in real time.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. defining an early point at which to dissolve a troubled relationship. "},{"question":"  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","choices":["  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. distributor integration (DI) network.","107. The correct answer is B. ","Proactive reasons an organization should consider a strategic alliance are the alliance's ability to add value to products, enable strategic growth, increase market access, strengthen operations, increase organizational expertise, build organizational skills, and enhance financial strength.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. "},{"question":"  B. improving time to market or increasing quality. ","choices":["  C. a sourcing relationship's potential to jeopardize attaining business objectives. ","  D. strategic importance of the component being purchased. ","108. The correct answer is C. ","Contact channel strategy may include the choice of advertising media and designing a distribution system, but it includes more concerns and is more interactive than those choices suggest. The contact channel strategy should address both contacting customers and being contacted by customers.  . "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. complexity of the component's interface with the final product. "},{"question":"  B. selection of key distributors of service or product. ","choices":["  C. designing a two-way communication architecture between customers and businesses. ","  D. none of the above.","109. The correct answer is D. ","Companies that can benefit from knowing more about the end customer or shaping the needs and wants of the end customer will be most interested in CRM. The manufacturer of power tools must design, manufacture, and sell tools that appeal to customers. The other companies are suppliers that must satisfy a purchaser's technical qualifications or expectations.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. choosing media for advertising. "},{"question":"  B. Company that manufactures testing equipment for a laboratory builder ","choices":["  C. Company that fabricates fiberglass insulation for a heating equipment manufacturer ","  D. Manufacturer of power tools","110. The correct answer is C. ","With shorter lead and cycle times, the level of safety stock may be reduced, which leads to savings by reducing inventory levels and obsolescence costs.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Company that develops billing application software for a health-care provider "},{"question":"  B. shortening cycle times.    ","choices":["  C. lowering inventory levels and reducing costs. ","  D. enhancing demand.","111. The correct answer is D. ","SRM is a methodology to structure and support relationships with suppliers that will assist in reducing procurement and excess inventory costs, supporting a customer-focused business that delivers product/service customization and quality in the desired time frame, and improving processes in an ongoing manner.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. improving the ability to anticipate needs and convey benefits. "},{"question":"  B. Improving depth of purchased parts knowledge ","choices":["  C. Targeting suppliers for cross-selling and up-selling opportunities ","  D. Reducing procurement and excess inventory costs ","112. The correct answer is C. ","Rates, such as number of floor failures, rejected materials, or delays in shipment, are used to compile reports of supplier performance but are not themselves reports. Reporting mechanisms include such tools as scorecards, performance failure alerts (which are online and in real time), and surveys. A certification indicates that a supplier has met criteria but does not report ongoing performance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Focusing on cost of materials and components "},{"question":"  B. a rejected materials rate. ","choices":["  C. an automated performance alert. ","  D. a floor failure event rate.","113. The correct answer is B. ","While businesses may employ customer segmentation, competitive differentiation, and niche marketing to appeal to customers, this strategy describes the creation of lifetime customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a certification document. "},{"question":"  B. creating lifetime customers. ","choices":["  C. competitive differentiation. ","  D. customer segmentation.","114. The correct answer is A. ","Cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include costs of hardware, software, overhead, and consulting fees.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. niche marketing. "},{"question":"  B. What are the hardware expenses? ","choices":["  C. Are there consulting fees involved? ","  D. What are the overhead expenses?","115. The correct answer is D. ","Retailers may also choose to combine shipments from different manufacturers in a process called cross-docking. Decision support systems enable the supply chain to find a suitable balance between transportation and delivery costs by considering all aspects of the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. How profitable are each of the partner SCM organizations? "},{"question":"  B. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","choices":["  C. By enabling delayed differentiation ","  D. By combining shipments through cross-docking","116. The correct answer is B. ","Customer segmentation predates CRM but in the past relied heavily on demographic segmentation, which does not use actual customer buying behavior as CRM segmentation methods do. Customer segmentation can increase both revenue and profitability for retail as well as B2B customers.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By reducing lead times "},{"question":"  B. Demographic segmentation is not based on data about actual customer buying behaviors. ","choices":["  C. Customer segmentation may help increase revenue but is not a tool for increasing profitability. ","  D. Customer segmentation is a concept introduced in CRM. ","117. The correct answer is A. ","In this arrangement, the manufacturer receives better information about market demand, enabling more efficient production and better inventory management, thereby reducing costs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Customer segmentation does not apply well to business (B2B) customers. "},{"question":"  B. lengthening intervals between restocking. ","choices":["  C. shortening production times. ","  D. enhancing demand.","118. The correct answer is B. ","Customer-focused businesses try to make their customers feel better educated about what they are buying before, during, and after the purchase. They promote sharing of information about the customer throughout the supply chain, appreciate the need to consider customer needs in designing as well as marketing and distributing products, and maintain communication and distribution strategies that value convenience for the customer more than profitability.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. reducing costs. "},{"question":"  B. educates customers throughout the purchasing process. ","choices":["  C. focuses on customer care rather than product/service design and delivery. ","  D. gathers information about the customer but restricts its use to critical points in the supply chain. ","119. The correct answer is A. ","Up-selling is a CRM tactic in which customers are offered higher-priced or more profitable items instead of the item they were originally considering. The operator in this case may be supported by a workflow that suggests specific models and links to more data in an electronic catalog or data about the customer's previous purchases that suggest a tendency toward higher-priced purchases.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. restricts communication and distribution channels to the most profitable options. "},{"question":"  B. cross-selling. ","choices":["  C. a win-back program. ","  D. a loyalty program.","120. The correct answer is B. ","In a continuous replenishment model, suppliers are notified daily of actual sales or warehouse shipments and commit to replenishing inventory without receiving purchase orders.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. up-selling. "},{"question":"  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","choices":["  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above. ","121. The correct answer is D. ","The product component of a CRM strategy refers to all those actions taken to craft products and services that relate to customer needs, opportunities to add value in the supply chain and enhance competitive position, and still meet profit objectives. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a quick response inventory management model. "},{"question":"  B. Placement ","choices":["  C. Price ","  D. Product ","122. The correct answer is D. ","CTMs can deliver all of these benefits by aligning transportation needs with transportation assets to eliminate inefficiencies, such as wait time, half-filled loads, or empty backhauls (\"deadheading\").   "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Promotion "},{"question":"  B. Optimization of weight and volume capacity of network resources ","choices":["  C. Increase in backhaul opportunities for carriers ","  D. All of the above","123. The correct answer is B. ","There is a distinction between price and total cost of ownership. For example, a manufacturer of electronics may choose a component based on the lowest price, but that choice may not translate into low cost if the low-priced components are not reliable and fail early.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Reduction of carriers' wait time for loading and unloading "},{"question":"  B. Purchase price versus total cost of ownership ","choices":["  C. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","  D. Transactional versus collaborative ","124. The correct answer is C. ","An interorganizational team conducts an assessment to analyze demand, supply, competition, and systems as well as to determine what features will set this supply chain network apart within the targeted market. The team also creates a plan for combining best practices across the network and formulates a strategic plan.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows "},{"question":"  B. Identify place and promotion in a strategic plan. ","choices":["  C. Create a plan for combining best practices across the network. ","  D. Designate the initiative's channel master. ","125. The correct answer is A. ","After determining the nature and costs of potential disruptions, organizations assemble a desirable risk portfolio that balances risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Determine profits the new supply chain network will generate within the targeted market. "},{"question":"  B. Identify current risk-prone partnerships that should be severed. ","choices":["  C. Eliminate risks by predicting their likely sources. ","  D. Identify those risk costs that can shifted to a partner's portfolio.","126. The correct answer is C. ","Information gathered in the CRM process is used to support service to customers and potential customers and sales and marketing decisions, not resource and production planning.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Balance risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation. "},{"question":"  B. Solely a marketing philosophy ","choices":["  C. Tool to support existing and potential customer needs ","  D. Tool to manage marketing, sales, supply planning, and production scheduling ","127. The correct answer is A. ","CRM focuses on learning more about one's customers and using this knowledge to enhance product, increase customer satisfaction, and improve revenue and profit. The company with the diverse customer base can potentially benefit greatly from being able to gather and use more information about its customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Focused on forecasting and analysis of information "},{"question":"  B. A company that performs purchasing for a large manufacturer from several strategic suppliers ","choices":["  C. A company that provides raw materials for an extended supply chain in which value is added at later points in the chain ","  D. A company with one large customer who specifies product/service features ","128. The correct answer is B. ","In a commodity market, goods are distinguished primarily by lowest price and greatest availability, which creates downward pressure on profit.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. A company with a customer base with diverse needs and interests "},{"question":"  B. Businesses compete primarily on price and availability of goods. ","choices":["  C. Competition is limited. ","  D. Businesses have greater opportunities for maintaining profit margins","129. The correct answer is C. ","A chief customer officer may supervise management of customer dissatisfaction, but the job entails more activities, including identifying customer touch points, defining and enforcing service standards, enriching the customer experience, and helping customers navigate within the organization.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Goods are sold based on added value. "},{"question":"  B. assigning account managers to high-value customers. ","choices":["  C. identifying and responding to customer care opportunities. ","  D. identifying opportunities for enhancing revenue and profit through customer interactions","130. The correct answer is B. ","In mergers and acquisitions, suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity. Business goals are shared; business areas participate in setting strategy and planning integration of capabilities, processes, and information. Competition has been eliminated. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. responding to customer dissatisfaction. "},{"question":"  B. Mergers and acquisitions ","choices":["  C. Ongoing relationship ","  D. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","131. The correct answer is B. ","External data networks are created through collaboration of partners in a supply chain and facilitate the exchange and analysis of information gathered at various points in the supply chain, from factory through distribution to call centers. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Buy the market "},{"question":"  B. a network resulting from collaboration between the information and communication systems of a company and other members of its supply chain. ","choices":["  C. an information repository for purchased customer data. ","  D. any information system outside the business from which it may have to extract customer data.","132. The correct answer is B. ","The five best practices for supply chains are strategic sourcing and supplier management, operations and logistics, customer relationship management and channels, information technology, and change management.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. an outsourced CRM information management system. "},{"question":"  B. Strategic sourcing and supplier management ","choices":["  C. Maximizing profits ","  D. Outsourcing operations and logistics","133. The correct answer is B. ","Pricing is generally a strategic decision, based on competition, perceived value, and brand identity. Strategic pricing must be carefully and frequently analyzed to ensure that the pricing structure is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Advertising and sales analysis "},{"question":"  B. must be continually analyzed to ensure that it is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business. ","choices":["  C. is calculated by adding a competitive profit margin to the total costs of creation, sales, and overhead. ","  D. is calculated by a sliding scale based upon customers' ability to pay. ","134. The correct answer is A. ","The most accurate answer is that a vulnerable customer is one who is about to stop being a customer. This may be due to factors described in some of the incorrect choices. A vulnerable customer may perceive little value in the relationship, may have developed little loyalty, and may be willing to try a competitor. A customer with obsolete product who does not receive customer care may soon become vulnerable.   "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. must be consistent across targeted customer segments. "},{"question":"  B. is segmented into a low-value group and offered little incentive. ","choices":["  C. the competition has been selling intensively. ","  D. has bought product that is becoming obsolete","135 The correct answer is C. ","Retailers may also choose to combine shipments from different manufacturers in a process called cross-docking. Decision support systems enable the supply chain to find a suitable balance between transportation and delivery costs by considering all aspects of the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. is about to discontinue service or stop purchasing the brand products. "},{"question":"  B. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","choices":["  C. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  D. By enabling delayed differentiation ","136. The correct answer is B. ","Because of costs associated with marketing, establishing inventory, and developing the distribution system and because a customer base has not yet been acquired, the introduction phase of the product life cycle is marked by high costs but low sales.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By reducing lead times "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity","137. The correct answer is C. ","Effective supplier performance measurement systems track the performance of a broad portion of the supply chain base; collaborate with suppliers on performance measurements, reporting, and improvements; automate key supplier performance measurement activities; and standardize supplier performance measurement procedures across the organization.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. They track the performance of a narrowly defined portion of the supply chain base. ","choices":["  C. They automate key supplier performance measurement activities. ","  D. Their performance measurements, reporting, and improvements should be unilaterally defined by the purchasing organization","138. The correct answer is B. ","Consumers and competitors have more and faster access to information, causing market volatility. Supply chain integration provides comparable improvements in information access.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They enable each department within an organization to define its own supplier performance measurement procedures. "},{"question":"  B. Integration helps counter consumers' and competitors' increased access to information. ","choices":["  C. Integration enables demand enhancement. ","  D. Integration helps reduce conflicts of interest.","139. The correct answer is B. ","Customer segmentation allows businesses to learn customer desires and habits and design more effective promotional programs. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Integration enables a global response to demands. "},{"question":"  B. Better ROI on promotion budgets ","choices":["  C. Shorter time-to-market ","  D. Shorter sales cycle","140. The correct answer is B. ","A customer data warehouse (CDW) stores data about customers, products, and market trends, consolidating it in a manner that can facilitate future analysis to spot trends and relationships.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Lower production costs "},{"question":"  B. Data about customers, products, and marketplace extracted from internal and external resources ","choices":["  C. Repository of all data related to customer transactions ","  D. Purchased data on specific customer segment ","141. The correct answer is D. ","Traditional purchasing sees each purchase as a discrete transaction. Since strategic sourcing involves ongoing relationships, there is opportunity for collaboration between the purchaser and suppliers that can result in improving the profitability of the supply chain and adding value to the final product or service.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Current customer profiles stored in a database "},{"question":"  B. Purchase price versus true cost ","choices":["  C. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","  D. Transactional versus collaborative ","142. The correct answer is A. ","As with any technological solution, systems may be underpowered, overly complex, poorly designed, or just not right for the job at hand. In general, more systems today are designed to be open, information is more accessible, and software solutions are more easily customized to specific settings. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility "},{"question":"  B. Inability to customize off-the-shelf solutions ","choices":["  C. Open system infrastructures ","  D. Difficulty in accessing information","143. The correct answer is C. ","Good CRM technology is easy to use and meets customer expectations. Successful implementation of CRM technology rests on a clear, well-thought-out architecture. Rather than inhibiting change, good design enhances integration and lessens the chances of conflicts as the system evolves. Since it may involve redefining jobs, implementation teams should be cross-functional.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Underpowered, overly complex, or poorly designed solutions "},{"question":"  B. Implementation teams should represent technological areas only. ","choices":["  C. Systems should be measured against whether they increase efficiency and meet customer expectations. ","  D. If technology is optimal, job responsibilities may remain static in the new system. ","144. The correct answer is D. ","Supplier rating systems take an approach similar to certification in setting supplier performance standards, measuring performance against those standards, and taking steps to improve supplier performance. However, they incorporate data from supply chain information systems and occur more frequently (sometimes in an ongoing, real-time manner) to paint a picture of ongoing performance levels.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Detailed architecture design at an early stage may lead to an inflexible system that is difficult to change. "},{"question":"  B. Certification programs incorporate data from supply chain information systems. ","choices":["  C. Certification programs take steps to improve supplier performance. ","  D. Supplier rating systems occur more frequently to capture ongoing performance levels. ","145. The correct answer is B. ","A chief customer officer may supervise management of customer dissatisfaction, but the job entails more activities, including identifying customer touch points, defining and enforcing service standards, enriching the customer experience, and helping customers navigate within the organization.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Supplier rating systems measure performance at predefined intervals. "},{"question":"  B. identifying and responding to customer care opportunities. ","choices":["  C. assigning account managers to high-value customers. ","  D. identifying opportunities for enhancing revenue and profit through customer interactions.","146.  The correct answer is B. ","A loyalty program simultaneously rewards repeat or high-value customers and encourages continued business through special incentives. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. responding to customer dissatisfaction. "},{"question":"  B. Free shipping for high-volume customers ","choices":["  C. \"Buy one, get two\" offer ","  D. Customer profiling system ","147. The correct answer is C. ","Forging supplier relationships represents an investment that must be protected by developing ways to identify potential and actual conflicts, resolve them without endangering the relationship, and learning from the conflict.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Introductory rates "},{"question":"  B. defining an early point at which to dissolve a troubled relationship. ","choices":["  C. a conflict resolution model. ","  D. maintaining separate decision-making structures to avoid conflicts. ","148. The correct answer is C. ","Purchasing has, in fact, become more complex with the use of strategic sourcing. Roles have become more stratified, with senior-level managers focusing on strategic decisions and lower-level managers focusing on procurement and monitoring. They are aided by SRM technology, which has automated and supported many of their new tasks, such as partner research and contracting and invoice development.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. structuring communication and decision making so that conflicts do not occur. "},{"question":"  B. Strategic sourcing has greatly simplified the tasks associated with purchasing. ","choices":["  C. Purchasing roles have become more layered between strategic management and buying. ","  D. Under an SRM model, strategic decisions such as selection of alliance partners are pushed down to subordinate purchasing roles. ","149. The correct answer is B. ","In a virtual organization, there is integration of many systems and extensive sharing of information, often proprietary information. Forming virtual organizations thus requires trust and a cultural shift that embraces the common identity of the virtual organization. At the same time, the member organizations must evaluate the risk of the relationship and preserve their own identity and integrity.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. SRM technology has greatly complicated the tasks of purchasing managers and agents. "},{"question":"  B. Individual organizations must preserve their own identity and integrity. ","choices":["  C. Member organizations retain their original, distinctive cultures and values. ","  D. Information belonging to member organizations remains proprietary. ","150. The correct answer is D. ","Workflow management systems automate a sequence of steps and communications that must be completed to handle a customer situation. This is especially valuable when resolving a customer's problem may involve multiple company employees. Workflow management systems allow the system users to visualize the entire relationship and share the same information about the customer at all critical service points.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Customers perceive the member organizations as distinct entities. "},{"question":"  B. They ensure consistency in implementing CRM policies. ","choices":["  C. They allow access to customer information and communications at critical service points. ","  D. All of the above","151. The correct answer is A. ","Although vendors may suggest inventory levels, retailers must approve initial levels. After that point, levels will be maintained by the vendor according to an agreement and models based on POS and shipment data for greatest customer satisfaction and return on inventory. Data can be tied into planning processes so that MPSs can be created and MRPs set.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They are a form of automated CRM. "},{"question":"  B. Retailers have no hand in setting initial inventory; historical data are used. ","choices":["  C. Retailers maintain oversight on ordering. ","  D. Inventory data cannot be tied to MPS or MRP. ","152. The correct answer is B. ","Alliance relationships are marked by organization integration at many points in the partners' organizations, from information systems through marketing and sales to finance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Inventory levels can be adjusted according to different variables. "},{"question":"  B. Alliances are relationships between two or more partners in the supply chain. ","choices":["  C. Alliance relationships are marked by organizational integration at a few critical points. ","  D. Despite potential benefits, there has been little growth in the development of strategic alliances","153. The correct answer is A. ","\"Buy the market\" is a traditional approach to purchasing, in which organizations buy in response to immediate needs, choosing freely from among all the suppliers who can meet those needs and sharing technical purchasing requirements rather than strategies or plans.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. In alliance relationships, flexibility is not a good thing. Processes must be rigidly followed and enforced. "},{"question":"  B. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","choices":["  C. Mergers and acquisitions ","  D. Ongoing relationship ","154. The correct answer is D. ","Purchasing managers focus on strategic tasks such as supplier selection, contract negotiation, and analysis and evaluation of the supply system. Purchasing agents or planners focus on placing orders, following up with suppliers as needed, monitoring supply needs, and measuring supplier performance "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Buy the market "},{"question":"  B. Selecting suppliers ","choices":["  C. Analyzing value of supply process ","  D. Order placement ","155. The correct answer is C. ","In a commodity market, goods are distinguished primarily by lowest price and greatest availability, which creates downward pressure on profit.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Negotiating contracts with strategic sourcing partners "},{"question":"  B. Businesses have greater opportunities for maintaining profit margins. ","choices":["  C. Businesses compete primarily on price and availability of goods. ","  D. Competition is limited.","156. The correct answer is A. ","Fourth-party logistics providers are often found in global markets where they can combine the resources of suppliers and often 3PLs to meet the challenges of time zone, geographical, and cultural differences.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Goods are sold based on added value. "},{"question":"  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","choices":["  C. distributor integration (DI) network. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","157. The correct answer is C. ","One of the reasons to establish metrics and then monitor performance is to identify opportunities to improve supplier performance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. "},{"question":"  B. achieve annual cost reduction of 10 percent. ","choices":["  C. monitor and identify opportunities for improvement. ","  D. penalize partners who do not adhere to agreed rules. ","158. The correct answer is D. ","Manufacturing organizations strive for high production output and low production costs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. achieve 50 percent adherence and adaptation by all partners. "},{"question":"  B. Customers ","choices":["  C. Suppliers ","  D. Manufacturers","159. The correct answer is D. ","Information sharing benefits organizations by improving forecasts, improving coordination of manufacturing and distribution systems and strategies, reducing lead times, and accelerating reactions to marketing data. Information technology costs may increase but are offset by other benefits. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Retailers "},{"question":"  B. Lower information technology cost ","choices":["  C. Reduced forecast accuracy ","  D. Lower shortage costs ","160．The correct answer is A. ","During the development phase of the product life cycle, CRM businesses research customer needs and expectations and incorporate this research into product design and the entire CRM strategy (i.e., price, placement, promotional message).  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Increased warehousing capacities "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity","161. The correct answer is B. ","Customers demand a variety of products and features as well as low prices.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. Customers ","choices":["  C. Retailers ","  D. Suppliers ","162. The correct answer is C. ","Proactive reasons for an organization to consider a strategic alliance are the alliance's ability to add value to products, enable strategic growth, increase market access, strengthen operations, increase organizational expertise, build organizational skills, and enhance financial strength.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Manufacturers "},{"question":"  B. Acquiring technological expertise in weaker areas of the company ","choices":["  C. Improving time to market or increasing quality ","  D. Improving management compensation programs","163. The correct answer is C. ","It is reasonable to outsource transportation, especially in a global marketplace. And it is an especially sound practice to manage risks associated with this outsourcing by maintaining a redundant supplier in the event of disruptions with the primary outsourced transportation network.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Acquiring competitive high-tech equipment "},{"question":"  B. using an off-site delivery center. ","choices":["  C. managing possible risks of SRM outsourcing. ","  D. poor outsourcing practice","164. The correct answer is D. ","Generally, customers who resort to this tactic feel that they have not been heard by the \"offending\" business and that attempts have not been made to address their problems. This is a failure of customer communication and customer care rather than brand identity, specific communication media, or competitors' activities.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. outsourcing transportation needs. "},{"question":"  B. development of brand identity. ","choices":["  C. monitoring of competitive activities. ","  D. none of the above.","165. The correct answer is C. ","While businesses may employ customer segmentation, competitive differentiation, and niche marketing to appeal to customers, this strategy describes the creation of lifetime customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. managing media for customer communication. "},{"question":"  B. niche marketing. ","choices":["  C. creating lifetime customers. ","  D. customer segmentation.","166. The correct answer is A. ","From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider the strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. competitive differentiation. "},{"question":"  B. Improving overall financial position. ","choices":["  C. Overcoming barriers to market entry. ","  D. Improving operations by lowering system costs.","167. The correct answer is C. ","While in the past the strategic focus for many organizations was to improve their internal quality and reduce costs, the new focus is on implementing total supply chain solutions that require collaboration from partner organizations both upstream and downstream.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Surmounting limited availability of component suppliers. "},{"question":"  B. The focus has shifted from human resource-based solutions to technology-driven solutions. ","choices":["  C. The focus has shifted from internal quality improvement and cost reduction to collaborative solutions up and down the supply chain. ","  D. The focus has shifted from brick-and-mortar solutions to Web-based solutions.","168. The correct answer is D. ","A collaborative transportation network allows trading partners to share their transportation assets through aligning transportation needs with assets in real time.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The focus has shifted from inventory management to demand enhancement. "},{"question":"  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","choices":["  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network.  ","169. The correct answer is A. ","When information from suppliers, manufacturers, distributors, retailers, and customers is available for analysis, there is enhanced visibility of the supply chain and opportunities for improvement. Demand information, inventory status, capacity status, capacity plans, production schedules, promotion plans, shipment forecasts, and demand forecasts are all shared and ideally can be accessed by all parties on a real-time, online basis.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. third-party logistics (3PL) company. "},{"question":"  B. Purchase price versus true cost ","choices":["  C. Transactional versus collaborative ","  D. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","170. The correct answer is A. ","Measurement of customer satisfaction is a key element of CRM. B2B companies may measure the CRM effectiveness of their account managers by inviting the managers' customers to participate in their performance evaluations. VOC is considered a more general research tool.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility "},{"question":"  B. supply chain integration. ","choices":["  C. voice of the customer information gathering. ","  D. collaborative management practices. ","171. The correct answer is B. ","When manufacturers and retailers collaborate by sharing information, they develop products that are better able to meet the needs of the customer and are also better able to communicate the benefits to those customers. This may actually lead to premium prices for certain types of deliveries.   . "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. measuring customer satisfaction. "},{"question":"  B. By improving the ability to anticipate needs and convey benefits ","choices":["  C. By standardizing prices across channels ","  D. By increasing the number of response channels available to consumers ","172. The correct answer is C. ","While CRM and SRM are not synonymous with technical tools (they are philosophies and competitive strategies), they are both greatly supported by technological solutions.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By reducing the need to retool product lines constantly "},{"question":"  B. The effects of technology are more significant in SRM than CRM. ","choices":["  C. Technology plays a supporting role in CRM and SRM. ","  D. All of the above","173. The correct answer is A. ","Because collaboration skills may not come naturally to everyone, firms must develop their employees' skills for resolving conflicts, negotiating, solving problems jointly, and conducting difficult conversations. Conflicts are unavoidable but must be treated as learning experiences. Agreements must be flexible. Alliance managers must focus on the overall goals of the alliance rather than those of the channel master.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Both CRM and SRM are essentially technological. "},{"question":"  B. avoiding conflicts throughout the relationship. ","choices":["  C. establishing a well-defined purchasing contract with potential partners. ","  D. thinking in terms of the overall goals of the channel master. ","174. The correct answer is A. ","ISO certification is a globally recognized process that certifying companies must update every three years. Since it is industry- rather than business-specific, it often complements a business's own certification process. ISO certification may be a requirement for suppliers, but because of the certification's broad criteria it is usually not the only requirement in the certification process.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. developing employee negotiation and joint problem solving skills. "},{"question":"  B. ISO certification is a one-time process. ","choices":["  C. Because of their depth, ISO standards can often be used in place of a company's own supplier criteria in the supplier certification process. ","  D. ISO certification has limited recognition globally. ","175. The correct answer is D. ","Development of the PSA, procedures to handle all customer interactions, infrastructure (people and information) to perform the procedures, and metrics to measure success are all parts of a successful customer service management strategy. Customer interaction scenarios are determined by customer needs, not by existing infrastructure. Specific responses should be developed and followed. Service levels may be customized for different customer segments.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. ISO certification may be one criterion a supplier must meet in a larger certification process. "},{"question":"  B. Developing a general system but allowing flexibility to customer service personnel to develop specific procedures ","choices":["  C. Delivering consistent and identical customer service to all customer segments ","  D. Development of a product and service agreement (PSA) ","176. The correct answer is B. ","Companies that can benefit from knowing more about the end customer or shaping the needs and wants of the end customer will be most interested in CRM. The manufacturer of power tools must design, manufacture, and sell tools that appeal to customers. The other companies are suppliers that must satisfy a purchaser's technical qualifications or expectations.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Restricting customer interactions to a limited set of defined scenarios that may be performed within the existing infrastructure "},{"question":"  B. Manufacturer of power tools ","choices":["  C. Company that manufactures testing equipment for a laboratory builder ","  D. Company that develops billing application software for a health-care provider ","177. The correct answer is C. ","Rates, such as number of floor failures, rejected materials, or delays in shipment, are used to compile reports of supplier performance but are not themselves reports. Reporting mechanisms include such tools as scorecards, performance failure alerts (which are online and in real time), and surveys. A certification indicates that a supplier has met criteria but does not report ongoing performance.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Company that fabricates fiberglass insulation for a heating equipment manufacturer "},{"question":"  B. a floor failure event rate. ","choices":["  C. an automated performance alert. ","  D. a rejected materials rate.","178. The correct answer is D. ","Up-selling is a CRM tactic in which customers are offered higher-priced or more profitable items instead of the item they were originally considering. The operator in this case may be supported by a workflow that suggests specific models and links to more data in an electronic catalog or data about the customer's previous purchases that suggest a tendency toward higher-priced purchases.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a certification document. "},{"question":"  B. cross-selling. ","choices":["  C. a win-back program. ","  D. up-selling. ","179. The correct answer is A. ","As structures and processes change, managers will need to acquire new skills to support implementation of SRM and CRM. Decision making will actually move downward throughout the organization, closer to critical points in the supply chain. Technology is increasingly available, powerful, and easy to integrate.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a loyalty program. "},{"question":"  B. Decision making must become more centralized and uniform. ","choices":["  C. Technology is too complex and expensive. ","  D. None of the above","180. The correct answer is D. ","Increased customer visibility is a benefit of CRM in that CRM helps businesses to see each point of the purchasing transaction from the customer's perspective and to understand what the customer needs and values.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Managers must acquire new skill sets. "},{"question":"  B. being aware of each point of contact between the customer and the business. ","choices":["  C. seeing the transaction from the customer's viewpoint. ","  D. all of the above. ","181. The correct answer is D. ","While the computer, intranets, and advanced telephony have certainly enhanced both supplier and customer relationship management, the Internet has made the largest impact on communication with customers and between partners in the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. knowing what each customer values. "},{"question":"  B. the intranet. ","choices":["  C. the computer. ","  D. the Internet.","182. The correct answer is C. ","From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. advanced telephony features. "},{"question":"  B. Building organizational expertise ","choices":["  C. The number of suppliers able to provide the component ","  D. Opening new markets","183. The correct answer is B. ","A PSA between partners should be mutually beneficial. It may be customized, should precede pilot and full implementation, and should always be measured for improvement.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Adding value to products "},{"question":"  B. The negotiated PSA must be mutually beneficial for both partners. ","choices":["  C. The PSA is crafted only after a carefully conducted pilot program. ","  D. PSAs should be standardized for all suppliers. ","184. The correct answer is B. ","Organizations implementing CRM and SRM must move toward greater collaboration and away from more hierarchical structures defined by task-focused responsibility centers and top-down decision making. They call for a new attitude and new skills in the existing workforce.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The PSA is not subject to standard strategic goal metrics. "},{"question":"  B. New job definitions ","choices":["  C. Greater emphasis on task-focused responsibility centers ","  D. Greater control from the top down","185. The correct answer is B. ","SRM is a methodology to structure and support relationships with suppliers that will assist in reducing procurement and excess inventory costs, supporting a customer-focused business that delivers product/service customization and quality in the desired time frame, and improving processes in an ongoing manner.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. A new workforce "},{"question":"  B. Reducing procurement and excess inventory costs ","choices":["  C. Focusing on cost of materials and components ","  D. Targeting suppliers for cross-selling and up-selling opportunities","186. The correct answer is B. ","The traditional marketing definition of placement has been expanded to include not only getting product into the hands of customers (distribution) but also the customer's ability to access the business (e.g., for information, actual sales, or support).  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Improving depth of purchased parts knowledge "},{"question":"  B. Placement ","choices":["  C. Product ","  D. Price","187. The correct answer is C. ","During the growth phase, the customer base increases and competitors begin to enter the market. Data on the growing customer base must be analyzed for new opportunities, and supply must be managed to meet growing demand.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Promotion "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity","188. The correct answer is B. ","In a customer-focused world, the starting point for a product is often customer need.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. identifying customer need. ","choices":["  C. identifying a new market niche. ","  D. identifying a price point most acceptable to lifetime customers. ","189. The correct answer is D. ","The key is collaborative planning across the supply chain rather than mere information sharing or single alliances.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. evaluating current customer product complaints. "},{"question":"  B. Information sharing with key partners ","choices":["  C. Creating individual partnerships ","  D. Collaborative planning across the entire supply chain ","190. The correct answer is C. ","SRM helps ensure that demand created by CRM can be fulfilled in a manner profitable for all supply chain partners while maintaining customer satisfaction. Success of supplier relationships may be measured by various means, including time-to-market, cost efficiency, competitive advantage, and end customer satisfaction. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Creating an alliance with a key supplier "},{"question":"  B. It focuses on gaining information about customers. ","choices":["  C. It focuses on meeting demand. ","  D. It helps ensure the same profitability for all supply chain elements","191. The correct answer is D. ","Companies whose ability to meet customer demands rests on their control over the supply side of the supply chain model will be most interested in SRM. The other companies are primarily concerned with understanding and responding to customer needs and expectations.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. It measures success only by satisfaction of end customers. "},{"question":"  B. Company that performs market research for political candidates ","choices":["  C. Credit card company ","  D. Paint manufacturer that purchases chemicals and dyes from various suppliers ","192. The correct answer is A. ","Lifetime customers have a win-win relationship with the businesses they frequent. The customers gain greater satisfaction while the business enjoys decreased marketing costs and increased revenue and profit potential. Lifetime customers are not common in markets competing on price rather than added value.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Company that produces video games "},{"question":"  B. are increasingly more expensive for a business to maintain as they become more demanding. ","choices":["  C. are common in commodity markets driven by price rather than value. ","  D. can increase revenue but have a neutral effect on profit.","193. The correct answer is C. ","Contact channel strategy may include the choice of advertising media and designing a distribution system, but it includes more concerns and is more interactive than those choices suggest. The contact channel strategy should address both contacting customers and being contacted by customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. have forged a win-win relationship with the business in question. "},{"question":"  B. selection of key distributors of service or product. ","choices":["  C. designing a two-way communication architecture between customers and businesses. ","  D. none of the above.","194. The correct answer is D. ","Dissatisfied customers have the means to make their disloyalty very well-known by the Internet. Complaints posted on Web sites, Web logs, chat rooms, or electronic bulletin boards can have a significant impact on today's Internet-savvy customer and can destroy a once-strong business relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. choosing media for advertising. "},{"question":"  B. Price and placement are no longer of importance to today's service-conscious customer. ","choices":["  C. Customer loyalty no longer extends from an individual product to the supplier of that product. ","  D. The Internet has given dissatisfied customers the means to make their disloyalty quickly and widely known. ","195. The correct answer is A. ","Successful product designs begin with knowledge of the customer's needs and buying habits. Promotional activities are greatly supported and enhanced by CRM abilities, but promotion decisions, goals, and activities are, for the most part, unchanged from the traditional marketing model. Price may be determined by a number of factors, as may placement.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Brand image awareness has become independent of product satisfaction. "},{"question":"  B. Promotion in CRM is distinctly different from traditional marketing strategies. ","choices":["  C. Price is determined primarily by the cost of production. ","  D. Placement is determined primarily by product specifications. ","196．The correct answer is B. ","Customer-focused businesses try to make their customers feel better educated about what they are buying before, during, and after the purchase. They promote sharing of information about the customer throughout the supply chain, appreciate the need to consider customer needs in designing as well as marketing and distributing products, and maintain communication and distribution strategies that value convenience for the customer more than profitability.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. The starting point for product design is the customer. "},{"question":"  B. educates customers throughout the purchasing process. ","choices":["  C. restricts communication and distribution channels to the most profitable options. ","  D. gathers information about the customer but restricts its use to critical points in the supply chain","197. The correct answer is A. ","Demographic segmentation groups customers by group characteristics such as age, income, marital status, or family size.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. focuses on customer care rather than product/service design and delivery. "},{"question":"  B. Segmentation by need ","choices":["  C. Segmentation by channel ","  D. Segmentation by value ","198. The correct answer is D. ","Shipping generic products and creating the customer variations further down the supply chain (delayed differentiation) aggregates customer demand across all products. This produces a more accurate demand forecast with a smaller degree of variability, allowing reduced storage of safety stock.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Segmentation by demographics "},{"question":"  B. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","choices":["  C. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","  D. By enabling delayed differentiation ","199. The correct answer is B. ","Predictive churn uses data about individual customer transactions and histories to identify trends that indicate that a customer may switch to a competitor or cease being a customer. As a result, the vulnerable customer may be offered incentives, such as loyalty programs. The data used in the model may be gathered through data mining.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By reducing lead times "},{"question":"  B. Predictive churn ","choices":["  C. Loyalty programs ","  D. Win-back programs ","200. The correct answer is A. ","Designating one organization as channel master positioned at the center of the initiative during its inception can contribute to the strategy's success. The channel master should be capable of rallying supporters and driving the implementation beyond the preoccupation with improving internal competencies.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Data mining "},{"question":"  B. the person designated as strategic team leader. ","choices":["  C. the organization that designates the optimal delivery channels. ","  D. the person who designates the optimal communications channels.","201. The correct answer is B. ","After determining the nature and costs of potential disruptions, organizations assemble a desirable risk portfolio that balances risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. the organization that drives the implementation process. "},{"question":"  B. Balance risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation. ","choices":["  C. Identify current risk-prone partnerships that should be severed. ","  D. Eliminate risks by predicting their likely sources. ","202. The correct answer is D. ","All of the answers are correct. Higher quality, made possible through technology, has created increased customer expectations, which has in turn led to price as a differentiating factor. This has created a downward pressure on profit margin. Greater customer focus helps counter this pressure.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Identify those risk costs that can shifted to a partner's portfolio. "},{"question":"  B. Advances in technology ","choices":["  C. Greater global competition ","  D. All of the above","201.  The correct answer is D. ","Many SRM tasks may be outsourced, from researching and contracting with alliance partners to development of technology. However, companies should never outsource strategic tasks or core competencies.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Higher quality of goods and services "},{"question":"  B. Selection of strategic partners ","choices":["  C. Setting corporate goals and developing strategy for alliances ","  D. Contracting with strategic partners  ","202. The correct answer is D. ","During the maturity phase of the product life cycle, the costs of acquiring sales are declining, so profit is higher. At the same time, growing competition places pressure on prices. Increased sales promotion and aggressive customer acquisition help balance this influence.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Setting of procurement budgets "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity","203.The correct answer is B. ","Using modern information and communication systems, distributor integration relationships allow distributors to share access to product and service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","choices":["  C. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  D. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","204. The correct answer is C. ","If CRM vendors train their employees in the client's business and products and if they have adequate resources, they can convey the impression of seamless customer service. CRM may be outsourced for various reasons. Cost is not the only consideration; vendors may offer advanced capabilities, for example. Information gained by one vendor should be shared with all vendors to create a learning organization.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. "},{"question":"  B. CRM should not be outsourced. ","choices":["  C. CRM vendors may provide seamless customer service. ","  D. Separation of CRM vendors should be strictly enforced to protect the outsourcing business's autonomy. ","205. The correct answer is B. ","This company is probably a third-party logistics provider, a company that performs all or part of an organization's procurement of materials and distribution.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. The only good reason for outsourcing CRM is cost savings. "},{"question":"  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","choices":["  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. distributor integration (DI) network. ","206. The correct answer is A. ","Because it allows a high degree of customization, one-to-one marketing programs cannot be implemented without using a CDW. CDWs are used for a variety of purposes, including segmentation, implementing different offers to customers, analyzing buying behaviors to detect preferences, and supporting strategic decisions, such as the allocation of human resources. They are usually used in conjunction with information from a company's other databases.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. "},{"question":"  B. CDWs are primarily used as measurement tools. ","choices":["  C. CDWs are maintained as separate entities from a company's customer databases. ","  D. None of the above","207. The correct answer is A. ","Many suppliers feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity where price is emphasized rather than quality or the partnership.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. One-to-one marketing cannot be achieved without using a CDW. "},{"question":"  B. Distributor ","choices":["  C. Customer ","  D. Internal ","208. The correct answer is C. ","Pricing, product, and placement are all important strategy elements in implementing and maintaining brand image or identity, but creation of the desired image is a promotional activity.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Supplier "},{"question":"  B. product. ","choices":["  C. promotion. ","  D. pricing. ","209. The correct answer is D. ","Commodity pricing has made it more important for businesses to streamline the supply chain and become more cost-effective. The supply chain has, in fact, consolidated rather than fragmented; global markets have grown rather than shrunk. Consolidation may necessitate strategic sourcing as the number of sources narrows. Growing global markets present opportunities but also costs and risks that must be managed.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. placement. "},{"question":"  B. Shrinking global markets ","choices":["  C. Decreasing customer response time ","  D. Commodity pricing","210. The correct answer is D. ","SRM has been used in the parts or after-market industry to plan both strategy and tactics as well as to budget and manage specific business events, such as managing inventory.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Greater fragmentation on both sides of the supply chain "},{"question":"  B. select suppliers. ","choices":["  C. gather information about customers. ","  D. implement both production and sales tactics. ","211. The correct answer is B. ","Customer segment mapping is a key component of implementing CRM strategy since it leads to a better understanding of customer values and needs and increased potential for success in responding to those values and needs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. retool aging technology. "},{"question":"  B. customer segment mapping. ","choices":["  C. market prioritization. ","  D. demographic analysis. ","212. The correct answer is B. ","Suppliers of raw materials typically prefer flexible delivery times, large yet stable volume demands, and consistency in mix of materials.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. predictive analysis. "},{"question":"  B. Suppliers ","choices":["  C. Warehouse managers ","  D. Retailers","213. The correct answer is D. ","Direct shipping from the warehouse to the customer's home lowers costs by storing inventory at a centrally located warehouse rather than at the retail location. Customer service is improved by allowing a larger selection of inventory and providing front-door delivery service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Logistics managers "},{"question":"  B. By enabling delayed differentiation ","choices":["  C. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  D. By enabling direct shipping from warehouse to customer's home ","214. The correct answer is A. ","Data purchased from companies such as database marketing companies provide information about customers outside a company's own customer base. These data are useful in reaching new customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By supporting factory-distributor-retailer-customer distribution pathways "},{"question":"  B. They paint a picture of a business's own customers. ","choices":["  C. They are very useful in managing relationships with existing customers. ","  D. They can be very broad. ","215. The correct answer is B. ","Single sourcing of a key material or component is not a good example of risk management, even if the supplier is the lowest-cost provider. Good risk management may involve additional costs incurred through maintaining redundancy in the supply chain and requiring additional supplier performance or assumption of risk.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They may be more useful in new customer acquisition. "},{"question":"  B. This company develops detailed plans to shift work orders among several certified global suppliers in the event of labor disruptions in their countries. ","choices":["  C. This company requires in its contracts that all suppliers use a defined third-party transportation provider for all shipments. ","  D. This company sources a key raw material from one supplier who reliably provides the lowest price.  ","216. The correct answer is D. ","SRM focuses on the supply side of the supply chain to ensure that customer demands can be met with a high degree of satisfaction but also with mutual profitability for all suppliers. Relationships using SRM are marked by a high degree of integration of processes and even information systems. SRM may not be appropriate in relationships with all suppliers but rather with suppliers considered key partners in maintaining the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. This company relies on the selection process as its only means of risk management. "},{"question":"  B. Philosophy applied equally to all suppliers ","choices":["  C. Tool to align the customer voice with the product produced ","  D. Way to ensure mutual profitability while meeting marketplace needs","217. The correct answer is A. ","Companies are responding to the forces of globalization, increased project complexity, and greater market volatility by investing in technology that will enable them to better manage knowledge both within and across organizations.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Provides fuller communication without actual integration "},{"question":"  B. Shrinking markets ","choices":["  C. Increased difficulties in communication and application sharing ","  D. Increased influence of trade unions ","218. The correct answer is C. ","Before the rules, supervision, and improvement of the relationship can be pursued, a win-win deal must be negotiated. This sets the tone for the future alliance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Greater market volatility "},{"question":"  B. establish ground rules. ","choices":["  C. negotiate a win-win deal. ","  D. engage in a collaborative corporate mindset.","219. The correct answer is D. ","A product and service agreement does define specifications, but it does so in the context of segmenting customer groups. Customers are mapped and then aligned with different levels of customer service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. appoint an alliance manager. "},{"question":"  B. is a type of customer communication. ","choices":["  C. is part of a promotional strategy to win back customers. ","  D. aligns customer groups with certain service levels. ","220. The correct answer is B. ","Customer segmentation predates CRM but in the past relied heavily on demographic segmentation, which does not use actual customer buying behavior as CRM segmentation methods do. Customer segmentation can increase both revenue and profitability for retail as well as B2B customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. defines product or service specifications. "},{"question":"  B. Demographic segmentation is not based on data about actual customer buying behaviors. ","choices":["  C. Customer segmentation may help increase revenue but is not a tool for increasing profitability. ","  D. Customer segmentation is a concept introduced in CRM. ","221. The correct answer is B. ","In a continuous replenishment model, suppliers are notified daily of actual sales or warehouse shipments and commit to replenishing inventory without receiving purchase orders.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Customer segmentation does not apply well to business (B2B) customers. "},{"question":"  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","choices":["  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above. ","222. The correct answer is D. ","In this arrangement, the manufacturer receives better information about market demand, enabling more efficient production and better inventory management, thereby reducing costs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a quick response inventory management model. "},{"question":"  B. lengthening intervals between restocking. ","choices":["  C. shortening production times. ","  D. reducing costs.  ","223. The correct answer is B. ","Both CRM and SRM focus on gathering information but for different purposes: CRM to understand customers better and support marketing, SRM to develop and manage relationships with key partners in the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. enhancing demand. "},{"question":"  B. gathering and sharing information. ","choices":["  C. understanding buying habits of retail customers. ","  D. providing superior marketing decision support. ","224. The correct answer is D. ","Promotion comprises a variety of marketing activities, from customer research through strategy setting and advertising. CRM enhances both the gathering of information about customers and the use of that information in marketing activities.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. choosing appropriate strategic partners. "},{"question":"  B. Product ","choices":["  C. Placement ","  D. Promotion","225. The correct answer is C. ","A virtual organization is a long-term strategic alliance of separate business entities that presents itself to third parties as a single entity.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Price "},{"question":"  B. Raw materials supplier that agrees to supply product for an upcoming production cycle ","choices":["  C. Strategic alliance of four companies to develop a new drug product and market it under the name of one of the companies ","  D. Company that sells only services, not products ","226. The correct answer is D. ","As sales decline, customer care becomes more critical. As distribution and sales decrease, customers with products that are becoming obsolete must be supported. Success now can win customers loyal to the brand. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Merger of two competitors "},{"question":"  B. Growth ","choices":["  C. Maturity ","  D. Decline","227. The correct answer is B. ","An ongoing relationship involves repeated transactions, perhaps regulated through medium-term contracts. Communication is funneled through an account manager, who adjusts in all interactions to the customer's culture and way of doing business.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Introduction "},{"question":"  B. Ongoing relationship ","choices":["  C. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  D. Buy the market","228. The correct answer is D. ","Retailers need short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround times.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Mergers and acquisitions "},{"question":"  B. Warehousers ","choices":["  C. Manufacturers ","  D. Retailers ","229. The correct answer is B. ","In SRM's collaborative relationships, suppliers can participate in improving the system, which results in better product, higher customer satisfaction, and better customer retention.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Suppliers "},{"question":"  B. Higher customer satisfaction ","choices":["  C. Cheaper products ","  D. Increased control by the alliance manager ","230. The correct answer is B. ","A 'best cost\" analysis of risk is performed by multiplying the anticipated cost of the business disruption by the likelihood of its occurrence.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Reduced marketing costs "},{"question":"  B. multiplying the expected cost of the risk by its likelihood. ","choices":["  C. adding accumulated risk associated with all strategic suppliers. ","  D. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business.  ","231. The correct answer is A. ","Collaborations or strategic alliances are long-term arrangements ruled more by agreements than contracts. The suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. Trust levels are high.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business and dividing that by likelihood of the occurrence. "},{"question":"  B. Buy the market ","choices":["  C. Mergers and acquisitions ","  D. Ongoing relationship ","232. The correct answer is B. ","Customer design groups are an example of open-ended information gathering used by VOC to make complex customer perceptions more visible to a business. A brief checkoff survey does not capture complex information. Analysis of behaviors and analysis by others do not present the customer's own voice.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Collaborations/strategic alliance "},{"question":"  B. Customer design groups ","choices":["  C. Collated comments of sales representatives calling on specific customer groups ","  D. Brief checkoff customer satisfaction surveys printed on invoices","233. The correct answer is A. ","In general, CRM benefits the supply chain by creating and maintaining demand for products and services.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Analysis of customer buying behaviors "},{"question":"  B. ensuring supply at the retail level. ","choices":["  C. aligning distributors with retailers. ","  D. eliminating volatility in orders of raw materials. ","234. The correct answer is D. ","In a dynamic marketplace, a static consultant contract without clear and flexible guidelines and processes to manage the relationship simply encourages consultants to break their connection with the company rather than redefine it.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. creating and maintaining demand. "},{"question":"  B. providing clear channels of legal redress for each participant. ","choices":["  C. preventing any sources of tension between participant organizations. ","  D. encouraging participants to redefine problematic connections rather than break them. ","235. The correct answer is D. ","CTMs can deliver all of these benefits by aligning transportation needs with transportation assets to eliminate inefficiencies, such as wait time, half-filled loads, or empty backhauls (\"deadheading\").  . "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. ensuring strict adherence to the established alliance contract by both participants. "},{"question":"  B. Optimization of weight and volume capacity of network resources ","choices":["  C. Increase in backhaul opportunities for carriers ","  D. All of the above ","236. The correct answer is D. ","Improved, real-time communication can benefit supply relationships in all of the ways listed, from planning through production and distribution.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Reduction of carriers' wait time for loading and unloading "},{"question":"  B. Better forecasting of raw materials and labor through synchronized planning activities ","choices":["  C. Decreased time-to-market through coordinating workflows ","  D. All of the above ","237. The correct answer is B. ","Pricing, product, and placement are all important strategy elements in implementing and maintaining brand image or identity, but creation of the desired image is a promotional activity.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Early detection of quality problems through timely information sharing "},{"question":"  B. promotion. ","choices":["  C. placement. ","  D. pricing. ","238. The correct answer is C. ","The most accurate answer is that a vulnerable customer is one who is about to stop being a customer. This may be due to factors described in some of the incorrect choices. A vulnerable customer may perceive little value in the relationship, may have developed little loyalty, and may be willing to try a competitor. A customer with obsolete product who does not receive customer care may soon become vulnerable.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. product. "},{"question":"  B. is segmented into a low-value group and offered little incentive. ","choices":["  C. is about to discontinue service or stop purchasing the brand products. ","  D. has bought product that is becoming obsolete. ","239. The correct answer is C. ","Off-site delivery centers add value to the supply chain by performing tasks that require special expertise and resources, such as application and data management. They are not necessarily faster, but they have been shown to reduce technology project costs by up to 40 percent.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. the competition has been selling intensively. "},{"question":"  B. Off-site delivery centers are used only when IT resources are required. ","choices":["  C. Off-site delivery centers may add value to the supply chain through better performance. ","  D. Off-site delivery centers reduce lead time because they typically offer faster performance. ","240. The correct answer is B. ","While the other options are also valuable SRM tools, data warehousing and mining allow sharing of information between applications and partners.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Off-site delivery centers typically offer 60 percent savings in total project costs. "},{"question":"  B. Data warehousing and mining applications ","choices":["  C. Web-based procurement ","  D. Satellite-based tracking of transportation assets","241. The correct answer is D. ","All of the answers are correct. Higher quality, made possible through technology, has created increased customer expectations, which has in turn led to price as a differentiating factor. This has created a downward pressure on profit margin. Greater customer focus helps counter this pressure.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Wireless communication "},{"question":"  B. Advances in technology ","choices":["  C. Greater global competition ","  D. All of the above ","242. The correct answer is D. ","CTMs can deliver all of these benefits by aligning transportation needs with transportation assets to eliminate inefficiencies, such as wait time, half-filled loads, or empty backhauls (\"deadheading\").  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Higher quality of goods and services "},{"question":"  B. Optimization of weight and volume capacity of network resources ","choices":["  C. Increase in backhaul opportunities for carriers ","  D. All of the above ","243. The correct answer is B. ","The Pareto principle posits that a small percentage of the customer base (usually about or less than 20 percent) accounts for a large proportion of a company's revenue or profit (80 percent or more).  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Reduction of carriers' wait time for loading and unloading "},{"question":"  B. about or less than 20 percent of the customer base. ","choices":["  C. about or less than 40 percent of the customer base. ","  D. about or less than 80 percent of the customer base. ","244. The correct answer is C. ","Many suppliers feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity where price is emphasized rather than quality or the partnership.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. less than 10 percent of the customer base. "},{"question":"  B. Customer ","choices":["  C. Supplier ","  D. Internal ","245. The correct answer is B. ","Forging supplier relationships represents an investment that must be protected by developing ways to identify potential and actual conflicts, resolve them without endangering the relationship, and learning from the conflict.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Distributor "},{"question":"  B. a conflict resolution model. ","choices":["  C. structuring communication and decision making so that conflicts do not occur. ","  D. defining an early point at which to dissolve a troubled relationship.","246. The correct answer is C. ","Customers demand a variety of products and features as well as low prices.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. maintaining separate decision-making structures to avoid conflicts. "},{"question":"  B. Retailers ","choices":["  C. Customers ","  D. Manufacturers","247. The correct answer is C. ","Development of the PSA, procedures to handle all customer interactions, infrastructure (people and information) to perform the procedures, and metrics to measure success are all parts of a successful customer service management strategy. Customer interaction scenarios are determined by customer needs, not by existing infrastructure. Specific responses should be developed and followed. Service levels may be customized for different customer segments.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Suppliers "},{"question":"  B. Developing a general system but allowing flexibility to customer service personnel to develop specific procedures ","choices":["  C. Development of a product and service agreement (PSA) ","  D. Restricting customer interactions to a limited set of defined scenarios that may be performed within the existing infrastructure  ","248. The correct answer is A. ","Shipping generic products and creating the customer variations further down the supply chain (delayed differentiation) aggregates customer demand across all products. This produces a more accurate demand forecast with a smaller degree of variability, allowing reduced storage of safety stock.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Delivering consistent and identical customer service to all customer segments "},{"question":"  B. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping ","choices":["  C. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  D. By reducing lead times ","249. The correct answer is B. ","Because of costs associated with marketing, establishing inventory, and developing the distribution system and because a customer base has not yet been acquired, the introduction phase of the product life cycle is marked by high costs but low sales.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By enabling delayed differentiation "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity  ","250. The correct answer is C. ","A customer data warehouse (CDW) stores data about customers, products, and market trends, consolidating it in a manner that can facilitate future analysis to spot trends and relationships. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. Purchased data on specific customer segment ","choices":["  C. Data about customers, products, and marketplace extracted from internal and external resources ","  D. Repository of all data related to customer transactions ","251. The correct answer is A. ","Supply partners must accept and commit to the fact of change in their relationships. As conditions and individual priorities and strategies change, the processes that define the relationship should change as well. It is better if change can be accomplished incrementally.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Current customer profiles stored in a database "},{"question":"  B. Although marketplace change may be constant, the details of the relationship should not change. ","choices":["  C. Relationships should not be affected by the shifting priorities of the partners. ","  D. The best change occurs in large movements that motivate the entire organization rather than in smaller increments","252. The correct answer is D. ","Purchasing has, in fact, become more complex with the use of strategic sourcing. Roles have become more stratified, with senior-level managers focusing on strategic decisions and lower-level managers focusing on procurement and monitoring. They are aided by SRM technology, which has automated and supported many of their new tasks, such as partner research and contracting and invoice development.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. No single restructuring of processes will be adequate. "},{"question":"  B. Strategic sourcing has greatly simplified the tasks associated with purchasing. ","choices":["  C. SRM technology has greatly complicated the tasks of purchasing managers and agents. ","  D. Purchasing roles have become more layered between strategic management and buying. ","253. The correct answer is D. ","It is reasonable to outsource transportation, especially in a global marketplace. And it is an especially sound practice to manage risks associated with this outsourcing by maintaining a redundant supplier in the event of disruptions with the primary outsourced transportation network.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Under an SRM model, strategic decisions such as selection of alliance partners are pushed down to subordinate purchasing roles. "},{"question":"  B. outsourcing transportation needs. ","choices":["  C. using an off-site delivery center. ","  D. managing possible risks of SRM outsourcing.","254. The correct answer is B. ","After determining the nature and costs of potential disruptions, organizations assemble a desirable risk portfolio that balances risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. poor outsourcing practices. "},{"question":"  B. Balance risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation. ","choices":["  C. Eliminate risks by predicting their likely sources. ","  D. Identify those risk costs that can shifted to a partner's portfolio.","255. The correct answer is A. ","Logistics and warehousing management seek to minimize transportation costs by utilizing quantity discounts and minimizing inventory levels.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Identify current risk-prone partnerships that should be severed. "},{"question":"  B. Retailers ","choices":["  C. Manufacturers ","  D. Customers","256. The correct answer is B. ","Customer segmentation allows businesses to learn customer desires and habits and design more effective promotional programs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Warehousers "},{"question":"  B. Better ROI on promotion budgets ","choices":["  C. Shorter sales cycle ","  D. Lower production costs ","257. The correct answer is B. ","Data mining is the process of studying data to search for previously unknown relationships.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Shorter time-to-market "},{"question":"  B. data mining. ","choices":["  C. data warehousing. ","  D. setting a channel strategy. ","258. The correct answer is A. ","Both CRM and SRM focus on gathering information but for different purposes: CRM to understand customers better and support marketing, SRM to develop and manage relationships with key partners in the supply chain.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. developing a PSA. "},{"question":"  B. providing superior marketing decision support. ","choices":["  C. choosing appropriate strategic partners. ","  D. understanding buying habits of retail customers. ","259. The correct answer is D. ","In general, CRM benefits the supply chain by creating and maintaining demand for products and services.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. gathering and sharing information. "},{"question":"  B. eliminating volatility in orders of raw materials. ","choices":["  C. aligning distributors with retailers. ","  D. creating and maintaining demand","260. The correct answer is D. ","Customer segmentation predates CRM but in the past relied heavily on demographic segmentation, which does not use actual customer buying behavior as CRM segmentation methods do. Customer segmentation can increase both revenue and profitability for retail as well as B2B customers.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. ensuring supply at the retail level. "},{"question":"  B. Customer segmentation is a concept introduced in CRM. ","choices":["  C. Customer segmentation may help increase revenue but is not a tool for increasing profitability. ","  D. Demographic segmentation is not based on data about actual customer buying behaviors. ","261. The correct answer is B. ","Consumers and competitors have more and faster access to information, causing market volatility. Supply chain integration provides comparable improvements in information access.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Customer segmentation does not apply well to business (B2B) customers. "},{"question":"  B. Integration helps counter consumers' and competitors' increased access to information. ","choices":["  C. Integration helps reduce conflicts of interest. ","  D. Integration enables demand enhancement. ","262. The correct answer is A. ","Single sourcing of a key material or component is not a good example of risk management, even if the supplier is the lowest-cost provider. Good risk management may involve additional costs incurred through maintaining redundancy in the supply chain and requiring additional supplier performance or assumption of risk. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Integration enables a global response to demands. "},{"question":"  B. This company relies on the selection process as its only means of risk management. ","choices":["  C. This company requires in its contracts that all suppliers use a defined third-party transportation provider for all shipments. ","  D. This company sources a key raw material from one supplier who reliably provides the lowest price. ","263. The correct answer is A. ","While businesses may employ customer segmentation, competitive differentiation, and niche marketing to appeal to customers, this strategy describes the creation of lifetime customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. This company develops detailed plans to shift work orders among several certified global suppliers in the event of labor disruptions in their countries. "},{"question":"  B. customer segmentation. ","choices":["  C. competitive differentiation. ","  D. niche marketing. ","264. The correct answer is D. ","Fourth-party logistics providers are often found in global markets where they can combine the resources of suppliers and often 3PLs to meet the challenges of time zone, geographical, and cultural differences.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. creating lifetime customers. "},{"question":"  B. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","choices":["  C. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","  D. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company.","265. The correct answer is A. ","Up-selling is a CRM tactic in which customers are offered higher-priced or more profitable items instead of the item they were originally considering. The operator in this case may be supported by a workflow that suggests specific models and links to more data in an electronic catalog or data about the customer's previous purchases that suggest a tendency toward higher-priced purchases.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. distributor integration (DI) network. "},{"question":"  B. a loyalty program. ","choices":["  C. cross-selling. ","  D. a win-back program","266. The correct answer is D. ","During the maturity phase of the product life cycle, the costs of acquiring sales are declining, so profit is higher. At the same time, growing competition places pressure on prices. Increased sales promotion and aggressive customer acquisition help balance this influence. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. up-selling. "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity","267. The correct answer is D. ","A strategic plan addresses how the network will be differentiated across the full chain, the architecture used for Internet and intranet supply chain features, how physical assets and resources will be shared, and who will be in charge of executing each of the major changes needed.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. Defining how physical assets and resources will be reduced ","choices":["  C. Defining the architecture to be used for the company's intranet ","  D. How the network will be differentiated across the full chain ","268.  The correct answer is B. ","Customer-focused businesses try to make their customers feel better educated about what they are buying before, during, and after the purchase. They promote sharing of information about the customer throughout the supply chain, appreciate the need to consider customer needs in designing as well as marketing and distributing products, and maintain communication and distribution strategies that value convenience for the customer more than profitability.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Communicating the business rationale for the initiative "},{"question":"  B. educates customers throughout the purchasing process. ","choices":["  C. restricts communication and distribution channels to the most profitable options. ","  D. gathers information about the customer but restricts its use to critical points in the supply chain","269. The correct answer is C. ","From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider the strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. focuses on customer care rather than product/service design and delivery. "},{"question":"  B. Overcoming barriers to market entry. ","choices":["  C. Surmounting limited availability of component suppliers. ","  D. Improving overall financial position. ","270. The correct answer is A. ","While the computer, intranets, and advanced telephony have certainly enhanced both supplier and customer relationship management, the Internet has made the largest impact on communication with customers and between partners in the supply chain. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Improving operations by lowering system costs. "},{"question":"  B. the intranet. ","choices":["  C. advanced telephony features. ","  D. the computer. ","271. The correct answer is B. ","A PSA between partners should be mutually beneficial. It may be customized, should precede pilot and full implementation, and should always be measured for improvement.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. the Internet. "},{"question":"  B. The negotiated PSA must be mutually beneficial for both partners. ","choices":["  C. The PSA is crafted only after a carefully conducted pilot program. ","  D. PSAs should be standardized for all suppliers","272. The correct answer is A. ","Organizations implementing CRM and SRM must move toward greater collaboration and away from more hierarchical structures defined by task-focused responsibility centers and top-down decision making. They call for a new attitude and new skills in the existing workforce.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The PSA is not subject to standard strategic goal metrics. "},{"question":"  B. A new workforce ","choices":["  C. Greater control from the top down ","  D. Greater emphasis on task-focused responsibility centers","273. The correct answer is A. ","SRM has been used in the parts or after-market industry to plan both strategy and tactics as well as to budget and manage specific business events, such as managing inventory.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. New job definitions "},{"question":"  B. retool aging technology. ","choices":["  C. gather information about customers. ","  D. select suppliers.","274. The correct answer is A. ","Because it allows a high degree of customization, one-to-one marketing programs cannot be implemented without using a CDW. CDWs are used for a variety of purposes, including segmentation, implementing different offers to customers, analyzing buying behaviors to detect preferences, and supporting strategic decisions, such as the allocation of human resources. They are usually used in conjunction with information from a company's other databases.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. implement both production and sales tactics. "},{"question":"  B. CDWs are primarily used as measurement tools. ","choices":["  C. CDWs are maintained as separate entities from a company's customer databases. ","  D. None of the above ","275. The correct answer is B. ","To achieve certification's highest potential, companies must clearly communicate what they will be measuring and how. Criteria should be consistent from one supplier to the next. The outcome can be used not only for selection but also for supplier improvement. Companies usually opt to pursue the certification process only with actual or key suppliers.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. One-to-one marketing cannot be achieved without using a CDW. "},{"question":"  B. Suppliers should be clearly informed of criteria and processes to be used in the certification process. ","choices":["  C. Certification is a supplier selection tool only. ","  D. All potential suppliers should go through the certification process. ","276. The correct answer is C. ","Cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include costs of hardware, software, overhead, and consulting fees.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Criteria should be adjusted to individual suppliers' capabilities. "},{"question":"  B. What are the hardware expenses? ","choices":["  C. How profitable are each of the partner SCM organizations? ","  D. What are the overhead expenses?","277. The correct answer is B. ","Successful product designs begin with knowledge of the customer's needs and buying habits. Promotional activities are greatly supported and enhanced by CRM abilities, but promotion decisions, goals, and activities are, for the most part, unchanged from the traditional marketing model. Price may be determined by a number of factors, as may placement.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Are there consulting fees involved? "},{"question":"  B. The starting point for product design is the customer. ","choices":["  C. Price is determined primarily by the cost of production. ","  D. Placement is determined primarily by product specifications. ","278. The correct answer is B. ","A virtual organization is best described as a short-term alliance of independent businesses for a potentially long-term relationship. Businesses cooperate to design, create, and distribute product (including services) based on shared values and are perceived by third parties as a single entity.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Promotion in CRM is distinctly different from traditional marketing strategies. "},{"question":"  B. Potentially long-term relationship between separate business entities to design, produce, and distribute a product ","choices":["  C. Merger of separate entities with common business values and goals to gain better market position ","  D. Separate entities that collaborate to design and sell intangible products and services ","279. The correct answer is A. ","Manufacturing organizations strive for high production output and low production costs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Short-term tactical alliance in which partnering companies remain distinct and visible to end users "},{"question":"  B. Retailers ","choices":["  C. Customers ","  D. Suppliers ","280. The correct answer is C. ","SRM focuses on identifying opportunities for strategic relationships between supply chain partners and on developing and managing those relationships. The Internet banking company is concerned primarily with customers rather than suppliers. The commodity-driven company may have some benefit, but it will be limited by the opportunities to add value. Similarly, the gift catalog company requires adequate supply at the right times but may rely on so many suppliers that strategic partnerships are not practical. The manufacturer of consumer goods will benefit from developing strategic relationships with suppliers that add value and make its products more competitive.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Manufacturers "},{"question":"  B. An Internet banking company seeking to expand use among high-value customers ","choices":["  C. A company that uses raw materials and prefabricated components to create consumer goods ","  D. A company competing in a commodity market with little opportunity for adding value ","281. The correct answer is C. ","Proactive reasons for an organization to consider a strategic alliance are the alliance's ability to add value to products, enable strategic growth, increase market access, strengthen operations, increase organizational expertise, build organizational skills, and enhance financial strength.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. A gift catalog company that offers a large number of items from a wide variety of suppliers "},{"question":"  B. Acquiring technological expertise in weaker areas of the company ","choices":["  C. Improving time to market or increasing quality ","  D. Acquiring competitive high-tech equipment ","282. The correct answer is C. ","Lifetime customers increase the need for CRM, but they also make it a little easier as the business learns more about them over time. Total marketing costs decline, satisfaction increases with better customer understanding, and both revenue and profit increase.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Improving management compensation programs "},{"question":"  B. They increase total marketing costs. ","choices":["  C. They increase the need for CRM activities. ","  D. They tend to have a null effect on revenue but a positive effect on profit. ","283. The correct answer is B. ","The five best practices for supply chains are strategic sourcing and supplier management, operations and logistics, customer relationship management and channels, information technology, and change management.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They are more difficult to satisfy than first-time or short-term customers. "},{"question":"  B. Strategic sourcing and supplier management ","choices":["  C. Outsourcing operations and logistics ","  D. Maximizing profits","284. The correct answer is A. ","In a quick response model, the retailer continues to order from the supplier, although the supplier may collect POS data for the purposes of planning and forecasting.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Advertising and sales analysis "},{"question":"  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","choices":["  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above. ","285. The correct answer is C. ","Data purchased from companies such as database marketing companies provide information about customers outside a company's own customer base. These data are useful in reaching new customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a quick response inventory management model. "},{"question":"  B. They are very useful in managing relationships with existing customers. ","choices":["  C. They may be more useful in new customer acquisition. ","  D. They paint a picture of a business's own customers.","286. The correct answer is C. ","Increased supply chain visibility can lessen the bullwhip effect and enable early problem detection, faster response and better contingency planning, and stronger relationships because of increased trust.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They can be very broad. "},{"question":"  B. Simplifies market segmentation ","choices":["  C. Enables faster response and better contingency planning ","  D. Reduces customer service calls","287. The correct answer is A. ","This company is probably a third-party logistics provider, a company that performs all or part of an organization's procurement of materials and distribution.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Lowers the number of required distributors "},{"question":"  B. distributor integration (DI) network. ","choices":["  C. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","  D. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","288. The correct answer is C. ","There is a distinction between price and total cost of ownership. For example, a manufacturer of electronics may choose a component based on the lowest price, but that choice may not translate into low cost if the low-priced components are not reliable and fail early.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. third-party logistics (3PL) company. "},{"question":"  B. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","choices":["  C. Purchase price versus total cost of ownership ","  D. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","289. The correct answer is A. ","Because collaboration skills may not come naturally to everyone, firms must develop their employees' skills for resolving conflicts, negotiating, solving problems jointly, and conducting difficult conversations. Conflicts are unavoidable but must be treated as learning experiences. Agreements must be flexible. Alliance managers must focus on the overall goals of the alliance rather than those of the channel master.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Transactional versus collaborative "},{"question":"  B. establishing a well-defined purchasing contract with potential partners. ","choices":["  C. avoiding conflicts throughout the relationship. ","  D. thinking in terms of the overall goals of the channel master. ","290.  The correct answer is D. ","Using modern information and communication systems, distributor integration relationships allow distributors to share access to product and service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. developing employee negotiation and joint problem solving skills. "},{"question":"  B. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. ","choices":["  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. distributor integration (DI) network","291. The correct answer is C. ","Initially, customers may complain of getting lost in the network and never knowing whom to contact or how to check on an order. This is particularly common when more than one organization is involved in the support of a product or service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. third-party logistics (3PL) company. "},{"question":"  B. Internal ","choices":["  C. Customer ","  D. Supplier","292. The correct answer is C. ","EBS backbone applications focus on gathering, storing, and reporting information that is necessary to perform other functions in the SRM system, such as data on order history and accounting and information about suppliers and their performance.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Distributor "},{"question":"  B. Managing online bidding sessions ","choices":["  C. Order history ","  D. Product cataloging","293. The correct answer is B. ","Although vendors may suggest inventory levels, retailers must approve initial levels. After that point, levels will be maintained by the vendor according to an agreement and models based on POS and shipment data for greatest customer satisfaction and return on inventory. Data can be tied into planning processes so that MPSs can be created and MRPs set.  "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A. Managing EDI with suppliers "},{"question":"  B. Inventory levels can be adjusted according to different variables. ","choices":["  C. Retailers maintain oversight on ordering. ","  D. Retailers have no hand in setting initial inventory; historical data are used. ","294. The correct answer is C. ","During the growth phase, the customer base increases and competitors begin to enter the market. Data on the growing customer base must be analyzed for new opportunities, and supply must be managed to meet growing demand.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Inventory data cannot be tied to MPS or MRP. "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity ","295. The correct answer is D. ","Traditional purchasing sees each purchase as a discrete transaction. Since strategic sourcing involves ongoing relationships, there is opportunity for collaboration between the purchaser and suppliers that can result in improving the profitability of the supply chain and adding value to the final product or service.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","choices":["  C. Purchase price versus true cost ","  D. Transactional versus collaborative ","296. The correct answer is D. ","Measurement of customer satisfaction is a key element of CRM. B2B companies may measure the CRM effectiveness of their account managers by inviting the managers' customers to participate in their performance evaluations. VOC is considered a more general research tool.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility "},{"question":"  B. collaborative management practices. ","choices":["  C. supply chain integration. ","  D. measuring customer satisfaction. ","297. The correct answer is B. ","With shorter lead and cycle times, the level of safety stock may be reduced, which leads to savings by reducing inventory levels and obsolescence costs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. voice of the customer information gathering. "},{"question":"  B. lowering inventory levels and reducing costs. ","choices":["  C. shortening cycle times. ","  D. improving the ability to anticipate needs and convey benefits.","298. The correct answer is C. ","While in the past the strategic focus for many organizations was to improve their internal quality and reduce costs, the new focus is on implementing total supply chain solutions that require collaboration from partner organizations both upstream and downstream.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. enhancing demand. "},{"question":"  B. The focus has shifted from brick-and-mortar solutions to Web-based solutions. ","choices":["  C. The focus has shifted from internal quality improvement and cost reduction to collaborative solutions up and down the supply chain. ","  D. The focus has shifted from inventory management to demand enhancement. ","299. The correct answer is A. ","CRM focuses on learning more about one's customers and using this knowledge to enhance product, increase customer satisfaction, and improve revenue and profit. The company with the diverse customer base can potentially benefit greatly from being able to gather and use more information about its customers. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The focus has shifted from human resource-based solutions to technology-driven solutions. "},{"question":"  B. A company that provides raw materials for an extended supply chain in which value is added at later points in the chain ","choices":["  C. A company with one large customer who specifies product/service features ","  D. A company that performs purchasing for a large manufacturer from several strategic suppliers ","300. The correct answer is B. ","Successful alliances begin from a position of mutual strength and excellence. In this case, one partner is driven primarily by a desire to escape the problem of looming competition. This will be a hard obstacle to overcome even though the partners have invested in the relationship and integrated their organizations.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. A company with a customer base with diverse needs and interests "},{"question":"  B. individual excellence. ","choices":["  C. integration. ","  D. information. ","301. The correct answer is A. ","As structures and processes change, managers will need to acquire new skills to support implementation of SRM and CRM. Decision making will actually move downward throughout the organization, closer to critical points in the supply chain. Technology is increasingly available, powerful, and easy to integrate.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. investment. "},{"question":"  B. Decision making must become more centralized and uniform. ","choices":["  C. Technology is too complex and expensive. ","  D. None of the above","302. The correct answer is C. ","Information sharing benefits organizations by improving forecasts, improving coordination of manufacturing and distribution systems and strategies, reducing lead times, and accelerating reactions to marketing data. Information technology costs may increase but are offset by other benefits.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Managers must acquire new skill sets. "},{"question":"  B. Reduced forecast accuracy ","choices":["  C. Lower shortage costs ","  D. Lower information technology cost","303. The correct answer is B. ","Rates, such as number of floor failures, rejected materials, or delays in shipment, are used to compile reports of supplier performance but are not themselves reports. Reporting mechanisms include such tools as scorecards, performance failure alerts (which are online and in real time), and surveys. A certification indicates that a supplier has met criteria but does not report ongoing performance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Increased warehousing capacities "},{"question":"  B. an automated performance alert. ","choices":["  C. a certification document. ","  D. a rejected materials rate.","304. The correct answer is B. ","Pricing is influenced by many factors other than cost of production, including competitive positions, customers' willingness to pay for the value received, and consistency with the brand identity that has been created.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a floor failure event rate. "},{"question":"  B. Price ","choices":["  C. Placement ","  D. Product","305. The correct answer is C. ","Contact channel strategy may include the choice of advertising media and designing a distribution system, but it includes more concerns and is more interactive than those choices suggest. The contact channel strategy should address both contacting customers and being contacted by customers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Promotion "},{"question":"  B. selection of key distributors of service or product. ","choices":["  C. designing a two-way communication architecture between customers and businesses. ","  D. none of the above.","306. The correct answer is B. ","Direct shipping from the warehouse to the customer's home lowers costs by storing inventory at a centrally located warehouse rather than at the retail location. Customer service is improved by allowing a larger selection of inventory and providing front-door delivery service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. choosing media for advertising. "},{"question":"  B. By enabling direct shipping from warehouse to customer's home ","choices":["  C. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","  D. By enabling delayed differentiation","307. The correct answer is B. ","The key is collaborative planning across the supply chain rather than mere information sharing or single alliances.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By supporting factory-distributor-retailer-customer distribution pathways "},{"question":"  B. Collaborative planning across the entire supply chain ","choices":["  C. Creating individual partnerships ","  D. Information sharing with key partners","308. The correct answer is B. ","In a continuous replenishment model, suppliers are notified daily of actual sales or warehouse shipments and commit to replenishing inventory without receiving purchase orders.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Creating an alliance with a key supplier "},{"question":"  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","choices":["  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above.","309. The correct answer is A. ","Before entering alliances, start identifying key issues and decisions and involving key stakeholders for fewer surprises and greater buy-in by key people.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a quick response inventory management model. "},{"question":"  B. select the proper partners by evaluating corporate culture and operating style. ","choices":["  C. establish ground rules for how partners will work together and resolve conflict. ","  D. appoint a dedicated alliance manager to oversee the partner relationship. ","310. The correct answer is A. ","Information gathered in the CRM process is used to support service to customers and potential customers and sales and marketing decisions, not resource and production planning.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. align internally by identifying key issues and stakeholders. "},{"question":"  B. Solely a marketing philosophy ","choices":["  C. Tool to manage marketing, sales, supply planning, and production scheduling ","  D. Focused on forecasting and analysis of information ","311. The correct answer is A. ","A virtual organization is a long-term strategic alliance of separate business entities that presents itself to third parties as a single entity.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Tool to support existing and potential customer needs "},{"question":"  B. Merger of two competitors ","choices":["  C. Company that sells only services, not products ","  D. Raw materials supplier that agrees to supply product for an upcoming production cycle ","312. The correct answer is D. ","Implementing CRM and SRM does not require that companies change their core competencies, although employees may need to acquire new skills. Nor do organizations need to form common goals or mission statements. They will need, however, to revisit work processes, job definitions, and decision-making structures.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Strategic alliance of four companies to develop a new drug product and market it under the name of one of the companies "},{"question":"  B. outsourcing to companies with special expertise. ","choices":["  C. common business goals and mission statements for all supply chain members. ","  D. revision of decision-making processes.","313. The correct answer is C. ","Before the rules, supervision, and improvement of the relationship can be pursued, a win-win deal must be negotiated. This sets the tone for the future alliance.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. redefinition of core competencies. "},{"question":"  B. engage in a collaborative corporate mindset. ","choices":["  C. negotiate a win-win deal. ","  D. appoint an alliance manager. ","314. The correct answer is C. ","The traditional marketing definition of placement has been expanded to include not only getting product into the hands of customers (distribution) but also the customer's ability to access the business (e.g., for information, actual sales, or support).  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. establish ground rules. "},{"question":"  B. Product ","choices":["  C. Placement ","  D. Promotion ","315. The correct answer is C. ","Promotion comprises a variety of marketing activities, from customer research through strategy setting and advertising. CRM enhances both the gathering of information about customers and the use of that information in marketing activities.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Price "},{"question":"  B. Placement ","choices":["  C. Promotion ","  D. Product","316. The correct answer is B. ","ISO certification is a globally recognized process that certifying companies must update every three years. Since it is industry- rather than business-specific, it often complements a business's own certification process. ISO certification may be a requirement for suppliers, but because of the certification's broad criteria it is usually not the only requirement in the certification process.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Price "},{"question":"  B. ISO certification may be one criterion a supplier must meet in a larger certification process. ","choices":["  C. ISO certification is a one-time process. ","  D. Because of their depth, ISO standards can often be used in place of a company's own supplier criteria in the supplier certification process. ","317. The correct answer is C. ","Lifetime customers have a win-win relationship with the businesses they frequent. The customers gain greater satisfaction while the business enjoys decreased marketing costs and increased revenue and profit potential. Lifetime customers are not common in markets competing on price rather than added value.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. ISO certification has limited recognition globally. "},{"question":"  B. can increase revenue but have a neutral effect on profit. ","choices":["  C. have forged a win-win relationship with the business in question. ","  D. are common in commodity markets driven by price rather than value.","318. The correct answer is C. ","Customer design groups are an example of open-ended information gathering used by VOC to make complex customer perceptions more visible to a business. A brief checkoff survey does not capture complex information. Analysis of behaviors and analysis by others do not present the customer's own voice.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. are increasingly more expensive for a business to maintain as they become more demanding. "},{"question":"  B. Collated comments of sales representatives calling on specific customer groups ","choices":["  C. Customer design groups ","  D. Brief checkoff customer satisfaction surveys printed on invoices ","319. The correct answer is B. ","SRM helps ensure that demand created by CRM can be fulfilled in a manner profitable for all supply chain partners while maintaining customer satisfaction. Success of supplier relationships may be measured by various means, including time-to-market, cost efficiency, competitive advantage, and end customer satisfaction.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Analysis of customer buying behaviors "},{"question":"  B. It focuses on meeting demand. ","choices":["  C. It focuses on gaining information about customers. ","  D. It measures success only by satisfaction of end customers. ","320. The correct answer is B. ","When information from suppliers, manufacturers, distributors, retailers, and customers is available for analysis, there is enhanced visibility of the supply chain and opportunities for improvement. Demand information, inventory status, capacity status, capacity plans, production schedules, promotion plans, shipment forecasts, and demand forecasts are all shared and ideally can be accessed by all parties on a real-time, online basis.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. It helps ensure the same profitability for all supply chain elements. "},{"question":"  B. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility ","choices":["  C. Transactional versus collaborative ","  D. Purchase price versus true cost","321. The correct answer is C. ","A product and service agreement does define specifications, but it does so in the context of segmenting customer groups. Customers are mapped and then aligned with different levels of customer service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows "},{"question":"  B. defines product or service specifications. ","choices":["  C. aligns customer groups with certain service levels.  ","  D. is part of a promotional strategy to win back customers. ","322. The correct answer is C. ","Alliance relationships are marked by organization integration at many points in the partners' organizations, from information systems through marketing and sales to finance.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. is a type of customer communication. "},{"question":"  B. Despite potential benefits, there has been little growth in the development of strategic alliances. ","choices":["  C. Alliances are relationships between two or more partners in the supply chain. ","  D. Alliance relationships are marked by organizational integration at a few critical points.","323. The correct answer is B. ","Segmenting customers is an essential part of creating a promotional strategy, one of the four Ps of traditional marketing and CRM strategies. The other choices reflect those other components of a CRM strategy: product, price, and placement.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. In alliance relationships, flexibility is not a good thing. Processes must be rigidly followed and enforced. "},{"question":"  B. Segmenting customers according to their value to the business ","choices":["  C. Deciding where to distribute one's products ","  D. Charging less if a customer orders through the Internet ","324. The correct answer is B. ","In a dynamic marketplace, a static consultant contract without clear and flexible guidelines and processes to manage the relationship simply encourages consultants to break their connection with the company rather than redefine it.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Creating a product and service agreement (PSA) "},{"question":"  B. encouraging participants to redefine problematic connections rather than break them. ","choices":["  C. providing clear channels of legal redress for each participant. ","  D. preventing any sources of tension between participant organizations. ","325. The correct answer is D. ","Effective supplier performance measurement systems track the performance of a broad portion of the supply chain base; collaborate with suppliers on performance measurements, reporting, and improvements; automate key supplier performance measurement activities; and standardize supplier performance measurement procedures across the organization.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. ensuring strict adherence to the established alliance contract by both participants. "},{"question":"  B. They track the performance of a narrowly defined portion of the supply chain base. ","choices":["  C. Their performance measurements, reporting, and improvements should be unilaterally defined by the purchasing organization. ","  D. They automate key supplier performance measurement activities. ","326. The correct answer is D. ","Retailers need short order lead times and quick delivery turnaround times.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They enable each department within an organization to define its own supplier performance measurement procedures. "},{"question":"  B. Manufacturers ","choices":["  C. Warehousers ","  D. Retailers ","327. The correct answer is A. ","A chief customer officer may supervise management of customer dissatisfaction, but the job entails more activities, including identifying customer touch points, defining and enforcing service standards, enriching the customer experience, and helping customers navigate within the organization.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Suppliers "},{"question":"  B. identifying opportunities for enhancing revenue and profit through customer interactions. ","choices":["  C. assigning account managers to high-value customers. ","  D. responding to customer dissatisfaction.","328. The correct answer is B. ","Organizations' internal members are sometimes hesitant initially to trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share what they value as important internal information or data. While most organizations are open to receiving information regarding best practices from partner organizations, they are typically not willing to reciprocate by sharing equal information.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. identifying and responding to customer care opportunities. "},{"question":"  B. Internal ","choices":["  C. Supplier ","  D. Distributor","329. The correct answer is B. ","A cross-functional organization is one that enjoys cooperation between internal groups, especially IT and operations.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Customer "},{"question":"  B. cross-functional. ","choices":["  C. able to lead. ","  D. change-oriented. ","330. The correct answer is B. ","Suppliers of raw materials typically prefer flexible delivery times, large yet stable volume demands, and consistency in mix of materials.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. farseeing. "},{"question":"  B. Suppliers ","choices":["  C. Logistics managers ","  D. Retailers","331. The correct answer is B. ","Good CRM technology is easy to use and meets customer expectations. Successful implementation of CRM technology rests on a clear, well-thought-out architecture. Rather than inhibiting change, good design enhances integration and lessens the chances of conflicts as the system evolves. Since it may involve redefining jobs, implementation teams should be cross-functional.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Warehouse managers "},{"question":"  B. Systems should be measured against whether they increase efficiency and meet customer expectations. ","choices":["  C. Detailed architecture design at an early stage may lead to an inflexible system that is difficult to change. ","  D. If technology is optimal, job responsibilities may remain static in the new system. ","332. The correct answer is D. ","Purchasing managers focus on strategic tasks such as supplier selection, contract negotiation, and analysis and evaluation of the supply system. Purchasing agents or planners focus on placing orders, following up with suppliers as needed, monitoring supply needs, and measuring supplier performance.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Implementation teams should represent technological areas only. "},{"question":"  B. Selecting suppliers ","choices":["  C. Negotiating contracts with strategic sourcing partners ","  D. Order placement ","333. The correct answer is A. ","Pricing is generally a strategic decision, based on competition, perceived value, and brand identity. Strategic pricing must be carefully and frequently analyzed to ensure that the pricing structure is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Analyzing value of supply process "},{"question":"  B. is calculated by a sliding scale based upon customers' ability to pay. ","choices":["  C. is calculated by adding a competitive profit margin to the total costs of creation, sales, and overhead. ","  D. must be consistent across targeted customer segments. ","334. The correct answer is A. ","One of the reasons to establish metrics and then monitor performance is to identify opportunities to improve supplier performance.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. must be continually analyzed to ensure that it is attractive to customers but still profitable to the business. "},{"question":"  B. achieve 50 percent adherence and adaptation by all partners. ","choices":["  C. penalize partners who do not adhere to agreed rules. ","  D. achieve annual cost reduction of 10 percent.","335. The correct answer is C. ","Companies whose ability to meet customer demands rests on their control over the supply side of the supply chain model will be most interested in SRM. The other companies are primarily concerned with understanding and responding to customer needs and expectations.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. monitor and identify opportunities for improvement. "},{"question":"  B. Company that produces video games ","choices":["  C. Paint manufacturer that purchases chemicals and dyes from various suppliers ","  D. Credit card company ","336. The correct answer is B. ","SRM is a methodology to structure and support relationships with suppliers that will assist in reducing procurement and excess inventory costs, supporting a customer-focused business that delivers product/service customization and quality in the desired time frame, and improving processes in an ongoing manner.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Company that performs market research for political candidates "},{"question":"  B. Reducing procurement and excess inventory costs ","choices":["  C. Targeting suppliers for cross-selling and up-selling opportunities ","  D. Focusing on cost of materials and components ","337. The correct answer is A. ","In mergers and acquisitions, suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity. Business goals are shared; business areas participate in setting strategy and planning integration of capabilities, processes, and information. Competition has been eliminated.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Improving depth of purchased parts knowledge "},{"question":"  B. Ongoing relationship ","choices":["  C. Buy the market ","  D. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","338. The correct answer is D. ","From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Mergers and acquisitions "},{"question":"  B. Building organizational expertise ","choices":["  C. Adding value to products ","  D. The number of suppliers able to provide the component ","339. The correct answer is A. ","A collaborative transportation network allows trading partners to share their transportation assets through aligning transportation needs with assets in real time.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Opening new markets "},{"question":"  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","choices":["  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. distributor integration (DI) network.","340. The correct answer is B. ","The product component of a CRM strategy refers to all those actions taken to craft products and services that relate to customer needs, opportunities to add value in the supply chain and enhance competitive position, and still meet profit objectives.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network. "},{"question":"  B. Product ","choices":["  C. Placement ","  D. Promotion","341. The correct answer is A. ","Successful product designs begin with knowledge of the customer's needs and buying habits. Promotional activities are greatly supported and enhanced by CRM abilities, but promotion decisions, goals, and activities are, for the most part, unchanged from the traditional marketing model. Price may be determined by a number of factors, as may placement.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Price "},{"question":"  B. Promotion in CRM is distinctly different from traditional marketing strategies. ","choices":["  C. Price is determined primarily by the cost of production. ","  D. Placement is determined primarily by product specifications. ","342. The correct answer is A. ","From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider the strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. The starting point for product design is the customer. "},{"question":"  B. Improving overall financial position. ","choices":["  C. Improving operations by lowering system costs. ","  D. Overcoming barriers to market entry.","343. The correct answer is D. ","The five best practices for supply chains are strategic sourcing and supplier management, operations and logistics, customer relationship management and channels, information technology, and change management.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Surmounting limited availability of component suppliers. "},{"question":"  B. Outsourcing operations and logistics ","choices":["  C. Advertising and sales analysis ","  D. Strategic sourcing and supplier management ","344. The correct answer is A. ","During the development phase of the product life cycle, CRM businesses research customer needs and expectations and incorporate this research into product design and the entire CRM strategy (i.e., price, placement, promotional message).  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Maximizing profits "},{"question":"  B. Introduction ","choices":["  C. Growth ","  D. Maturity","345. The correct answer is A. ","External data networks are created through collaboration of partners in a supply chain and facilitate the exchange and analysis of information gathered at various points in the supply chain, from factory through distribution to call centers.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Development "},{"question":"  B. an information repository for purchased customer data. ","choices":["  C. an outsourced CRM information management system. ","  D. any information system outside the business from which it may have to extract customer data. ","346. The correct answer is B. ","In a virtual organization, there is integration of many systems and extensive sharing of information, often proprietary information. Forming virtual organizations thus requires trust and a cultural shift that embraces the common identity of the virtual organization. At the same time, the member organizations must evaluate the risk of the relationship and preserve their own identity and integrity.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a network resulting from collaboration between the information and communication systems of a company and other members of its supply chain. "},{"question":"  B. Individual organizations must preserve their own identity and integrity. ","choices":["  C. Information belonging to member organizations remains proprietary. ","  D. Member organizations retain their original, distinctive cultures and values. ","347. The correct answer is B. ","Dissatisfied customers have the means to make their disloyalty very well-known by the Internet. Complaints posted on Web sites, Web logs, chat rooms, or electronic bulletin boards can have a significant impact on today's Internet-savvy customer and can destroy a once-strong business relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Customers perceive the member organizations as distinct entities. "},{"question":"  B. The Internet has given dissatisfied customers the means to make their disloyalty quickly and widely known. ","choices":["  C. Brand image awareness has become independent of product satisfaction. ","  D. Customer loyalty no longer extends from an individual product to the supplier of that product. ","348. The correct answer is B. ","This company is probably a third-party logistics provider, a company that performs all or part of an organization's procurement of materials and distribution.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Price and placement are no longer of importance to today's service-conscious customer. "},{"question":"  B. third-party logistics (3PL) company. ","choices":["  C. fourth-party logistics (4PL) company. ","  D. collaborative transportation management (CTM) network.","349. The correct answer is D. ","As sales decline, customer care becomes more critical. As distribution and sales decrease, customers with products that are becoming obsolete must be supported. Success now can win customers loyal to the brand.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. distributor integration (DI) network. "},{"question":"  B. Growth ","choices":["  C. Maturity ","  D. Decline","350. The correct answer is B. ","A 'best cost\" analysis of risk is performed by multiplying the anticipated cost of the business disruption by the likelihood of its occurrence.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Introduction "},{"question":"  B. multiplying the expected cost of the risk by its likelihood. ","choices":["  C. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business and dividing that by likelihood of the occurrence. ","  D. adding accumulated risk associated with all strategic suppliers.","351. The correct answer is D. ","Demographic segmentation groups customers by group characteristics such as age, income, marital status, or family size.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. subtracting cost of possible risk from cost of business. "},{"question":"  B. Segmentation by value ","choices":["  C. Segmentation by need ","  D. Segmentation by demographics ","352. The correct answer is B. ","All those affected by the SRM strategy should be informed and trained before the program is piloted.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Segmentation by channel "},{"question":"  B. Delaying training and corporate communication of the strategy until after pilot program results are identified ","choices":["  C. Performing a Pareto analysis of all suppliers ","  D. Conducting a pilot study ","353. The correct answer is A. ","Before entering alliances, start identifying key issues and decisions and involving key stakeholders for fewer surprises and greater buy-in by key people.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Developing a PSA to define deliverables "},{"question":"  B. appoint a dedicated alliance manager to oversee the partner relationship. ","choices":["  C. select the proper partners by evaluating corporate culture and operating style. ","  D. establish ground rules for how partners will work together and resolve conflict.","354. The correct answer is B. ","Cross-selling is a CRM tactic made possible by the accumulation of data about a customer's buying habits. Customers are offered related products in addition to their current purchase.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. align internally by identifying key issues and stakeholders. "},{"question":"  B. cross-selling. ","choices":["  C. a win-back program. ","  D. a loyalty program","355. The correct answer is B. ","In a continuous replenishment model, suppliers are notified daily of actual sales or warehouse shipments and commit to replenishing inventory without receiving purchase orders.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. up-selling. "},{"question":"  B. a continuous replenishment inventory management model. ","choices":["  C. a vendor-managed inventory model. ","  D. none of the above.","356. The correct answer is D. ","Generally, customers who resort to this tactic feel that they have not been heard by the \"offending\" business and that attempts have not been made to address their problems. This is a failure of customer communication and customer care rather than brand identity, specific communication media, or competitors' activities.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. a quick response inventory management model. "},{"question":"  B. development of brand identity. ","choices":["  C. monitoring of competitive activities. ","  D. none of the above. ","357. The correct answer is D. ","After determining the nature and costs of potential disruptions, organizations assemble a desirable risk portfolio that balances risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation.   "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. managing media for customer communication. "},{"question":"  B. Eliminate risks by predicting their likely sources. ","choices":["  C. Identify current risk-prone partnerships that should be severed. ","  D. Balance risks in terms of probability, cost of occurrence, and cost of mitigation.","358. The correct answer is C. ","Initially, customers may complain of getting lost in the network and never knowing whom to contact or how to check on an order. This is particularly common when more than one organization is involved in the support of a product or service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Identify those risk costs that can shifted to a partner's portfolio. "},{"question":"  B. Supplier ","choices":["  C. Customer ","  D. Distributor","359. The correct answer is B. ","Proactive reasons for an organization to consider a strategic alliance are the alliance's ability to add value to products, enable strategic growth, increase market access, strengthen operations, increase organizational expertise, build organizational skills, and enhance financial strength.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Internal "},{"question":"  B. Improving time to market or increasing quality ","choices":["  C. Acquiring competitive high-tech equipment ","  D. Improving management compensation programs","360. The correct answer is B. ","Alliance relationships are marked by organization integration at many points in the partners' organizations, from information systems through marketing and sales to finance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Acquiring technological expertise in weaker areas of the company "},{"question":"  B. Alliances are relationships between two or more partners in the supply chain. ","choices":["  C. In alliance relationships, flexibility is not a good thing. Processes must be rigidly followed and enforced. ","  D. Alliance relationships are marked by organizational integration at a few critical points.","361. The correct answer is D. ","Good CRM technology is easy to use and meets customer expectations. Successful implementation of CRM technology rests on a clear, well-thought-out architecture. Rather than inhibiting change, good design enhances integration and lessens the chances of conflicts as the system evolves. Since it may involve redefining jobs, implementation teams should be cross-functional.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Despite potential benefits, there has been little growth in the development of strategic alliances. "},{"question":"  B. Implementation teams should represent technological areas only. ","choices":["  C. If technology is optimal, job responsibilities may remain static in the new system. ","  D. Systems should be measured against whether they increase efficiency and meet customer expectations","362. The correct answer is C. ","While CRM and SRM are not synonymous with technical tools (they are philosophies and competitive strategies), they are both greatly supported by technological solutions.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Detailed architecture design at an early stage may lead to an inflexible system that is difficult to change. "},{"question":"  B. The effects of technology are more significant in SRM than CRM. ","choices":["  C. Technology plays a supporting role in CRM and SRM. ","  D. All of the above ","363. The correct answer is A. ","In this arrangement, the manufacturer receives better information about market demand, enabling more efficient production and better inventory management, thereby reducing costs.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Both CRM and SRM are essentially technological. "},{"question":"  B. shortening production times. ","choices":["  C. enhancing demand. ","  D. lengthening intervals between restocking.","364. The correct answer is A. ","SRM technology has made it easier to see what is happening at each point of the supply chain in real time. It can streamline many strategic sourcing tasks, but it should not substitute for the judgment required to select sources. The Internet has helped connect the supply chain and simplify communication in SRM systems and the performance of SRM tasks. New SRM technology is increasingly modular and compatible with existing applications and is therefore financially feasible in some form for most companies.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. reducing costs. "},{"question":"  B. SRM technology should be used to automate the sourcing process itself. ","choices":["  C. The Internet has greatly increased the complexity of SRM technology. ","  D. SRM technology is often too costly for many businesses to implement.","365. The correct answer is D. ","Customers demand a variety of products and features as well as low prices.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. SRM technology can increase visibility of the entire supply chain. "},{"question":"  B. Manufacturers ","choices":["  C. Retailers ","  D. Customers ","366. The correct answer is D. ","If CRM vendors train their employees in the client's business and products and if they have adequate resources, they can convey the impression of seamless customer service. CRM may be outsourced for various reasons. Cost is not the only consideration; vendors may offer advanced capabilities, for example. Information gained by one vendor should be shared with all vendors to create a learning organization. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Suppliers "},{"question":"  B. The only good reason for outsourcing CRM is cost savings. ","choices":["  C. Separation of CRM vendors should be strictly enforced to protect the outsourcing business's autonomy. ","  D. CRM vendors may provide seamless customer service.","367. The correct answer is C. ","Organizations' internal members are sometimes hesitant initially to trust any of their supply chain partners enough to share what they value as important internal information or data. While most organizations are open to receiving information regarding best practices from partner organizations, they are typically not willing to reciprocate by sharing equal information.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. CRM should not be outsourced. "},{"question":"  B. Distributor ","choices":["  C. Internal ","  D. Supplier ","368. The correct answer is C. ","Pricing, product, and placement are all important strategy elements in implementing and maintaining brand image or identity, but creation of the desired image is a promotional activity.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Customer "},{"question":"  B. placement. ","choices":["  C. promotion. ","  D. pricing. ","369. The correct answer is D. ","While in the past the strategic focus for many organizations was to improve their internal quality and reduce costs, the new focus is on implementing total supply chain solutions that require collaboration from partner organizations both upstream and downstream.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. product. "},{"question":"  B. The focus has shifted from inventory management to demand enhancement. ","choices":["  C. The focus has shifted from brick-and-mortar solutions to Web-based solutions. ","  D. The focus has shifted from internal quality improvement and cost reduction to collaborative solutions up and down the supply chain.","370. The correct answer is C. ","A virtual organization is a long-term strategic alliance of separate business entities that presents itself to third parties as a single entity.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The focus has shifted from human resource-based solutions to technology-driven solutions. "},{"question":"  B. Company that sells only services, not products ","choices":["  C. Strategic alliance of four companies to develop a new drug product and market it under the name of one of the companies ","  D. Merger of two competitors ","371. The correct answer is D. ","An effective collaborative strategy must be measured to ensure its effectiveness. Processes and systems must be in place to monitor performance. Important measurements include supply chain sales, shipments, stockouts, invoicing, and payments.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Raw materials supplier that agrees to supply product for an upcoming production cycle "},{"question":"  B. Continuously improve. ","choices":["  C. Understand the needs of the partners. ","  D. Monitor performance. ","372. The correct answer is D. ","Predictive churn uses data about individual customer transactions and histories to identify trends that indicate that a customer may switch to a competitor or cease being a customer. As a result, the vulnerable customer may be offered incentives, such as loyalty programs. The data used in the model may be gathered through data mining.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Use supply chain assets collectively. "},{"question":"  B. Loyalty programs ","choices":["  C. Win-back programs ","  D. Predictive churn","373. The correct answer is C. ","Successful alliances begin from a position of mutual strength and excellence. In this case, one partner is driven primarily by a desire to escape the problem of looming competition. This will be a hard obstacle to overcome even though the partners have invested in the relationship and integrated their organizations.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Data mining "},{"question":"  B. integration. ","choices":["  C. individual excellence. ","  D. information.","374. The correct answer is C. ","Development of the PSA, procedures to handle all customer interactions, infrastructure (people and information) to perform the procedures, and metrics to measure success are all parts of a successful customer service management strategy. Customer interaction scenarios are determined by customer needs, not by existing infrastructure. Specific responses should be developed and followed. Service levels may be customized for different customer segments.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. investment. "},{"question":"  B. Restricting customer interactions to a limited set of defined scenarios that may be performed within the existing infrastructure ","choices":["  C. Development of a product and service agreement (PSA) ","  D. Developing a general system but allowing flexibility to customer service personnel to develop specific procedures ","375. The correct answer is D. ","Lifetime customers increase the need for CRM, but they also make it a little easier as the business learns more about them over time. Total marketing costs decline, satisfaction increases with better customer understanding, and both revenue and profit increase.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Delivering consistent and identical customer service to all customer segments "},{"question":"  B. They are more difficult to satisfy than first-time or short-term customers. ","choices":["  C. They tend to have a null effect on revenue but a positive effect on profit. ","  D. They increase the need for CRM activities.","376. The correct answer is B. ","Measurement of customer satisfaction is a key element of CRM. B2B companies may measure the CRM effectiveness of their account managers by inviting the managers' customers to participate in their performance evaluations. VOC is considered a more general research tool.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. They increase total marketing costs. "},{"question":"  B. measuring customer satisfaction. ","choices":["  C. collaborative management practices. ","  D. voice of the customer information gathering.","377. The correct answer is A. ","Increased supply chain visibility can lessen the bullwhip effect and enable early problem detection, faster response and better contingency planning, and stronger relationships because of increased trust.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. supply chain integration. "},{"question":"  B. Lowers the number of required distributors ","choices":["  C. Simplifies market segmentation ","  D. Reduces customer service calls ","378. The correct answer is D. ","Commodity pricing has made it more important for businesses to streamline the supply chain and become more cost-effective. The supply chain has, in fact, consolidated rather than fragmented; global markets have grown rather than shrunk. Consolidation may necessitate strategic sourcing as the number of sources narrows. Growing global markets present opportunities but also costs and risks that must be managed. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Enables faster response and better contingency planning "},{"question":"  B. Shrinking global markets ","choices":["  C. Greater fragmentation on both sides of the supply chain ","  D. Commodity pricing","379. The correct answer is C. ","Cost considerations that SCM partner organizations must examine include costs of hardware, software, overhead, and consulting fees. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Decreasing customer response time "},{"question":"  B. What are the overhead expenses? ","choices":["  C. How profitable are each of the partner SCM organizations? ","  D. What are the hardware expenses?","380. The correct answer is C. ","Shipping generic products and creating the customer variations further down the supply chain (delayed differentiation) aggregates customer demand across all products. This produces a more accurate demand forecast with a smaller degree of variability, allowing reduced storage of safety stock. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Are there consulting fees involved? "},{"question":"  B. By reducing lead times ","choices":["  C. By enabling delayed differentiation ","  D. By combining shipments through cross-docking ","381. The correct answer is B. ","A loyalty program simultaneously rewards repeat or high-value customers and encourages continued business through special incentives.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. By enabling direct warehouse-to-customer shipping "},{"question":"  B. Free shipping for high-volume customers ","choices":["  C. Introductory rates ","  D. \"Buy one, get two\" offer","382. The correct answer is C. ","Supply partners must accept and commit to the fact of change in their relationships. As conditions and individual priorities and strategies change, the processes that define the relationship should change as well. It is better if change can be accomplished incrementally.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Customer profiling system "},{"question":"  B. The best change occurs in large movements that motivate the entire organization rather than in smaller increments. ","choices":["  C. No single restructuring of processes will be adequate. ","  D. Relationships should not be affected by the shifting priorities of the partners.","383. The correct answer is A. ","When information from suppliers, manufacturers, distributors, retailers, and customers is available for analysis, there is enhanced visibility of the supply chain and opportunities for improvement. Demand information, inventory status, capacity status, capacity plans, production schedules, promotion plans, shipment forecasts, and demand forecasts are all shared and ideally can be accessed by all parties on a real-time, online basis.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Although marketplace change may be constant, the details of the relationship should not change. "},{"question":"  B. Transactional versus collaborative ","choices":["  C. Purchase price versus true cost ","  D. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","384. The correct answer is C. ","Before the rules, supervision, and improvement of the relationship can be pursued, a win-win deal must be negotiated. This sets the tone for the future alliance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility "},{"question":"  B. engage in a collaborative corporate mindset. ","choices":["  C. negotiate a win-win deal. ","  D. establish ground rules.","385. The correct answer is C. ","In mergers and acquisitions, suppliers are folded into the purchasing entity. Business goals are shared; business areas participate in setting strategy and planning integration of capabilities, processes, and information. Competition has been eliminated.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. appoint an alliance manager. "},{"question":"  B. Buy the market ","choices":["  C. Mergers and acquisitions ","  D. Collaborations/strategic alliance","386. The correct answer is C. ","Collaborations or strategic alliances are long-term arrangements ruled more by agreements than contracts. The suppliers are fully aware of the purchaser's goals and strategies and work with the purchaser to develop and implement tactics. Trust levels are high.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Ongoing relationship "},{"question":"  B. Buy the market ","choices":["  C. Collaborations/strategic alliance ","  D. Mergers and acquisitions ","387. The correct answer is D. ","Traditional purchasing sees each purchase as a discrete transaction. Since strategic sourcing involves ongoing relationships, there is opportunity for collaboration between the purchaser and suppliers that can result in improving the profitability of the supply chain and adding value to the final product or service.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Ongoing relationship "},{"question":"  B. Boundary-specific versus realigned work processes and workflows ","choices":["  C. Purchase price versus true cost ","  D. Transactional versus collaborative","388. The correct answer is A. ","A PSA between partners should be mutually beneficial. It may be customized, should precede pilot and full implementation, and should always be measured for improvement.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Limited visibility versus entire supply chain visibility "},{"question":"  B. The PSA is not subject to standard strategic goal metrics. ","choices":["  C. PSAs should be standardized for all suppliers. ","  D. The PSA is crafted only after a carefully conducted pilot program. ","389. The correct answer is C. ","Customer segmentation allows businesses to learn customer desires and habits and design more effective promotional programs.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The negotiated PSA must be mutually beneficial for both partners. "},{"question":"  B. Shorter sales cycle ","choices":["  C. Better ROI on promotion budgets ","  D. Shorter time-to-market","390. The correct answer is A. ","From a purely reactive stance, companies with certain types of supply situations may be able to manage risk better in a strategic alliance. Purchasers must consider strategic importance of the component, the complexity of the component-product interface, the number of component suppliers available, and the uncertainty of the supplier relationship.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Lower production costs "},{"question":"  B. Opening new markets ","choices":["  C. Adding value to products ","  D. Building organizational expertise ","391. The correct answer is C. ","Many suppliers feel that e-marketplaces have the effect of reducing their products and services to a commodity where price is emphasized rather than quality or the partnership.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. The number of suppliers able to provide the component "},{"question":"  B. Customer ","choices":["  C. Supplier ","  D. Distributor","392. The correct answer is D. ","Improved, real-time communication can benefit supply relationships in all of the ways listed, from planning through production and distribution.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Internal "},{"question":"  B. Better forecasting of raw materials and labor through synchronized planning activities ","choices":["  C. Decreased time-to-market through coordinating workflows ","  D. All of the above ","393. The correct answer is C. ","Suppliers of raw materials typically prefer flexible delivery times, large yet stable volume demands, and consistency in mix of materials.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Early detection of quality problems through timely information sharing "},{"question":"  B. Retailers ","choices":["  C. Suppliers ","  D. Warehouse managers ","394. The correct answer is D. ","Although vendors may suggest inventory levels, retailers must approve initial levels. After that point, levels will be maintained by the vendor according to an agreement and models based on POS and shipment data for greatest customer satisfaction and return on inventory. Data can be tied into planning processes so that MPSs can be created and MRPs set.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Logistics managers "},{"question":"  B. Retailers have no hand in setting initial inventory; historical data are used. ","choices":["  C. Inventory data cannot be tied to MPS or MRP. ","  D. Inventory levels can be adjusted according to different variables. ","395. The correct answer is B. ","Designating one organization as channel master positioned at the center of the initiative during its inception can contribute to the strategy's success. The channel master should be capable of rallying supporters and driving the implementation beyond the preoccupation with improving internal competencies.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Retailers maintain oversight on ordering. "},{"question":"  B. the organization that drives the implementation process. ","choices":["  C. the organization that designates the optimal delivery channels. ","  D. the person designated as strategic team leader. ","396. The correct answer is C. ","Promotion comprises a variety of marketing activities, from customer research through strategy setting and advertising. CRM enhances both the gathering of information about customers and the use of that information in marketing activities.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. the person who designates the optimal communications channels. "},{"question":"  B. Placement ","choices":["  C. Promotion ","  D. Product ","397. The correct answer is D. ","Customer-focused businesses try to make their customers feel better educated about what they are buying before, during, and after the purchase. They promote sharing of information about the customer throughout the supply chain, appreciate the need to consider customer needs in designing as well as marketing and distributing products, and maintain communication and distribution strategies that value convenience for the customer more than profitability. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. Price "},{"question":"  B. focuses on customer care rather than product/service design and delivery. ","choices":["  C. restricts communication and distribution channels to the most profitable options. ","  D. educates customers throughout the purchasing process","398. The correct answer is A. ","As structures and processes change, managers will need to acquire new skills to support implementation of SRM and CRM. Decision making will actually move downward throughout the organization, closer to critical points in the supply chain. Technology is increasingly available, powerful, and easy to integrate.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. gathers information about the customer but restricts its use to critical points in the supply chain. "},{"question":"  B. Decision making must become more centralized and uniform. ","choices":["  C. Technology is too complex and expensive. ","  D. None of the above ","399. The correct answer is D. ","In a dynamic marketplace, a static consultant contract without clear and flexible guidelines and processes to manage the relationship simply encourages consultants to break their connection with the company rather than redefine it. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A. Managers must acquire new skill sets. "},{"question":"  B. ensuring strict adherence to the established alliance contract by both participants. ","choices":["  C. preventing any sources of tension between participant organizations. ","  D. encouraging participants to redefine problematic connections rather than break them. ","400. The correct answer is C. ","Rates, such as number of floor failures, rejected materials, or delays in shipment, are used to compile reports of supplier performance but are not themselves reports. Reporting mechanisms include such tools as scorecards, performance failure alerts (which are online and in real time), and surveys. A certification indicates that a supplier has met criteria but does not report ongoing performance.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A. providing clear channels of legal redress for each participant. "}]